<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Caravan</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/feed" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in</link>
	<description>A Journal of Politics and Culture</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:36:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/cropped-cvn-icon-32x32.jpg</url>
	<title>The Caravan</title>
	<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>&#8220;We Will Fight Till the End&#8221;: On the Protests Against Appa Rao Podile&#8217;s Return to the University of Hyderabad</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-appa-rao-podile-reinstatement</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-appa-rao-podile-reinstatement#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:27:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Surabhi Kanga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Vantage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ABVP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Appa Rao Podile]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ASA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[caste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dalit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protest]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Rohith Vemula]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[student politics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[University of Hyderabad]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25999</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, the University of Hyderabad served suspension notices to two of its faculty members: KY Ratnam and Tathagata Sengupta. Both Ratnam and Sengupta were arrested on 22 March this year during a protest outside the residence of Appa Rao Podile, the vice chancellor of the university. That day, Podile, who had been on leave since a week after &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-appa-rao-podile-reinstatement" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">&#8220;We Will Fight Till the End&#8221;: On the Protests Against Appa Rao Podile&#8217;s Return to the University of Hyderabad</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-appa-rao-podile-reinstatement">&#8220;We Will Fight Till the End&#8221;: On the Protests Against Appa Rao Podile&#8217;s Return to the University of Hyderabad</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Yesterday, the University of Hyderabad served suspension notices to two of its faculty members: KY Ratnam and Tathagata Sengupta. Both Ratnam and Sengupta were arrested on 22 March this year during a protest outside the residence of Appa Rao Podile, the vice chancellor of the university. That day, Podile, who had been on leave since a week after the death of the Dalit PhD student Rohith Vemula, returned to the campus and resumed his post. </em><em>Vemula was a member of the Ambedkar Students Association, an anti-caste student political group. The ASA and its affiliates held Podile and the university&#8217;s oppressive casteist mandate responsible for Vemula&#8217;s death. </em><em>Several student groups protested Podile&#8217;s return, congregating outside his residence and demanding an audience with him. </em></p>
<p><em>In his May 2016 cover story, &#8216;<span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/reportage/from-shadows-to-the-stars-rohith-vemula" target="_blank">From Shadows to the Stars</a></span>,&#8217; Praveen Donthi reported on how the ASA came to be one of the most potent political forces on the university campus, as well as the events surrounding Vemula&#8217;s suicide. In this excerpt from the piece, Donthi recounts the events of 22 March, and how the mainstream media&#8217;s coverage of the incident left out essential aspects of the students&#8217; protest.</em></p>
<p>On 24 January, a week after Vemula’s death, the University of Hyderabad announced that Appa Rao Podile had gone on leave, with his replacement officer, Vipin Srivastava, citing “personal reasons” for the departure. It was a small sign that the university was willing to try and cool tempers. But since Srivastava had been part of the committee that punished the Dalit students, and had been the head of the school of physics when Senthil Kumar committed suicide in 2008, he too was an unacceptable interlocutor in the eyes of much of the student body.</p>
<p>In the face of protests at the end of that week, Srivastava also went on leave, and another senior professor, M Periasamy, took up the role. Periasamy, the first OBC individual to hold the post, adopted a far more thoughtful approach than Podile had, making a clear effort to address students’ concerns, and assuring the media that some of their demands could be met. After months of exhausting protests, the students saw some hope of relief.</p>
<p>That hope was shortlived. On the morning of 22 March, even as dialogue with Periasamy was underway, the vice chancellor’s secretariat sent out a one-line email to staff and students, which read: “Prof Appa Rao Podile resumed the charge in the forenoon of March 22, 2016.” Students were aghast. Just when it seemed there could be some resolution, they would once again have to deal with a man who they believed carried a toxic bias against Dalits.</p>
<p>That same morning, a group of students from the Joint Action Committee—an umbrella group that included members of the ASA, formed to support the five suspended students—gathered at the vice chancellor’s campus residence, known as the “VC’s lodge,” to protest Podile’s return. They learnt that he was holding a meeting of the executive council, and that many ABVP students from the school of life sciences—where Podile is a professor—were with him. The JAC students were provoked by what they saw as the administration’s partisan behaviour. “We told TV Rao, the chief security officer, that we want to meet the VC—but he said a meeting is on,” Ashok Dara, a senior ASA leader, told me. They waited for 15 minutes, he added, and then saw that the students inside were filming those who had gathered outside as they argued with the security guards. According to Dara, the JAC students demanded that the ABVP students exit the premises, in response to which the latter shouted at them to go away. “We have the same right as they do to sit in the VC bungalow,” Dara said. “Is he the VC of only that group?”</p>
<p>The JAC students tried to enter the room, which led to a skirmish. In the fight, students damaged the premises of the VC’s lodge, breaking window panes, flower pots, a television and other objects. But while the administration and the media portrayed the damage as being solely caused by the JAC group, the students I spoke to said the ABVP, too, was responsible for at least some of the damage. “We did some damage but nobody focussed on the damage they had done, but blamed it on us,” Dara told me.</p>
<p>“For three months we did a very peaceful protest, madam, we never did any vandalism or property destruction of our university,” an anguished Prabhakar of the ASA told the CNN-IBN reporter Sakshi Khanna. “We are human beings. Why he came again? He hurt our sentiments. Because he is the first culprit in the Rohith Vemula case.”</p>
<p>At around 11.30 am, police arrived on campus, even as the JAC students continued their efforts to enter the VC’s lodge. Wearing riot helmets and carrying protective shields and sticks, they continued to pour in and assembled at the lodge until they outnumbered the students present. The students remained undeterred. That evening, at around 5.30 pm, the police started forcefully vacating the protesting students from the premises.</p>
<p>Though several television journalists were present by this time, they recorded very little evidence of police action, instead focussing only on the lodge’s broken property. The mainstream media’s emphasis on the vandalism over the police crackdown lent credence to the Dalit students’ fears that coverage was biased, playing up the stereotype of the violent Dalit.</p>
<p>The clearest video available of the action shows students cowering and clinging to each other as the police drag them out of the lodge compound. Throughout, the students scream at the police, insisting that they are protesting peacefully.</p>
<p>In the absence of media footage, the most detailed accounts of the police’s excesses are in first-person video testimonies shot by students and uploaded onto YouTube. In these testimonies, women students said that members of the police abused them, threatened them with rape, and molested them. In her testimony, Akshita, an MSc student of physics, recounted that the police said, “You girls should behave like girls, not like prostitutes.”</p>
<p>According to Munna, the police took three hours to clear the students from the lodge. In the chaos, 27 people were picked up and bundled into police vehicles; among them were two faculty members, KY Ratnam and Tathagata Sengupta, as well as one film-maker, Moses Tulasi. “The police said, ‘Why are you standing here? Go away,’” Ratnam recalled. “I said, ‘I am faculty here, you are beating my students without a reason.’ They said, ‘Take this fellow as well.’” When Sreerag Poickadath, a Dalit student from Kerala, asked the police why they were picking up a professor, he, too, was forced inside the police van.” One student, Gautam Uyyala, who was filming the incident on his cell phone, told me that a policeman said to him, “Why don’t you film your mother and sister naked?”</p>
<p>The 27 people who were detained were transported in one group of nine, and another of 18. People in the latter group were beaten all the way from the university to the police station, according to Poickadath, who was among them. “In the van, a police slapped and asked me if I was a Muslim because of my beard without a moustache,” he told me. One sub-inspector, he said, told him, “I will kill all Muslims today.” Poickadath added: “While beating us, they said things like, ‘You eat beef and conduct beef festivals,’ as if it was a crime.’”</p>
<p>According to Poickadath, the students were not allowed to use their phones. They were also not produced before a magistrate within 24 hours, as required by law. “The judge did not give us an earlier time. The time she gave us is when we produced them,” the Telangana home minister Nayani Narasimha Reddy told <em>Frontline</em> magazine. But a report by Sudipto Mondal for the <em>Hindustan Times</em>revealed that there were networks of power working against the students—Dharmavarapu Varoodhini, the magistrate who was hearing their bail plea, is married to M Vijaykanth, who works in the law firm of the BJP MLC Ramachander Rao, accused in an abetment of suicide case filed by the police after Vemula’s death.</p>
<p>Five days later, on 28 March, those who had been detained were granted bail. More than a thousand students welcomed them back to the campus. But from the day of his return, the vice chancellor had turned the campus into a kind of fortress, barring the entry of outsiders and the media. The activist Yogendra Yadav, who was denied entry, called it “a 2,500-acre jail.” Prominent intellectuals and activists who visited the university in solidarity gave speeches outside the gate, while students stood inside and listened, in protest. As of the end of April, the blockade was still in force.</p>
<p>In the first week of April, I managed to get inside the campus to assess the mood. Munsif, one of the arrested students, told me, “22 March is the biggest blow to the culture of dissent that was the hallmark of this campus.” Though some students who had been arrested had returned inspired, the police had managed to instil fear in many others. “The semester is going to end and the holidays will begin,” Sunkanna told me. “I don’t know what to do, but we have to do something. We wanted to intensify the movement in April, but students are scared of cases.”</p>
<p>Political support had waned by this time, as had attendance at the evening velivada meetings. The VC was stationed in his bungalow and had been conducting all his official work from there instead of the administration building. A posse of 20 policemen provided him with round-the-clock security.</p>
<p>Poickadath offered a theory for why the student struggle at Jawaharlal Nehru University, which was occurring at around the same time, was receiving far greater support from faculty. “The protests in JNU had more faculty participation because it was not an anti-caste movement,” he said. “A Brahmin professor can come wearing the cloak of Marxism and talk about campus freedom. But here they have to criticise the privilege they are born with, so they don’t come and participate. They will be forced to talk about caste and criticise it, so they are wary. Their silence means they are casteist.” His conclusion was, “If you try to annihilate caste, the state will throw you in jail because it is a Brahminical state.”</p>
<p>Prashanth told me that in the government’s unbending support for Podile, he saw parallels with the situation in Gujarat after the violence of 2002. “Despite a lot of pressure, the RSS and the BJP kept Modi in the chair, giving him power to crush his opponents and establish his command,” he said. “Appa Rao is a hero for the RSS, as he performed his dharma.”</p>
<p>“Sustaining a movement for a Dalit cause is difficult because socially, politically, economically and legally we are not strong enough,” Sunkanna said. “The enemy is stronger. No sources outside the campus to lead the movement. It is an academic struggle and only students can speak about it.” But he did not concede defeat. “I can’t say we have lost the battle yet,” he said. “But I can’t predict the outcome. There is a legal battle going on and a student movement. If it was a fight between two individuals or two groups, it was OK. This is a fight against the system and the state that is thousand times more powerful than the ASA. Still, we are fighting and we will fight till the end.”</p>
<p>On 13 April, the university’s student union held a general body meeting to vote on a resolution demanding the removal of Podile from the post of vice chancellor. It was near unanimous: 948 students voted in favour of the resolution, while only one opposed it.</p>
<p>Sunkanna told me that some faculty members were trying to persuade the students to back down from their demand, warning them that the government might “bring in an RSS strongman to replace him.” According to Sunkanna, the teachers say, “This man has already been cornered and tomorrow if you put forth any demands, he will accept them.” He continued: “To them, I said only one thing. ‘Let someone stronger come, let Modi himself come. If he does anti-Dalit activities, we will fight against him too. But punish Appa Rao before that.’”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-appa-rao-podile-reinstatement">&#8220;We Will Fight Till the End&#8221;: On the Protests Against Appa Rao Podile&#8217;s Return to the University of Hyderabad</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-appa-rao-podile-reinstatement/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Graphic Novels for MBAs</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/graphic-novels-mbas-public-books</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/graphic-novels-mbas-public-books#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 05:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Surabhi Kanga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Vantage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Apple]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[case study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graphic novels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lynda Barry]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[MBA]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Scott McCloud]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25993</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This post was originally published on Public Books. Over the course of the two-year program at Harvard Business School, an MBA student will read over 500 case studies. They range in length from a single page to over 50, but their format is typically the same: a description of an ambiguous scenario that forces students to read &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/graphic-novels-mbas-public-books" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Graphic Novels for MBAs</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/graphic-novels-mbas-public-books">Graphic Novels for MBAs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This post was originally published on <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.publicbooks.org/multigenre/graphic-novels-for-mbas" target="_blank">Public Books</a></span>.</em></p>
<p>Over the course of the two-year program at Harvard Business School, an MBA student will read over 500 case studies. They range in length from a single page to over 50, but their format is typically the same: a description of an ambiguous scenario that forces students to read actively and decide for themselves what exactly is going on. But “Apple’s Core,” a 2014 reimagining of an original 2008 prose edition by Harvard Business School professor Noam Wasserman, would be almost unrecognisable to many of those students. Not because of what it contains—a study of the origins of Apple and the conflict between co-founders Steve Jobs and Steve Wozniak—but because of how it’s presented. This may be a case study, but it’s also a graphic novel.</p>
<p>“Apple’s Core” begins with a page split into two large panels, like a title slide on a PowerPoint. The top of the page features a diptych of two photorealistic covers of <i>Time</i> magazine, side by side: one shows a computer being named “Machine of the Year,” the other Steve Jobs. In the bottom, larger panel is a ruggedly handsome Steve Wozniak; we know he’s Steve Wozniak because stamped in a text box across his chest are the words “Steve Wozniak: Co-Founder of Apple.” He stands outside the frame, staring angrily into a space beyond both the panel and the reader, speaking to a gaggle of reporters. A three-tiered speech bubble stretches diagonally from Wozniak’s gaping mouth: “Steve Jobs did not do a single circuit, design, or piece of code.”</p>
<p>Graphic novels and business school case studies seem like very unlikely bedfellows. Case studies are a corporate genre, designed to teach proto-professionals how to become the man; comics are an underground, avant-garde art form, tied to countercultural movements that want to stick it to him. Yet both comics and case studies often assume the role of teacher-cum-therapist, demanding that readers engage directly with the text to fill in the blanks and complete the psychological dramas.</p>
<p>Case studies in graphic form join the growing trend of the comification of textbooks.<i> Classics Illustrated,</i> a series of comic book versions of literary classics, began publication in 1941 with <i>The Three Musketeers</i>. The adaptations, which feature gleefully garish covers and art of dubious quality, were immediately popular; from 1941 to 1962, the series sold 200 million copies. In the 1960s the series stopped putting out new titles due to competition from cheap paperbacks and the rise of CliffsNotes. But comics versions of texts in other genres have become prevalent again recently. <i>The 9/11 Report</i> was given a graphic adaptation in 2006. Comic book author Gareth Hinds reimagined <i>Beowulf</i> as a graphic novel in 2007. The “Graphic Freud Series,” which launched in 2012, adapts some of Freud’s most notorious works, such as “The Wolf Man” and “Studies in Hysteria,” in comic form. The show-and-tell nature of comics invites readers to step in and play diagnostician, providing visual as well as verbal cues to what Freud encountered. The <i>Classics Illustrated </i>series itself has seen a revival: in 2011, the comic book adaptation of <i>Nicholas Nickleby</i> was released, the series’ first new title since the 1960s<i>.</i></p>
<p>Case studies might seem like the last genre seeking formal innovation, but what better way to keep students engaged that than through comics? To date, Harvard Business Publishing has released four case studies in graphic treatment: “iPremier Co. (A): Denial of Service Attack” (2009); “Jazzed Up: A Global Strategy Manga Novel” (2013); “Eureka Forbes Ltd.: Managing the Selling Effort (A)” (2013); and “Apple’s Core” (2014). To be sure, a group of four comics, compared to the thousands of traditional case studies, barely qualifies as a needle in a haystack, let alone a drop in a bucket. Yet the fact that these graphic adaptations exist at all allows us to ask what might seem like an incongruous question: what can comics do for the case study, and what can the case study do for comics?</p>
<p>As comics expert Hillary L Chute has pointed out, comics have a long history in education. “I think comics have always been part of an explicitly didactic tradition, because they literally enact a ‘show and tell,’” she wrote to me. ABC books are ür-comics: the reader must make the connection between the text “A” and the image of, say, an apple, or an alligator, and the juxtaposition of both the image and the text creates meaning. As comic book author and theorist Scott McCloud writes in <i>Understanding Comics</i>, his now-classic 1993 tome on comics as a form, “From <i>stained glass windows</i> showing Biblical scenes in order to <i>Monet’s series paintings</i>, to your <i>car owner’s manual</i>, comics turn up <i>all over</i> when <i>sequential art</i> is employed as a definition.” (The emphasis is McCloud’s, but since his book is in comic form, and heavily emphasised text is so de rigueur in comics—think about the WHAM / BAM / KAPOW of superhero comics––you only really notice the emphases outside of the context.) Comics are diagrams; IKEA instructions are wordless comics. In 2013, McCloud wrote a graphic novel to announce and explain the launch of Google Chrome. Ironically, for a web browser, the graphic novel was printed on actual paper.</p>
<p>Jeremy Short, a professor of management at the University of Oklahoma, has become a proselytiser for the use of graphic novels as textbooks. “Business students are good at memorising frameworks and formulas,” he said to me. “The challenge in business school is: how do we teach creativity?” Creativity, in the business world, is revered as the “it factor,” the secret sauce that catapults a company from a couple of guys in an Oregon garage to Apple Inc. Everyone wants to figure out a way to teach creativity, but, of course, once you codify it, it’s not creative. According to Scott, graphic novels “push the envelope” to get students engaged and interacting dynamically with the material. <i>Tales of Garcón, </i>one of Short’s graphic novel textbooks, teaches students about managing a family business through a narrative depicting how the Garcón family operates its hotel. Rather than frog-marching readers through a laundry list of concepts, <i>Tales of Garcón </i>embeds us directly in a story. Short’s textbooks aren’t as formally freewheeling as texts such as Larry Gonick’s <i>Cartoon History</i> books, which are rife with visual jokes while managing to stuff in historically accurate information. But <i>Tales of Garcón </i>gets a lot of mileage out of the fact that readers will relate viscerally to an illustration as well as to a story, and that readers who might struggle with a traditional textbook are more likely to become engaged with the multidimensional presentation; we’re primed to have fun with comics. “Students hear about [“iPremier”], and sometimes ask about it, or tell us they’re looking forward to it, before the class begins,” Robert Austin, a professor at Copenhagen Business School who co-authored “iPremier,” told me.</p>
<p>Short told me that a medical doctor enrolled in the MBA program was one of his most enthusiastic proponents of the graphic novel form, suggesting that it might be used as a tool to further medical training. Others have had the same thought. Graphic medicine, as Jared Gardner <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.publicbooks.org/multigenre/show-me-where-it-hurts-part-1" target="_blank">described in <i>Public Books</i></a></span>, is a rapidly growing field, with many sophisticated comics versions of medical narratives. The <i>Graphic Medicine Manifesto</i>, published in 2015, demonstrates how textbook comics can be witty as well as didactic. In a panel of the comics-style introduction to the <i>Manifesto</i>, in which each author introduces his or herself in illustrated fashion, one of the authors depicted has a caption that reads, “I’m an internal medicine doc who spends a lot of time thinking about ethical issues in healthcare.” The doctor is pictured naked, seated, in the pose of Rodin’s famous sculpture “The Thinker.” The reader isn’t meant to take the doctor’s nudity literally, and the text never makes reference to the drawing’s visual wink. But the graphic novel form gives the same credence to an act of wild, associative imagination and an act of reality, creating a space where the imagination and reality can permeate each other, as they do in daily life, but as they rarely can in a traditional medical handbook.</p>
<p>Traditionally, case studies, like comics, present information in a form that appears familiar, but the content requires more interpretation than is immediately apparent. As Chute wrote to me, “I also feel like comics are accessible-feeling, and often accessible-looking, as a form, but they aren’t always actually simple in a problem-solving way (ambiguity of gutter, etc.), so that makes it interesting for a business school context.”</p>
<p>Of the four case studies that Harvard Business Publishing has put out so far, none use the graphic novel in a formally innovative way. “iPremier” and “Apple’s Core” both deploy black-and-white, representational drawings that essentially illustrate the scenes being described in the case. “Eureka Forbes” is a curious amalgam of scrapbook and comic: this “photonovel version,” as the case is subtitled, reads as though it’s a collection of stills from a silent film, or a “candid” photo shoot of people trying not to mug for the camera as they recreate each aspect of the case. The photographs capture people mid-action, with arms akimbo and mouths all too realistically half-open, and these stills are captioned with improbably long, comic-book-style speech bubbles emanating from the half-open lips, or with an offset explanation of the scene that is extradiegetic to the events portrayed. The photonovel form is endearing in theory, and there’s something charmingly retro about the low-budget aesthetic of these awkwardly re-staged scenes. The “Eureka Forbes” photonovel does allow for the incorporation of other visual elements, like charts and PowerPoint slides, directly into the flow of the narrative, rather than shuttling them into a detached appendix. In practice, however, the graphical treatment reads like a poorly abridged board book in comparison to the original version, which is not only rich with facts and figures but is written in lucid, efficient prose.</p>
<p>In 2008, Noam Wasserman wrote a case study about the founders of Apple, Steve Wozniak and Steve Jobs, and their early disputes. “Apple’s Core” is written colorfully, containing dialogue and quotes from the founders, and is one of Harvard Business Publishing’s most popular cases. In 2013, Thomas Alexander, a professor at the Asian Institute of Management in the Philippines, wanted a version of “Apple’s Core” that would be easier for international students to absorb. With the help of an illustrator, he created a graphic treatment of the case, drawn in manga style; Alexander uses this version, not the prose one, in the core assigned reading for the course. Most panels feature speech bubbles protruding from Graphic Wozniak and Graphic Jobs, who both have wide, expressive eyes and leonine hair. The two illustrated Steves say essentially the same things that they say in the prose version, amplified with exclamation points and interjections for verisimilitude (“Hey!” “Dude!!!” “EH!? REALLY!?”). “[The case] also has an important visceral/emotional side,” Wasserman wrote to me in an email, which he described as “great for the graphical approach,” since clumsy descriptive phrases such as “he looked upset” in prose can be rendered succinctly in illustration.</p>
<p>The graphic version of “Apple’s Core” doesn’t maximise all aspects of the form: it’s more of a graphic rendition of a prose case than a full-fledged graphic novel. Nearly all the drama gets narrated to the reader in the characters’ speech bubbles, or in explanatory sidebars. Yet in this kind of personality-driven case study, in which emotion and psychology play a huge role in how students are meant to interpret the situation, one could imagine how a treatment of “juxtaposed pictorial and other images in deliberate sequence,” as McCloud defines comics, could immerse readers in a nonlinear way that still allows them to put together all the information. What if Jobs and Wozniak were originally drawn in exactly the same style, but gradually, and without textual explanation, began to be drawn in increasingly divergent ways? Or, when Jobs tells Wozniak about a trip to an orchard and suggests that they name the company Apple, one can picture Jobs in a flight of fancy as Isaac Newton, under a tree in the orchard, awaiting the “eureka” moment. Instead of telling the reader about Jobs’s train of thought, in other words, graphic novels afford the opportunity to take the reader there directly. The prose version of “Apple’s Core” packs a great deal into its efficient and compulsively readable eight pages. The graphic version feels like a draggy adaptation of the tight case, weighted down by illustrations rather than pushing the reader forward into a newly immersive experience of the case.</p>
<p>“Jazzed Up,” a case study about an exercise clothing company, is the only one of the four of Harvard Business School’s graphic case studies that isn’t an adaptation of a study previously written in prose. It’s the most formally innovative of the bunch. The format still consists mostly of talking heads, but we do get to see scenes that move things along through icons and other elements beyond narration and dialogue. As a woman is running, for example, we see arrows pointing to her sweatshirt with icons telling us all the fancy statistics it’s measuring. These don’t get repeated in the text of the story; rather, the visuals and the words take the opportunity to convey complementary rather than identical pieces of information.</p>
<p>By comparison, cartoonist Lynda Barry’s “activity books” serve as an example of the graphic case study in a fully realised marriage of form and content. In <i>What It Is,</i> a nonnarrative comic about a writing workshop she teaches, Barry takes readers directly into her mind. Like case studies, which present a deliberately ambiguous situation and require students to make choices based on the fragments provided, Barry compels readers to enter directly into the meaning-making process. Yet unlike graphic novel case studies, which essentially translate narrative cases into illustrated versions, Barry uses a collage-like arrangement of images and pictures to build a nonnarrative, associative space. “Take a look around this image. Picture the car in your mind’s eye,” she writes, “then answer the questions below.” It is unclear whether they are actual or rhetorical queries: “Where are you?” “Why are you there?” “What time of day or night does it seem to be?”</p>
<p>Comics do non-pedantic didacticism well, and readers respond. The comics publisher <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/14/arts/design/25-years-of-drawn-quarterly-champion-of-female-cartoonists.html?_r=1" target="_blank">Drawn &amp; Quarterly has sold</a></span> over 135,000 copies of <i>What It Is</i>; a typical title from the publisher sells about 5,000. <i>Syllabus: Notes from an Accidental Professor</i>, which is cleverly bound to look like a marble composition notebook, splices Barry’s syllabi for her workshops with student work and her own musings to explore what it means to create images and how we perceive the world. Everything is hand-drawn, and crudeness in style (a circle with a few protruding squiggles represents a body) is celebrated. There are no right or wrong answers: the only way to be wrong is to leave it blank. Barry’s books are didactic in the sense that they show and tell, but they turn tradition on its head, subverting the form to invite readers in.</p>
<p>When the case study method was introduced in Harvard Business School in the 1920s, the practice cracked open the traditional pedagogy. Rather than a professor bequeathing a lecture to hundreds of silently scrawling students, a class based around case studies allows the students to lead discussion and requires them to become both academically and psychologically invested in the material. Similarly, the graphic novel presents a way in which the case study itself might be able to innovate radically. If case studies are about presenting information and emotions in a nonlinear fashion, and about actively immersing the reader in the situation, comics, which operate through juxtaposition and have enormous capacity for multiple narratives, seem ideal for presenting case studies that intentionally dangle red herrings or leave crucial parts blank.</p>
<p>The case studies that exist today in comics form haven’t gotten to Barry’s level yet. I’d rather read a prose version perfect in its form than a loose, baggy comic. But the unlikely friendliness of the comics form with case study content and purpose—the mix of public and private, the nonlinearity, the necessity for tangential ideas and details that may or may not become significant at any given moment—suggests that, if nothing else, change may well be afoot.</p>
<p><img class="size-medium wp-image-24944 aligncenter" src="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/publicbooks1-1-300x114.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="114" srcset="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/publicbooks1-1-300x114.jpg 300w, http://www.caravanmagazine.in/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/publicbooks1-1.jpg 386w" sizes="(max-width: 300px) 100vw, 300px" /></p>
<p><em>This article is a part of a collaboration between </em>Public Books<em> and </em>The Caravan<em>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/graphic-novels-mbas-public-books">Graphic Novels for MBAs</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/graphic-novels-mbas-public-books/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Protest outside the Manipur Bhawan in Delhi leaves several injured</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-outside-manipur-bhawan-delhi-leaves-several-injured</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-outside-manipur-bhawan-delhi-leaves-several-injured#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2016 07:22:08 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Vivek Gopal]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Vantage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Delhi Police]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Manipur]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[protesters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25972</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>On the evening of 7 June, around ten buses from various parts of Delhi set off for Chankyapuri. The people from the hill tribes of Manipur on board these buses were gathering outside the Manipur Bhawan to protest against the presence of their Chief Minister Okram Ibobi Singh and an 18-member delegation which was in the capital to pressure &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-outside-manipur-bhawan-delhi-leaves-several-injured" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Protest outside the Manipur Bhawan in Delhi leaves several injured</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-outside-manipur-bhawan-delhi-leaves-several-injured">Protest outside the Manipur Bhawan in Delhi leaves several injured</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: small">On the evening of 7 June, around ten buses from various parts of Delhi set off for Chankyapuri. The people from the hill tribes of Manipur on board these buses were gathering outside the Manipur Bhawan to protest against the presence of their <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://indianexpress.com/article/india/india-news-india/manipur-cm-okram-ibobi-singh-meets-rajnath-singh-on-inner-line-permit-bills-2840189/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">Chief Minister Okram Ibobi Singh</a></span> and an 18-member delegation which was in the capital to pressure the centre into giving assent to three land bills that the state legislature had passed on 31 August 2015. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small">In a special session, the Manipur State Assembly had <u><a href="http://www.ndtv.com/india-news/bills-for-protection-of-indigenous-people-passed-by-manipur-assembly-1212747" target="_blank" rel="nofollow">passed three bills</a></u>: the Protection of Manipur People Bill, the Manipur Land Revenue and Land Reforms Bill, and the Manipur Shops and Establishments Bill. All three bills—drafted to protect the indigenous people of the state—were passed unopposed by the tribal members of Legislative Assembly. </span><span style="font-size: small">The hill tribes of Manipur believe the bills impinge on their land rights. </span>The first of these bills proposes to issue a “pass” to any “non-Manipur person” while entering the state. These have been strongly opposed by tribals, who mainly inhabit the hill districts of Manipur and posit that this is a “hills versus valley” divide. <span style="font-size: small">Last September, nine protestors were killed in police firing in Churachandpur district of the state during a protest against the bill.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small">As night fell on Manipur Bhawan on Sardar Patel Marg, a huge contingent of police personnel was present. The bhawan itself was heavily barricaded, and a few senior police officers waited on the peripheries. At least five camera wielding policemen recorded the proceedings. No women police could be seen even though a majority of the protestors were women. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small">What began as a peaceful protest escalated as stones came flying from the direction of the bhawan. Protesters pushed through one of the gates of the bhawan. They were first brutally assaulted by the Manipur police present inside and then by the Delhi police contingent outside. A reporter with APN news, Himanshu Pandey, who was covering the incident, was assaulted by the police, and suffered blows to the head. I was roughed up despite identifying myself as a journalist several times. People dispersing weren’t spared either. The police conducted lathi charges on men and women who were atleast a kilometre away from the bhawan.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small">Without warning, the police used a water cannon after the lathi charge. <span style="text-decoration: underline">I witnessed around 50 protestors</span> injured and taken to various hospitals around the city, an equal number were detained, many of them women. At Ram Manohar Lohia Hospital, a nurse took me to policemen present at the casualty ward. They made me delete some of the images I had taken of the protestors admitted along with me.</span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-outside-manipur-bhawan-delhi-leaves-several-injured">Protest outside the Manipur Bhawan in Delhi leaves several injured</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/protest-outside-manipur-bhawan-delhi-leaves-several-injured/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The FDC Drugs Ban Will and Must Go to the Supreme Court</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/fdc-drugs-ban-supreme-court</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/fdc-drugs-ban-supreme-court#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2016 05:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Surabhi Kanga]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Vantage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[CDSCO]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Drugs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[FDC]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pharma]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[regulations]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25957</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>On the afternoon of 21 March 2016, the courtroom 12 of the Delhi High Court was packed with senior advocates, advocates and their juniors carrying sheaves of files. Justice Rajiv Sahai Endlaw, who was presiding over the court, was about to hear at least 164 pleas filed by 64 pharmaceutical companies. The companies were all &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/fdc-drugs-ban-supreme-court" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The FDC Drugs Ban Will and Must Go to the Supreme Court</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/fdc-drugs-ban-supreme-court">The FDC Drugs Ban Will and Must Go to the Supreme Court</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the afternoon of 21 March 2016, the courtroom 12 of the Delhi High Court was packed with senior advocates, advocates and their juniors carrying sheaves of files. Justice Rajiv Sahai Endlaw, who was presiding over the court, was about to hear at least 164 pleas filed by 64 pharmaceutical companies. The companies were all asking for the revocation of a recent notification issued by the centre. Almost two weeks earlier, on 10 March, the central government had passed a notification banning the sale and manufacturing of 344 Fixed Dose Combination, or FDC drugs—combinations of two or more active pharmaceutical ingredients in fixed ratios, given in the form of a single dose. Major Indian drugs such as Piramal Healthcare’s Saridon, Pfizer’s Corex, D’Cold Total, Vicks Action 500 Extra, Merck India’s Nasivion fell under the list of the banned FDCs.</p>
<p>The advocates of the pharma companies had presented the matter before the court early in the morning as “urgent,” so that it could be taken up that very day. After considering its roster of cases, the court slotted the hearings for that afternoon, at 2.45pm.</p>
<p>By 2.15pm—when the lunch break ends—the courtroom had already filled up with the small army of pharma lawyers. <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://delhihighcourt.nic.in/dhcqrydisp_o.asp?pn=63061&amp;yr=2016" target="_blank">According to an order he issued later that day</a></span>, other lawyers whose matters Justice Endlaw was supposed to hear between 2.15 and 2.45pm were unable to enter the courtroom, forcing the judge to adjourn their cases. The court staff’s repeated requests to the company of pharma lawyers to leave the courtroom had little effect. Exasperated with the crowd, the judge left the courtroom requesting that decorum should be restored. Eventually, the judge held the proceedings in his chambers in the presence of, he wrote, “whichever counsels were in the front row and / or could reach” it. There, he adjourned the proceedings and called on the registrar general of the court to ensure that the situation was “not repeated.”</p>
<p>This was a rare occurrence. I have reported on matters from the Delhi High Court for some time now, and while courtrooms packed to the brim are common, a judge recording their displeasure with the discipline of the court is not. But the reason for the eagerness of the pharma companies’ advocates to be heard—even at the risk of displeasing the bench—was evident. Had the centre’s notification gone uncontested, pharma companies in India stood to lose about Rs 3,000 crore annually—a dent of 20 percent in their profits, according to an <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.epw.in/journal/2016/14/commentary/cleaning-pharma-industry.html" target="_blank">April 2016 EPW article</a></span>. On 14 March, the court issued a stay on the centre’s notification, temporarily lifting the ban for Delhi. On 2 June, it reserved its judgment on the pharma companies’ plea challenging the notification.</p>
<p class="">The 10 March order and the ensuing hearings were only a recent development in what has been a long-standing issue with FDC regulation in India. While FDC cocktails have <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://apps.who.int/medicinedocs/pdf/s6172e/s6172e.pdf" target="_blank">been known to be effective in handling chronic diseases</a></span> that require many anti-bacterials at once (such as malaria, tuberculosis and AIDS), they can also have adverse side-effects if the combination is “irrational”—therapeutically not justified, or not efficacious. In high doses, FDCs can also aggravate existing conditions; sometimes, they can even cause anti-bacterial resistance to develop in patients. In India, the regulatory landscape for drugs lacks a clear hierarchy across the board, and has directly led to a status quo where the centre and states have both passed the buck on FDC supervision. With both public health and crores of money at stake, a decisive verdict on the matter can, and likely will, only be made by the Supreme Court.</p>
<p class="">In India, the Central Drug Standard Control Organisation, or the CDSCO approves new drugs to be introduced in the market. Once the CDSCO has granted approval, the state regulatory bodies—36 in all, one for each state and union territory—give out licenses for sale and manufacture of drugs. The resulting system, rife with red tape, malfunction and massive corruption, is afflicted with malaise such as <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/perspectives/no-remedy-india-drug-recall" target="_blank">a lack of an effective drug recall system</a></span> for substandard drugs and a high number of irrational FDCs. For instance, in the past, many drug manufacturers have continued to make and sell FDCs after obtaining state licenses, even when CDSCO approval for the drug was pending.</p>
<p>The dangers of unregulated FDCs are widely acknowledged. A <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC4316337/" target="_blank">2014 article</a></span> from the Journal of Clinical and Diagnostic Research says that the FDC drugs’ contribution to creating resistant strains of bacteria in patients is becoming “a lethal problem.” It cites as an example the emergence of a strain, salmonella typhi—the bacteria that causes typhoid—that is resistant to ciprofloxacin, the antibiotic used to treat it. This, the article notes, has made the treatment of typhoid not only “difficult but also expensive.” It goes on to list examples of irrational FDCs: two anti-hypertensives that have the same effect but are combined, seemingly for no medical reason; cough and cold remedies that contain drugs such as phenylpropanolamine, which was banned due to its potential to cause strokes. A <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.cdmuindia.org/Pdf-files/Final-report-IFDCs.pdf" target="_blank">2010 study on FDC drugs in India</a></span> found that over 1,356 unsafe FDC formulations were being sold under 4,559 pharmaceutical brands. Another study carried out by the PLOS Medicine in 2015, showed that the sale of these FDC drugs in 2011-12 alone came to Rs 41,618 crore.</p>
<p>This is not the first time that the Drug Controller General of India, which is responsible for the approval of licenses of specific categories of drugs, has cracked down on the FDCs in the Indian market. Since the 1980s, the medical community and drug activists have been calling for a ban on FDCs. In 2007, the DCGI had directed the state drug regulators to withdraw 294 FDCs from the markets that did not have his approval. However, even then, the manufacturers got a stay order in their favour from the Madras High Court. After nine years, the matter is still being heard in the court.</p>
<p>The most recent effort to ban FDCs that did not have therapeutic justification was set into motion by a parliamentary committee. The committee’s 2012 report pulled up the ministry for health and family welfare for failing to rein in a large number of FDCs circulating in the Indian market without an approval from the CDSCO.</p>
<p>In January 2013, the CDSCO sent a letter to all state and union territory drug controllers asking them to order all the drug manufacturers under their jurisdiction to prove the safety and efficacy of their FDCs within 18 months. In 2014, the government set up the Chandrakant Kokate committee, an expert committee that would review these submissions. By the end of the 18-month period, in July 2014, the Kokate committee had received over 6,220 applications for consideration.</p>
<p>After examination, the Kokate committee found 963 drugs to be irrational. Acting on the committee’s detailed report, the central government issued a show-cause notice to the manufacturers of these drugs. Once their replies were filed, the committee called on domain expert medical specialists from reputed hospitals such as AIIMS, Safdarjung Hospital, Ram Manohar Lohia Hospital and Maulana Azad Medical College to help assess the drugs.</p>
<p>Even after the second examination, the committee found, in February this year, that the FDCs in question to be medically inappropriate and ineffective. This was soon followed by the 10 March order, in which the central government banned 344 of the 963 drugs. The <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.cdsco.nic.in/writereaddata/SO%20705(E)%20TO%201048(E)%20DATED%2010-03-2016.pdf" target="_blank">government stated that</a></span> the ban was instituted because the drug combinations were “likely to involve risk to human beings” at a time when “safer drugs were available.” (Formal orders on the remaining FDCs are <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.pharmabiz.com/NewsDetails.aspx?aid=94168&amp;sid=1" target="_blank">likely to be passed soon</a></span>. A March <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://www.business-standard.com/article/companies/drug-ban-may-erode-12-of-pharma-market-turnover-116031800583_1.html" target="_blank"><em>Business Standard</em> report</a></span> noted that, had all the 963 drugs been banned at once, the estimated loss would have been to the tune of Rs 10,000 crore.)</p>
<p>Despite the opportunities given to the pharma companies to appear before and file replies to the Kokate committee, the companies’ advocates told the Delhi high Court that the expert committee lacked statutory backing—that it was not formed under a law—and that it did not make enquiries of them. In response to these allegations, the government told the court that interim order passed in the favour of the companies should be vacated and that their only objective is “to gain profits and the petition has been filed only to gain time and obstruct the legitimate functions of the Government of India.”</p>
<p>The Delhi High Court passed a stay order on 14 March. The reasoning employed was curious. It said that the centre’s notification apart from “generally stating that the use of the said drug is ‘likely to involve risk to human beings’ does not disclose any grave urgency.”</p>
<p>The high court order came as a relief at a time when two other High Courts in the country—Madras and Kerala—have passed orders against the drugs companies. On 19 March, the Kerala High Court granted two weeks time to the chemists and druggists to return the banned drugs to the distributors. On 22 March, the Madras High Court refused to stay the notification.</p>
<p>As things stand, these orders passed by discrete High Courts will be applicable only within their states. Uniformity across India in respect of the operation of the order will come through only when an appeal is filed before the Supreme Court. The government is <span style="text-decoration: underline"><a href="http://articles.economictimes.indiatimes.com/2016-04-29/news/72704176_1_fdc-drugs-dose-drugs-controller-general" target="_blank">reportedly planning</a></span> to move the SC, in a move that will club all the pharma company appeals together</p>
<p>One way or the other, the matter is bound to land up before the apex court. The Delhi High Court judgment will be appealed by the party in whose favour, the judgement isn’t. The government has already made its intention to file an appeal in the Supreme Court quite clear. Whenever the appeal is lodged before the apex court, the hope is that it will result in a judgment that settles the dust on the fate of FDCs in India, and consequently stems the pharma companies’ practice to earn profits at the cost of millions of patients.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/fdc-drugs-ban-supreme-court">The FDC Drugs Ban Will and Must Go to the Supreme Court</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/vantage/fdc-drugs-ban-supreme-court/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Editor&#8217;s Pick</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/editors-corner/editors-pick-31</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/editors-corner/editors-pick-31#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 15:03:03 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Editor's Corner]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25778</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>ON 19 APRIL 1966, Roberta “Bobbi” Gibb, aged 23, runs towards the finish line of the Boston Marathon, on the way to becoming the first woman to complete the 42.2-kilometre race. Gibb trained for the contest for two years, doing some of her most intense preparation on a month-long road trip across the United States. &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/editors-corner/editors-pick-31" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Editor&#8217;s Pick</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/editors-corner/editors-pick-31">Editor&#8217;s Pick</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>ON 19 APRIL 1966</strong>, Roberta “Bobbi” Gibb, aged 23, runs towards the finish line of the Boston Marathon, on the way to becoming the first woman to complete the 42.2-kilometre race.</p>
<p>Gibb trained for the contest for two years, doing some of her most intense preparation on a month-long road trip across the United States. With only her dog for company, and wearing the sturdiest footwear she could find—nurse’s shoes—she ran along the Mississippi River, through the Great Plains, and even up and over the Great Divide in the Rocky Mountains. In February of 1966, she contacted the Boston Athletic Association, or BAA, the body in charge of the marathon, requesting permission to register as a racer. The race director curtly refused to send her the application forms, saying women were physiologically unable to run such long distances.</p>
<p>Angry but unfazed, Gibb arrived at the start of the race wearing a black swimsuit, her brother’s shorts and a hooded sweatshirt that allowed her to cover her hair. She hid in some bushes near the starting line, and jumped into the fray after half of the other runners had begun. Some of them soon realised she was a woman, and—to her relief—were friendly and supportive. She removed her disguise, and was rewarded with wild cheering from supporters all along the race’s route. Gibb clocked in at 3 hours, 21 minutes and 40 seconds—ahead of two-thirds of the men.</p>
<p>Gibb’s achievement earned her celebrity—she made front-page news the next day, and was featured in <em>Sports Illustrated </em>later that year. She returned to run the Boston Marathon—still unofficially, though without subterfuge—in 1967 and 1968. One other woman completed the course in 1967, and a total of five competed the following year. In 1972, the BAA finally permitted women to register for the race.</p>
<p>In 1996, the BAA retroactively recognised Gibb as the first female winner of the Boston Marathon. This year, the race’s female champion, Atsede Baysa, presented her trophy to Gibb. She accepted the gift on the condition that, next year, she will travel to Baysa’s native Ethiopia to return it.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/editors-corner/editors-pick-31">Editor&#8217;s Pick</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/editors-corner/editors-pick-31/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Close To Home</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/photo-essay/close-to-home-photos-women-prison-croatia</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/photo-essay/close-to-home-photos-women-prison-croatia#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:58:01 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Photo Essay]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25750</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>POZEGA PENITENTIARY, nestled in a quiet valley in eastern Croatia, is a beige-coloured block of a building. Some of the windows on its ground floor have been filled in with concrete, and a few wiry trees line its front driveway. Housing over 130 inmates, it is Croatia’s only correctional institution for women who have been convicted &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/photo-essay/close-to-home-photos-women-prison-croatia" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Close To Home</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/photo-essay/close-to-home-photos-women-prison-croatia">Close To Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>POZEGA PENITENTIARY,</strong> nestled in a quiet valley in eastern Croatia, is a beige-coloured block of a building. Some of the windows on its ground floor have been filled in with concrete, and a few wiry trees line its front driveway. Housing over 130 inmates, it is Croatia’s only correctional institution for women who have been convicted of serious crimes, with sentences of six months or longer.</p>
<p>Marina Paulenka, who grew up near Pozega, became fascinated by the institution after she met a few women who had been convicted on minor charges—such as traffic accidents and petty thefts—and sent to prison since they were unable to post bail. “I heard many interesting stories which I wanted to document,” she said.</p>
<p>Her efforts culminated in <em>The Other Home</em>, a stark photo series about Pozega, which she shot on monthly visits to the institution over a year and a half. Surprisingly, the series does not show a single prisoner. Instead, it depicts objects and furnishings: curtains rustling before an open window, a bra hanging on a shower wall, a jar of flowers on a desk. By focussing on such subjects, Paulenka aimed to explore the way the prisoners construct a home for themselves in Pozega—“but a completely distant and cold home.” The photographer also paid close attention to the way gender influences the women’s experiences, and organised the images into thematic clusters dealing with such things as “motherhood” and “femininity.”</p>
<p>Initially, Paulenka did not intend for the women to be absent from her photos. Her choices were constrained by Croatian law, which prohibits the filming or photographing of prisoners in any way that renders them identifiable. She planned to circumvent this by photographing the women’s shadows and silhouettes, but even that was rejected by the government bureaucrats who reviewed her proposal. “I am sure this was not out of sympathy with the prisoners,” Paulenka said, pointing out that the women themselves had even consented to being photographed without any such camouflage.</p>
<p>Paulenka spent a large amount of time getting to know the women. “I wanted to be one of them, in a sense,” she said. “To taste their food, to spend more time with them, to listen and to look around so that I could absorb the story in its entirety.” Many of them told Paulenka about the harsh judgment they faced in society; “They are stigmatised and marked forever,” she said, while men in their position are more likely to be given a “second chance.” Paulenka hopes that <em>The Other Home</em> will help transform such societal norms, but for now she is content with how she has touched and positively influenced the women at Pozega. “I already sent a few photographs to the inmates,” she said, “and they liked them.”</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/photo-essay/close-to-home-photos-women-prison-croatia">Close To Home</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/photo-essay/close-to-home-photos-women-prison-croatia/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Gene</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/gene-intimate-history</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/gene-intimate-history#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:53:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bookshelf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25788</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Siddhartha Mukherjee From the author of The Emperor of All Maladies, this book provides a detailed history of the scientific discovery and development of the gene—the fundamental unit of heredity. Woven through it is also the intimate story of Siddhartha Mukherjee’s own family and its history of mental illness, reminding us that genetics is vitally &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/gene-intimate-history" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">The Gene</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/gene-intimate-history">The Gene</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Siddhartha Mukherjee<br />
</strong><br />
From the author of <em>The Emperor of All Maladies</em>, this book provides a detailed history of the scientific discovery and development of the gene—the fundamental unit of heredity. Woven through it is also the intimate story of Siddhartha Mukherjee’s own family and its history of mental illness, reminding us that genetics is vitally relevant to our everyday lives. These concerns reverberate even more urgently today, as humans are learning to “read” and “write” the human genome, unleashing the potential to change the fates and identities of our children.</p>
<p><strong>Allen Lane, 608 pages, Rs 699</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/gene-intimate-history">The Gene</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/gene-intimate-history/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Babies and Bylines</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/babies-and-bylines</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/babies-and-bylines#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:52:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bookshelf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25798</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Pallavi Aiyar The journalist Pallavi Aiyar, in an uplifting parenting memoir, describes the battles many mothers fight within themselves and in the workplace. Aiyar narrates her own struggles with issues such as finding a work-life balance, negotiating marital equality and taming toddlers. Both thought-provoking and irreverent, Babies and Bylines is as much a call to &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/babies-and-bylines" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Babies and Bylines</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/babies-and-bylines">Babies and Bylines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Pallavi Aiyar </strong></p>
<p>The journalist Pallavi Aiyar, in an uplifting parenting memoir, describes the battles many mothers fight within themselves and in the workplace. Aiyar narrates her own struggles with issues such as finding a work-life balance, negotiating marital equality and taming toddlers. Both thought-provoking and irreverent, <em>Babies and Bylines</em> is as much a call to arms for women in the workplace as it is a humorous read for those who are contemplating or experiencing parenthood.</p>
<p><strong>Harper Collins India, 232 pages, Rs 350</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/babies-and-bylines">Babies and Bylines</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/babies-and-bylines/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pakistan at the Crossroads</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/pakistan-crossroads-domestic-dynamics-external-pressures</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/pakistan-crossroads-domestic-dynamics-external-pressures#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bookshelf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25800</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Christophe Jaffrelot Edited by the political scientist Christophe Jaffrelot (also a contributing editor of The Caravan), this collection of articles by top international scholars assesses the main challenges faced by Pakistan’s civil and military leaders. Contributors to the book examine issues such as the state’s approach to tackling internal threats, tensions between civilians and the &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/pakistan-crossroads-domestic-dynamics-external-pressures" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">Pakistan at the Crossroads</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/pakistan-crossroads-domestic-dynamics-external-pressures">Pakistan at the Crossroads</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Christophe Jaffrelot</strong></p>
<p>Edited by the political scientist Christophe Jaffrelot (also a contributing editor of <em>The Caravan</em>), this collection of articles by top international scholars assesses the main challenges faced by Pakistan’s civil and military leaders. Contributors to the book examine issues such as the state’s approach to tackling internal threats, tensions between civilians and the military, police and law-enforcement reform, trends in judicial activism, the rise of border conflicts, and diplomatic relations with countries such as India, Saudi Arabia and the United States.</p>
<p><strong>Vintage Books, 376 pages, Rs 699</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/pakistan-crossroads-domestic-dynamics-external-pressures">Pakistan at the Crossroads</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/pakistan-crossroads-domestic-dynamics-external-pressures/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s War</title>
		<link>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/indias-war</link>
		<comments>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/indias-war#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2016 14:50:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[webmaster]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Bookshelf]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.caravanmagazine.in/?p=25802</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Srinath Raghavan During the Second World War, India underwent extraordinary and irreversible change. About 2.5 million volunteer troops from the subcontinent found themselves in uniform, fighting in places such as Africa and Europe. In India’s War, the historian and former infantry officer Srinath Raghavan discusses the crucial involvement and contribution of India in the Allied &#8230; <a href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/indias-war" class="more-link">Continue reading <span class="screen-reader-text">India&#8217;s War</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/indias-war">India&#8217;s War</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Srinath Raghavan</strong></p>
<p>During the Second World War, India underwent extraordinary and irreversible change. About 2.5 million volunteer troops from the subcontinent found themselves in uniform, fighting in places such as Africa and Europe. In <em>India’s War</em>, the historian and former infantry officer Srinath Raghavan discusses the crucial involvement and contribution of India in the Allied war effort, painting a compelling picture of battles abroad and of life on the home front. Raghavan even argues that the Second World War is crucial to explaining how and why colonial rule ended in South Asia.</p>
<p><strong>Penguin Books India, 550 pages, Rs 699</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/indias-war">India&#8217;s War</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://www.caravanmagazine.in">The Caravan</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.caravanmagazine.in/bookshelf/indias-war/feed</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>

<!-- Dynamic page generated in 0.171 seconds. -->
<!-- Cached page generated by WP-Super-Cache on 2016-06-14 23:27:16 -->

<!-- Compression = gzip -->