<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="0.92" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
	<title>The New Yorker</title>
	<link>http://www.newyorker.com</link>
	<description>Online version of the weekly magazine, with current articles, cartoons, blogs, audio, video, slide shows, an archive of articles and abstracts back to 1925.</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 18:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<docs>http://backend.userland.com/rss092</docs>
	<language>en-US</language>

	<!-- generator="WordPress/4.3.4" -->
<atom:link rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com"/><atom:link rel="hub" href="http://newyorker.superfeedr.com/"/>
	<item>
		<title>The Faith Behind Aubrey Beardsley’s Sexually Charged Art</title>
		<description><![CDATA[ <p class="descender">The drawings of the late-nineteenth-century English illustrator and author Aubrey Beardsley are so sexually charged that even a critic as generally snobbish and patrician as Kenneth Clark, in accounting for his youthful fondness for them, all but described the works, in a 1976 essay for The New York Review of Books, as autoerotic visual aids. Calling the drawings “<a href="http://www.nybooks.com/articles/1976/12/09/the-genius-of-aubrey-beardsley/" target="_blank">a kind of catmint to adolescents</a>,” Clark wrote that they “suggested vice . . . with an adolescent intensity which communicated itself through every fold and tightly drawn outline of an ostensibly austere style.” He added, “I like to think that my interest was not only sexual.”</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-faith-behind-aubrey-beardsleys-sexually-charged-art</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Yoga-Teacher Science</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="descender">Welcome, everyone. Thank you for bringing your energy to class today. I can really feel it in the air, warm and thick. Feel that? It&#8217;s almost electric, no? Yes, I definitely feel it.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/yoga-teacher-science</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Daily Cartoon: Tuesday, June 14th</title>
		<description><![CDATA[ <p align="center"><a style="font-family: neutra-face-text, Helvetica Neue sans-serif; font-size: 1.3rem; text-transform: uppercase; text-align: center;" href="http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&#38;utm_source=NewYorker&#38;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&#38;AID=1247905545" target="_blank">Buy New Yorker Cartoons»</a></p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/tuesday-june-14th-gun-control</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Donald Trump Steps on His Own Inflammatory Speech</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="descender">After months of running his mouth freely, Donald Trump has evidently hired a proper speechwriter. Coming a day after the horrific attack in Orlando, the <a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/06/transcript-donald-trump-national-security-speech-224273" target="_blank">address</a> that he delivered in Goffstown, New Hampshire, on Monday afternoon was misleading, malevolent, and inflammatory. But it was also pointed, clear, and carefully tailored to contrast Trump’s bellicose stance on terrorism with the measured response of Hillary Clinton, who, <a href="http://www.usatoday.com/story/news/politics/elections/2016/06/13/hillary-clinton-trump-orlando-muslims/85820028/" target="_blank">speaking in Cleveland</a> earlier that day, had called for unity, vigilance, outreach to Muslims, and <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/john-cassidy/gun-laws-and-terrorism-an-american-nightmare">reform of gun-control laws</a>.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/john-cassidy/donald-trump-steps-on-his-own-inflammatory-speech</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>What’s Really Standing in the Way of Gun Control</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="descender">After the Supreme Court decided <a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/html/07-290.ZS.html" target="_blank">District of Columbia v. Heller</a>, in 2008, it appeared that all attempts at gun control might be doomed, as a matter of constitutional law, for the foreseeable future. In an opinion by Antonin Scalia, writing for a five-Justice majority, the Court <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/so-you-think-you-know-the-second-amendment">reversed</a> decades of precedent and asserted that the Second Amendment guaranteed an individual the right to possess firearms (discounting the amendment’s reference to “a well regulated militia”). So, in light of monstrosities like the massacre in Orlando, are the state, local, and federal governments powerless to pass laws that restrict the purchase, possession, and use of guns?</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/whats-really-standing-in-the-way-of-gun-control</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>“Game of Thrones”: The Things We Do for Love</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="descender">Last night, feeling barely equipped to understand the United States, or perhaps humans in general, I made a reluctant journey to Westeros. I love “Game of Thrones”—we all love “Game of Thrones”—but last night I did not want to watch “Game of Thrones.” After the stunning sadness of Orlando, after watching Broadway mourn those losses and celebrate “Hamilton”—“How lucky we are to be alive right now,” the cast sang, having forgone their muskets in favor of mime—turning to HBO for gore, ice, and fire was too much. But here we are. “Game of Thrones,” despite its dragons and its mythmaking, is not a respite. Part of the reason we love it is that its conflicts, its violence, its triumphs and failures of leadership and governance and character, mirror our own.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/sarah-larson/game-of-thrones-the-things-we-do-for-love</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>“And Love Is . . .”: Live-Drawing the 2016 Tony Awards</title>
		<description><![CDATA[ <p class="descender">“And love is love is love is love is love is love is love is love,” Lin-Manuel Miranda said in his moving acceptance sonnet at Sunday night&#8217;s Tony Awards ceremony—which was, inescapably, as Michael Schulman writes, about the <a href="http://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-2016-tony-awards-after-orlando">horror in Orlando as much as it was about the unstoppability of “Hamilton.”</a> I spent the whole day at the Beacon Theatre, drawing the morning dress rehearsal and the mixture of sadness and celebration during the evening&#8217;s events, which were a reminder, as James Corden put it, that “theatre is a place where every race, creed, sexuality, and gender is equal, is embraced, and is loved.” This is what I saw, heard, and felt.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/and-love-is-live-drawing-the-2016-tony-awards</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Gawker Was a Great Place to Become a Journalist</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="descender">At 8 P.M. on October 27, 2009, I sat at my desk in the hallway that I used as an office in my Brooklyn apartment and stared at a blank field on my computer screen where I could type words and hit “publish” and the words would instantly appear on a Web site read by tens of thousands of people. It was the first day of my three-shift tryout as the night editor of Gawker.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/gawker-was-a-great-place-to-become-a-journalist</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>Terms and Conditions</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>IMPORTANT: PLEASE READ CAREFULLY.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/terms-and-conditions</link>
			</item>
	<item>
		<title>The Muhammad Ali Documentary That Gets to the Existential Heart of Boxing</title>
		<description><![CDATA[<p class="descender">The mourning of Muhammad Ali’s death and the celebration of his life have involved the screening of films about him, including William Klein’s “The Greatest” and Leon Gast’s “When We Were Kings.” They’re excellent films, but my favorite documentary about Ali is one that isn’t being screened at the moment and that isn’t currently available on home video or streaming: “The Fight,” directed by William Greaves, from 1974.</p>]]></description>
		<link>http://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/the-muhammad-ali-documentary-that-gets-to-the-existential-heart-of-boxing</link>
			</item>
</channel>
</rss>
