<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Vox -  All</title>
  <icon>https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/community_logos/52517/voxv.png</icon>
  <updated>2016-06-14T14:20:03-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.vox.com/rss/index.xml</id>
  <link type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/" rel="alternate"/>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T14:20:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T14:20:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Donald Trump’s speech scared me as an American Muslim. It should scare you, too.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BH4Ag13OkfeZ1ppEdJBlG95VAOg=/0x0:3591x2394/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49855581/Trump_speech.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="a2NpI7"&gt;There was something new — and utterly terrifying — in Donald Trump’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924660/trump-foreign-policy-ignorance-arrogance" target="_blank"&gt;speech on Monday&lt;/a&gt; in response to the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911962/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-orlando-updates-news" target="_blank"&gt;Orlando nightclub shooting&lt;/a&gt;: his portrayal of American Muslims as an internal enemy lurking among us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qcXTcu"&gt;Sure, he’s said Muslims are a threat who must be "temporarily" banned from entering the US before, but what he said about the peaceful Muslims living in America was a new level for him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the Muslim communities so importantly, they have to work with us. They have to cooperate with law enforcement and turn in the people who they know are bad. And they know it. And they have to do it and they have to do it forthwith. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They know what is going on. They know that [the Orlando shooter] was bad. They knew the people in San Bernardino were bad. But you know what, they didn't turn them in, and we had death and destruction. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[W]hen people know what is going on and they don't tell us and we have an attack and people die, these people have to have consequences. Big consequences. America must do more, much more, to protect its citizens. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="w30dLO"&gt;Trump is spinning a wild conspiracy theory: the idea that American Muslims secretly know who all the terrorists are. He's painting the entire American Muslim community as a fifth column — a devious enemy secretly undermining the very nation in which they live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YehOgN"&gt;But Trump is also tapping into some of the darkest aspects of American history. The idea that we should, McCarthy-style, search for enemies among us or risk being painted one ourselves is not so far in our past. And it’s truly frightening to Muslim Americans like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iQcrWJ"&gt;But it should also scare every single American, because we’ve seen this sort of thing happen before in our country — with disastrous consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="DSODyZ"&gt;Muslims already report terrorist activity and extremist views to the authorities all the time&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="96niOb"&gt;Muslim Americans are already &lt;a href="http://www.mpac.org/safespaces/"&gt;actively working&lt;/a&gt; to prevent terrorist attacks and counter extremism in our own communities. We're good Americans, and we want to stop terrorists from carrying out attacks in our name just as much as (and perhaps even more than) anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZJTcKT"&gt;According to &lt;a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/157082/islamophobia-understanding-anti-muslim-sentiment-west.aspx"&gt;Gallup&lt;/a&gt;, "Since 9/11, the Muslim-American community has helped security and law enforcement officials prevent nearly two of every five al Qaeda terrorist plots threatening the United States." Gallup also found that "tips from the Muslim-American community are the largest single source of initial information to authorities about these few plots."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="htjV9h"&gt;We are perhaps more aware than anyone of the consequences of not doing so. Not only do Muslims want to stop the direct loss of life and destruction that can result from an attack, but we also want to halt the damage to our image as a religion and a community whenever someone carries out an attack in our name. American Muslims have every reason to report suspected terrorism activity, and we're not going to stop doing it just because a few politicians say ugly things about us to win votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OkFWmw"&gt;The idea that Muslim Americans are mostly migrants and that Islam is a foreign phenomenon in America is patently false. In the past two-plus centuries, Islam and Muslim Americans &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/12/22/10645956/islam-in-america"&gt;have been intertwined with American history&lt;/a&gt;. Indeed, America’s Founding Fathers &lt;a href="http://www.loc.gov/loc/lcib/0205/tolerance.html"&gt;deliberately sought to include Islam&lt;/a&gt; as they established the principles of religious liberty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="COgwer"&gt;And we continue to be contributing members of American society to this day. We're good neighbors: Muslim organizations &lt;a href="http://www.huffingtonpost.com/entry/muslims-raise-over-100000-to-help-rebuild-black-churches-in-the-south_us_55ad4be7e4b0d2ded39fac57"&gt;raised more than $100,000&lt;/a&gt; to help rebuild black churches in the South that were damaged in arson attacks. We're there to lend a hand in a crisis: Muslim Americans &lt;a href="http://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2016/jan/17/rahat-husain-muslims-donate-30000-bottles-water-fl/"&gt;donated 30,000 bottles of water&lt;/a&gt; to the Red Cross in Flint, Michigan, to help Flint residents suffering from the water contamination crisis there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we're patriotic Americans: We fight and die for this country as &lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/US/5000-muslims-serving-us-military-pentagon/story?id=35654904"&gt;members of the US military&lt;/a&gt;, we dedicate our lives to &lt;a href="http://muslimobserver.com/elected-muslim-politicians-federal-and-state-levels/"&gt;public service&lt;/a&gt; in the government, and we earn merit badges, sell cookies, and recite the Pledge of Allegiance in &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/if-you-dont-believe-country-honor-and-allah-can-co-exist-meet-these-muslim-boy-scouts/2015/12/14/137f5674-a26e-11e5-9c4e-be37f66848bb_story.html"&gt;Boy Scout and Girl Scout troops&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="iZTSTW"&gt;Trump’s comments shouldn’t just scare Muslim Americans — they should scare &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; Americans&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="F6kUj9"&gt;That a man who could very well be the next US president is characterizing an entire group of Americans as internal enemy of the state just by virtue of their religion or nationality or identity (and irrespective of their actual beliefs) should terrify every single American.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="g4cq0o"&gt;This is the exact same extremism and fearmongering that led the US government to round up and imprison tens of thousands of Japanese Americans in internment camps during World War II.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="51xTA1"&gt;Take, for example, the congressional testimony of Lt. Gen. John L. DeWitt. DeWitt was head of the US Army’s Western Defense Command in 1942 and was instrumental in the development of Executive Order 9066, which directed the internment of all Japanese Americans living on the West Coast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Lw4FeC"&gt;On April 13, 1943, DeWitt &lt;a href="http://caselaw.findlaw.com/us-supreme-court/323/214.html#fff1"&gt;testified before a congressional subcommittee&lt;/a&gt; on the threat, as he saw it, from Japanese Americans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="5rv9yZ"&gt;I don't want any of them (persons of Japanese ancestry) here. They are a dangerous element. There is no way to determine their loyalty. The west coast contains too many vital installations essential to the defense of the country to allow any Japanese on this coast. …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Uz2tyP"&gt;The danger of the Japanese was, and is now — if they are permitted to come back — espionage and sabotage. It makes no difference whether he is an American citizen, he is still a Japanese. American citizenship does not necessarily determine loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="gNIkoU"&gt;That view that Japanese Americans — just by virtue of their Japanese ancestry — couldn’t be trusted to be loyal to America at a time when the country was at war with Japan led to scenes like this:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/V1hUF8aWQcEL-BPK8nHdXKtkr54=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6646643/Relocation_of_Japanese_Americans_LG.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Library of Congress, via &lt;a href="http://www.digitalhistory.uh.edu/disp_textbook.cfm?smtID=8&amp;amp;psid=4083&amp;amp;filepath=http://www.digitalhistory.uh.edu/primarysources_upload/images/Relocation_of_Japanese_Americans_LG.jpg"&gt;Digital History&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A "relocation center" (internment camp) for Japanese Americans, 1942.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="YSZUy7"&gt;That happened in America. Not Nazi Germany. America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pBktW1"&gt;And it happened because regular Americans like you and me allowed a few powerful and influential people in this country to whip up their fears and prejudices to the point that they lost all sense of decency and humanity and brotherhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OFwShp"&gt;Donald Trump and the &lt;a href="http://foreignpolicy.com/2015/12/08/donald-trump-frank-gaffney-islamophobia-poll/"&gt;anti-Muslim ideologues&lt;/a&gt; feeding his dangerous views are doing the exact same thing right now. It’s up to each and every American to make sure we don’t forget our humanity this time around.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11925278/trump-speech-muslims"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11925278/trump-speech-muslims</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Williams</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T14:19:40-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T14:19:40-04:00</updated>
    <title>Clinton: Trump "is temperamentally unfit and totally unqualified to be commander in chief"</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/EK5O6KGMpt26hR_YK-7NvPe9NIc=/0x0:4189x2793/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49856091/GettyImages-539903784.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="JRJAfi"&gt;Speaking today in Pittsburgh, Hillary Clinton further ratcheted up her rhetoric against Donald Trump, calling him "temperamentally unfit and totally unqualified to be commander in chief."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eoU8ja"&gt;Clinton said she read through Trump’s entire speech on Monday about the Orlando massacre, and said it includes "bizarre rants" and "outright lies" about both President Barack Obama and what led to the attack on the Pulse nightclub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="i2p011"&gt;"Just one day after the massacre, [Trump] went on TV and suggested that President Obama is on the side of the terrorists," Clinton said. "Just think about that. Even in a time of divided politics this is way beyond anything that should be said by someone running for president."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wfT2JQ"&gt;The notion that Trump is unfit to serve isn't new from the Clinton campaign — and it’s not surprising that she'd use his &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924448/donald-trump-lies-speech"&gt;factually challenged speech&lt;/a&gt; yesterday to drive that message home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="kXLYiu"&gt;How Clinton is trying to turn Trump’s anti-establishment rhetoric against him&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Rvc29O"&gt;What &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; new was Clinton reinforcing that argument by draping herself in the authority of America's law enforcement and intelligence professionals — establishment figures who are typically seen as above partisan conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aTJZmN"&gt;"Much of [Trump’s] speech was spent denigrating not just the president, but also the efforts of all the brave Americans — service members, law enforcement agents, intelligence officers, diplomats, and others — who have worked so hard to keep our country safe," Clinton said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IRxQBs"&gt;Trump had ripped President Obama for allowing the ISIS threat to fester in the US, echoing his calls throughout the campaign that America has become "weak" and "not tough."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ITFU3E"&gt;But Clinton turned that message into an attack against Trump, seizing on his criticism of American foreign policy to suggest he was also disrespecting the military.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WCpbUI"&gt;"He says he knows more about ISIS than the generals do," Clinton said, to big laughs. "I don't even know what to say about that."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gJOT54"&gt;Clinton added:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donald says our military is a disaster and the world is laughing at us … wrong again. Since 9/11, America has done a great deal at home and abroad to stop terrorists. Thousands of Americans have fought and died; we have worked intensively with our allies engaged in fierce and vital debates about how far, here at home, our government should go in monitoring threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="jcdLYd"&gt;Now, Democrats are more accustomed to being on the receiving end of this kind of tactic, as Bush-era conservatives often tried to paint strident criticism of administration policy as criticism of American soldiers. For now, at least, Clinton appears to have found a way to throw it back at them.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11934394/clinton-trump-pittsburgh-speech"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11934394/clinton-trump-pittsburgh-speech</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jeff Stein</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T14:10:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T14:10:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Trauma doctors are learning battlefield techniques. And they're saving victims of mass shootings.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xO8Uu0_DMS0MpDxpwWcpMzI9jCs=/0x0:998x665/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49855305/shutterstock_161808101.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;“The only beneficiary of war is medicine.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="UDgB1T"&gt;Amid America’s grim&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.vox.com/2015/10/3/9444417/gun-violence-united-states-america"&gt;epidemic of gun violence&lt;/a&gt;, doctors are learning new ways to save gunshot victims’ lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3RRQlg"&gt;According to the latest reports on the survivors of the mass shooting in Orlando, all of the 44 wounded who made it to the Orlando Regional Medical Center are still alive. Of the 27 who remain in the hospital, six are in critical condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="53FPMC"&gt;"All patients since arrival to the hospital are still with us," Dr. Michael Cheatham, the chief surgical quality officer at Orlando Regional Medical Center, said in a press briefing today. "And they are steadily improving." (Other surviving victims were sent to Florida Hospital in Orlando.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rnWVG4"&gt;Doctors who specialize in trauma care say they expect relatively good outcomes for all of these patients. "I am certain those that made it to the hospital [in Orlando], unless they had devastating injuries, will survive," said M. Margaret Knudson, a professor of surgery at the University of California San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swvSVj"&gt;One surprising reason for hope: a new approach to trauma care honed by military doctors on the battlefields of Iraq and Afghanistan that's been translated for wounded civilians here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hUkpSF"&gt;"During the height of the wars, we were treating injury patterns at a rate that was 10 to 100 times [that which] you would treat in any given city," said Col. Todd Rasmussen, a medical doctor and professor of surgery who served in both wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NptmEd"&gt;That unprecedented burden of injury and the instructive medical research it generated, researchers say, may even be helping gun fatalities&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24452421"&gt;stabilize in this country&lt;/a&gt; — while the rate of gunshot injuries has increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AILAsh"&gt;Rasmussen calls this "once-in-a-generation burden of injury" on the battlefields one of the few "silver linings of the wars."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mjdcub"&gt;Or, as he put it in a &lt;a href="http://journals.lww.com/jtrauma/Citation/2016/01000/The_giving_back___Battlefield_lesson_to_national.23.aspx"&gt;recent paper&lt;/a&gt;, "the only beneficiary of war is medicine."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Here are a few of the recent advances&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;learned on battlefields&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; for responding to life-threatening violence that are helping victims like those in Orlando.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="60PxVL"&gt;1) Stop the bleeding&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="HJKJbF"&gt;The most common reason people die at the scene of a mass casualty event like Orlando is bleeding. (The second most common cause of death at these events is massive brain injury.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fxnfcy"&gt;Before the Iraq and Afghanistan wars, the use of tourniquets in medicine had fallen out of favor. "Tourniquets to control extremity bleeding were not used, and best practice was that they shouldn't be used," said Rasmussen. But new &lt;a href="http://tra.sagepub.com/content/early/2016/02/19/1460408616632026.abstract"&gt;evidence&lt;/a&gt; changed the practice: Military health professionals saw early on that patients on whom tourniquets were used were more likely to survive their injuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DdGJeo"&gt;This change in practice is why the Department of Homeland Security launched the &lt;a href="https://www.dhs.gov/stopthebleed"&gt;Stop the Bleed campaign&lt;/a&gt; in 2015, encouraging bystanders in violent attacks to compress the wounds of victims if health professionals haven’t yet arrived at the scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sadpmw"&gt;"In the last 15 years of war," Knudson added, "those techniques have saved many lives on the battlefield." They also may have saved lives in Orlando, where some of the nightclub goers and bystanders&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/06/13/health/iyw-pulse-nightclub-heroes-trnd/"&gt; made makeshift tourniquets&lt;/a&gt; out of &lt;a href="http://fox43.com/2016/05/09/suspected-gunman-arrested-harrisburg-police-officer-uses-belt-as-tourniquet-to-save-victim/"&gt;T-shirts, bandanas, or belts&lt;/a&gt; to stop the bleeding from the injured around them, according to news reports.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="uXHyTk"&gt;2) Small, stopgap surgeries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class="caption"&gt;Dr. Michael Cheatham, chief surgeon of the Orlando Health Regional Medical Center hospital, addresses reporters in Orlando on Sunday, June 12, 2016.&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="yGJHD2"&gt;Some gunshot victims need immediate surgery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AEG7e2"&gt;But doing all the necessary surgeries immediately in a mass casualty event is usually impossible. So doctors now do smaller and quicker surgeries first, with one key goal: saving lives. This type of care was perfected in Iraq and Afghanistan, and it’s called "damage control surgery."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="purcUO"&gt;For example, for a patient with a more minor blood vessel injury on the leg, doctors may put a small piece of plastic in place (called a "shunt") to keep the blood flowing. That can allow them to move on to do other, more critical surgeries on the same patient or help other patients in a more critical state. Later, the doctors can go back and do a more definitive surgery to repair the broken blood vessel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OOESC5"&gt;"We do these abbreviated surgeries whenever we can," and they help save lives, said Knudson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="qfsGOy"&gt;3) Help clotting by giving blood plasma and platelets first&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="tNNjnS"&gt;Patients wounded by gunshot typically have lost a lot of blood. If they need surgery, they’ll also probably need blood transfusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yUNZVS"&gt;Blood transfusions oftentimes involve supplementing patients with specific blood components (also known as products) — like blood plasma, including red blood cells, which carry oxygen, or platelets, which are essential for making blood clot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4Ooe6g"&gt;In the past, doctors would first respond by giving patients saline solutions (mixtures of sodium chloride in water) in addition to or followed by blood products. But in the recent wars, military doctors started to notice that patients actually fared better when they got the blood products immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q0U60z"&gt;"When someone loses 20 to 30 percent of their blood volume from a gunshot wound," said Rasmussen, "we don't give them ... saline solutions. We try to give plasma, platelets, and packed red blood cells right away."&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Studies conducted during the wars also helped doctors refine the ratios and amounts of blood products to give to the injured. "We learned from military experience that it’s really important to give clotting factors almost first, and in a better ratio," Knudson said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b8lQI5"&gt;That definitely &lt;a href="http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/23192068"&gt;decreased mortality&lt;/a&gt; in military wounds, and it’s dramatically changing the way we care for patients in the civilian world. "Not only does it save some of the blood by using products judiciously but it also allows you to [better] direct what you give," said Knudson.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="lSnFEl"&gt;Despite these advancements in trauma care, there’s still a lot to learn&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class="caption"&gt;Angel Colon, one of the surviving victims of the Pulse nightclub shooting, at the Orlando Regional Medical Center Tuesday in Orlando. (AP Photo/John Raoux)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S0icEQ"&gt;As part of their preparedness plans, all trauma centers have been trained to handle terror attacks and mass shootings. Yet the mass tragedies in the US in recent years still present these facilities with unforeseen hurdles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6TRFfg"&gt;The tragedy in Orlando — the largest mass shooting in recent US history — turned the hospital there into  "a war scene" where "patient after patient after patient" overwhelmed the hospital’s capacity, doctors said at a Tuesday press briefing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mlcz34"&gt;The doctors also were faced with less familiar injuries that are challenging to treat. Joseph Ibrahim, the trauma medical director at  Orlando Regional Medical Center, told reporters, "We saw the gamut of wounds — from wounds to the extremities, the chest, abdomen, and pelvis area — as if they were shot from below ... something we’re not used to seeing." (&lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/science/sciencenow/la-sci-sn-gun-fatalities-20160614-snap-story.html"&gt;Recent evidence&lt;/a&gt; from at least one hospital suggests the types of injuries doctors have seen in recent years are indeed more severe and potentially deadly.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xCjXtQ"&gt;These moments remind us of the urgent need to translate even more lessons from the battlefields back home, said Boston Medical Center vascular surgeon Jeffrey Kalish, who treated victims of the Boston Marathon bombings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="InC6Iq"&gt;At that time in 2013, Kalish said he looked to the military for expertise about how to care for the victims "from day one," applying their experience on treating wounds from an improvised explosive device and related complications — such as ear trauma from the blast and infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5gYrbL"&gt;"We have an amazing wealth of knowledge with the military," he said, "I’m trying to bridge the gap between military and civilian worlds."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fg5jUm"&gt;Others in the scientific community see the opportunity, too. The National Academies of Sciences will release a &lt;a href="http://nationalacademies.org/TraumaCareRelease"&gt;report&lt;/a&gt; on Friday detailing "how military advances can be sustained and translated to the civilian sector."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0fqHpS"&gt;Kalish added: "Something like Boston or Orlando, I can almost guarantee it’s going to happen again." Applying the best evidence from war can save lives when the battlefield moves closer to home.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931438/battlefield-medicine-mass-shootings"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931438/battlefield-medicine-mass-shootings</id>
    <author>
      <name>Julia Belluz</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T13:50:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T13:50:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Sunday was not Omar Mateen’s first time at Pulse, say those who partied with him</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IuJI_bUH50eNCVEvOdXTGrtoero=/0x0:564x376/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49854293/omar-mateen-2.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="Q7cogx"&gt;The FBI will investigate allegations that Omar Mateen, the &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know/in/11676003"&gt;shooter at Pulse nightclub&lt;/a&gt; in Orlando, Florida, on Sunday, had used gay dating apps and frequented the gay club for years, mingling with club-goers, an unnamed official told the &lt;a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/9232a5d04a1b4723b1c461f7058f07d6/latest-some-say-orlando-shooter-was-regular-club"&gt;Associated Press Tuesday morning&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z5DS1q"&gt;Authorities are currently working to&lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/nation/la-na-orlando-nightclub-shooting-20160613-snap-story.html"&gt; extract information&lt;/a&gt; from Mateen’s cellphone, computers, and other items, to understand the motive behind the deadliest shooting rampage in &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911962/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-orlando-updates-news"&gt;modern US history&lt;/a&gt;. Some allege that Mateen's phone and other communication devices may yield clues that show his motivations — which his father alleged may have been &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/orlando-gay-club-gunman-father-shares-anti-gay-views-video-article-1.2671658"&gt;homophobia&lt;/a&gt; in addition to the shooter's claimed&lt;a href="http://www.aljazeera.com/news/2016/06/orlando-omar-mateen-pledged-loyalty-isil-160613174808533.html"&gt; allegiance&lt;/a&gt; to multiple terrorist groups — may have been more complex than initially perceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VcoIB4"&gt;Several who recognize Mateen from Pulse and gay dating apps have stepped forward&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="IafPU4"&gt;Pulse customer &lt;a href="http://www.nbcnews.com/card/fbi-investigates-whether-orlando-gunman-omar-mateen-visited-pulse-massacre-n591626?cid=sm_fb"&gt;Cord Cedeno told MSNBC &lt;/a&gt;on Monday that he recognized Mateen from the app Grindr. He said he blocked Mateen from contacting him "because he was creepy." He also said another friend corresponded with Mateen in 2007 and that Cedeno and others recognized him from the club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EREXvx"&gt;Cedeno added that two of his friends who recognized Mateen from the club itself and several dating apps, including Jack’d, Adam4Adam, and Grindr, had turned their relevant messages over to the FBI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="57kb4q"&gt;Several others have come forward in the past 48 hours with information about Mateen’s visits to Pulse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OJL8gX"&gt;Chris Callen, who performs as a drag queen at Pulse with his partner Ty Smith, told the &lt;a href="http://www.cjad.com/WorldCP/Article.aspx?id=517501"&gt;Canadian Press&lt;/a&gt; that Mateen, who lived in Miami, frequented the club for about three years. He said it did not make sense that Mateen was spurred to go on his rampage after seeing two men kiss in Miami, as was &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know/in/11676003"&gt;originally alleged&lt;/a&gt; by the shooter’s father, Seddique Mateen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvA9Y0"&gt;"That’s bullcrap, right there," he said to the Canadian Press. "That's straight-up crap. He's been around us." Callen added, "He was partying with the people who supposedly drove him to do this?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c2zJNR"&gt;Callen's partner Smith added, "Sometimes he would go over in the corner and sit and drink by himself, and other times he would get so drunk he was loud and belligerent."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="otC0Gc"&gt;Jim Van Horn, another Pulse customer, said he saw Mateen there often and claims he often saw him trying to pick up other men, &lt;a href="http://bigstory.ap.org/article/9232a5d04a1b4723b1c461f7058f07d6/latest-some-say-orlando-shooter-was-regular-club"&gt;according to the AP&lt;/a&gt;. Van Horn said he once talked to Mateen at Pulse, but his friends pulled him away because "they thought he was a strange person."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Yi9hiD"&gt;In fact, Mateen’s former Indian River State College Police Academy classmate from 2006 told the &lt;a href="http://www.palmbeachpost.com/news/news/orlando-shooter-omar-mateen-was-gay-former-classma/nrfwW/"&gt;Palm Beach Post&lt;/a&gt; that other classmates felt sorry for him because he was so awkward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="30yXAM"&gt;"He just wanted to fit in and no one liked him," the unnamed classmate told the Post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7L6Xcn"&gt;The classmate said that he, Mateen, and other students went to gay clubs together. He said Mateen asked him out romantically while at the academy, and that he thinks Mateen was gay but not out. (Mateen graduated from the academy but never served as a police officer, the Post reports).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="R76zLi"&gt;Meanwhile Mateen’s first wife, Sitora Yusufiy, who &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/06/14/us/sitora-yusufiy-omar-mateen-orlando-shooting.html"&gt;said she escaped&lt;/a&gt; their marriage in 2009 because he was abusive, told CNN's&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/OutFrontCNN/status/742501408881168384"&gt; CNN’s Erin Burnett&lt;/a&gt; she wasn't completely sure whether her ex-husband was gay. "I don’t know," she said to Burnett. "He never personally or physically made any indication while we were together, of that. But he did feel very strongly about homosexuality."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nl1qjE"&gt;She added that Mateen disclosed he enjoyed going to nightclubs and partying before they were married, "so I feel like it’s a side of him or a part of him that he lived but probably didn’t want everybody to know about."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hScslF"&gt;Mateen's father, however, who&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/orlando-gay-club-gunman-father-shares-anti-gay-views-video-article-1.2671658"&gt; expressed his own disdain for&lt;/a&gt; homosexuality, doesn't seem to agree that his son could have been gay or bisexual. "If he was gay," he posed to the &lt;a href="http://www.palmbeachpost.com/news/news/orlando-shooter-omar-mateen-was-gay-former-classma/nrfwW/"&gt;Palm Beach Post&lt;/a&gt;, "why would he do something like this?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xYmwb3"&gt;With new testimony and possible cellphone records and other correspondence, &lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/news_blog/director-provides-update-on-orlando-shootings-investigation?utm_campaign=email-Immediate&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;utm_source=extras&amp;amp;utm_content=552987"&gt;FBI investigators are seeking &lt;/a&gt;the answer to this question now.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11933142/omar-mateen-pulse"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11933142/omar-mateen-pulse</id>
    <author>
      <name>Michelle Garcia</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T13:30:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T13:30:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>Financial markets are begging the US, Europe, and Japan to run bigger deficits</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/e71mEUk0gElc8BNW8vVzufA4Rf0=/0x0:3500x2333/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49853555/494023823.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="IdqPAf"&gt;Tuesday marked a chaotic day in international bond markets, in which most of the world’s richest countries saw &lt;a href="http://www.ft.com/intl/cms/s/0/55176cf2-31fc-11e6-ad39-3fee5ffe5b5b.html"&gt;investors eager to snap up their debt&lt;/a&gt;, which pushed interest rates to some historic lows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bYyhW6"&gt;Here’s the Financial Times’s roundup:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German 10-year Bunds traded at &lt;a href="http://markets.ft.com/research/Markets/Bonds"&gt;interest rates below zero for the first time &lt;/a&gt;after Japan’s benchmark fell to a new low of minus 0.185 per cent. As the 10-year gilt yield recorded a new low, 30-year UK government debt dropped below 2 per cent for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Switzerland almost the entire market for Swiss government debt had fallen below zero, with 30-year debt offering an annual yield as low as 5 basis points. The US 10-year Treasury note yield at 1.6 per cent was on course for its lowest close since 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="aGm8fC"&gt;The FT attributes this to investor worries about the UK potentially&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/4/15/11405658/brexit-europe-america" target="_blank"&gt;leaving&lt;/a&gt; the European Union, possibly unleashing some kind of international economic catastrophe. That might be right, though it’s a little hard to see why the consequences would reach as far as Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XuiWDe"&gt;But if the exact cause of the bond boom is a little unclear, the right course of action is really pretty obvious: If the international financial community wants to lend money this cheaply, governments should borrow money and put it to good use. Ideally that would mean spending it on infrastructure projects that are large, expensive, and useful — the kind of thing that will pay dividends for decades to come but that under ordinary times you might shy away from taking on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WhBIfg"&gt;But if you don't believe there are any useful projects or if your country’s political system is simply too gridlocked to find them, there are easy alternatives. Do a broad-based tax cut, for example. In the United States, that would be a cut in Social Security taxes that are paid by every single worker in the country. In Germany or the UK, it would be a cut in the value-added tax that’s paid by everyone who buys anything. Either way, it would mean higher real incomes and real consumption and hopefully an increased pace of business investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3b2I41"&gt;The opportunity to borrow this cheaply (probably) won't last forever, and countries that boost their deficits will (probably) have to reverse course, but while it lasts everyone could be enjoying a better life instead of pointless austerity.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11933594/case-for-bigger-deficits"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11933594/case-for-bigger-deficits</id>
    <author>
      <name>Matthew Yglesias</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T13:20:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T13:20:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>It took a newspaper columnist 7 minutes to buy an AR-15</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UKJzFt4TV-81Uy-rvd1M8BJ7-eE=/0x67:3000x2067/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49853831/GettyImages-159576901.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="NLpv3H"&gt;How long does it take to legally get your hands on an assault rifle similar to the one used in the &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know"&gt;mass shooting in Orlando, Florida&lt;/a&gt; — the deadliest in US history? According to Philadelphia Inquirer Daily News columnist &lt;a href="http://www.philly.com/philly/columnists/helen_ubinas/20160614_Ubinas__I_bought_an_AR-15_semi-automatic_rifle_in_Philly_in_7_minutes.html"&gt;Helen Ubinas&lt;/a&gt;, the answer is seven minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mNFCvy"&gt;Omar Saddiqui Mateen, the 29-year-old American-born shooter who killed 49 people and sent dozens more to the hospital, legally bought a handgun and assault rifle from a licensed Florida gun shop in the weeks prior to staging his attack. He passed the background check and had no criminal record; it was easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JYVdMF"&gt;It was easy for Ubinas, too. "Seven minutes. From the moment I handed the salesperson my driver's license to the moment I passed my background check," Ubinas wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="npUfV3"&gt;She went to the store expecting to need an explanation, or at least to spend an extended amount of time filling out forms. Instead, the assault rifle she was about to buy — similar to the one Mateen used in Orlando — was "on display in the window of the gun shop. It is being promoted as the gun of the week." She filled out less paperwork than she does at a routine doctor’s appointment, and it cost less than $800.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="52tIhJ"&gt;"I told the guy I was on a budget, so I got an AR-15 for $759.99. God bless America," Ubinas wrote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1gF8bL"&gt;It shouldn’t be surprising given the United States' recent tragic history with mass shootings — there have been at least &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/a/mass-shootings-sandy-hook"&gt;1,000 mass shootings&lt;/a&gt; in the US since Sandy Hook in 2012. Ubinas wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it wasn't so easy to get a gun in this country, the 29-year-old gunman who went on a shooting rampage in a popular gay nightclub in Orlando on Sunday wouldn't have been able to buy the weapon he used to &lt;a href="http://www.philly.com/philly/news/20160614_Names_of_Orlando_massacre_victims.html"&gt;kill 49 people&lt;/a&gt; and injure 53.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it wasn't so appallingly easy to get a gun in this country, it wouldn't be easy for the next gunman to deliver the kind of carnage that's as much a part of this country as the American flag.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ubinas decided to turn the gun in to the police: "Spoiler alert: It takes longer than it does to buy a gun."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Go deeper:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="X2U7bJ"&gt;The United States has some of the most lax gun control laws in the world. Vox’s German Lopez &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2015/12/4/9850572/gun-control-us-japan-switzerland-uk-canada"&gt;compares the gun laws&lt;/a&gt; in the US with laws in four other rich countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RigrY7"&gt;America has a gun problem. Lopez &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/10/3/9444417/gun-violence-united-states-america"&gt;explains&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vFhUTP"&gt;Gun control is one way to address terrorism, Vox’s &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11912104/terrorism-gun-control"&gt;Zack Beauchamp argues&lt;/a&gt;: "The more we treat terrorism as something totally separate from, and scarier than, our gun problem, the more we help terrorists seem stronger than they are."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;18 charts that explain gun violence in America&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="18 charts that explain gun violence in America | 5642" data-volume-uuid="7c311cc88" data-volume-id="5642" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" id="volume-placement-7044" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11932492/orlando-how-to-buy-ar-15"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11932492/orlando-how-to-buy-ar-15</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tara Golshan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T13:10:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T13:10:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>President Obama just won a huge court victory on net neutrality</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/st-nUwXhVFir9G-xdEREW_6-Pzo=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49854161/539888642.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="6pm7uo"&gt;When the Federal Communications Commission published its &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/3/16/8223785/net-neutrality-400-pages"&gt;massive 400-page network neutrality ruling&lt;/a&gt; last year, everyone knew the fight wasn't over. Almost immediately, broadband providers filed lawsuits, arguing that the agency’s ambitious rules far exceeded the FCC’s authority.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SotgFm"&gt;And there was a real threat that the courts could undo the agency's work. Twice before — once in 2010 and again in 2014 — the courts had found the rules illegal and ordered the FCC to go back to the drawing board. And the agency's new rules are more ambitious than those past efforts, which left ample room for a hostile court to find fault.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fEoSSz"&gt;The DC Circuit Court heard arguments in the case last December and &lt;a href="http://pdfserver.amlaw.com/nlj/6-14-16%20DC%20Circuit%20net%20neutrality%20opinion.pdf"&gt;published its ruling&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday. The ruling represents a total victory for the FCC and its chair, Tom Wheeler. It also represents a victory for President Barack Obama, who named Wheeler to lead the FCC and has championed Wheeler’s approach to network neutrality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4dTM4B"&gt;The court systematically rejected the legal arguments thrown against Wheeler’s network neutrality rules, leaving in place the most sweeping regulation of broadband internet access in more than a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oilgMd"&gt;The ruling could still be appealed to a broader panel of DC Circuit judges or to the United States Supreme Court. Still, after a decade of legal limbo, the FCC is finally within striking distance of having its rules accepted by the courts. Not only that, but the court’s ruling makes it clear that the FCC has broad authority to regulate broadband internet access, which means we could see even more aggressive FCC action on this front in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Nnkwu5"&gt;Every challenge to the FCC’s rules fell flat&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="2016 Common Sense Media Awards" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/kUIYTfMJozi06CT7Snc10S9jszY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6647357/527829832.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Matthew Eisman/Getty Images for Common Sense Media&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;FCC Chair Tom Wheeler.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="9hzDdJ"&gt;If you followed the big network neutrality debate in 2014 and early 2015, you likely encountered a seemingly endless list of legal problems with the FCC’s approach. Critics seemed to find fault with every aspect of the FCC’s rules, arguing that the agency had exceeded the authority granted to it by Congress, failed to follow standard procedures in enacting the rules, and even violated the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0xlM8A"&gt;Indeed, these concerns were a major reason that the FCC’s final order was 400 pages long. The agency knew that big broadband providers and their allies would throw every legal argument they could think of at the rules to try to destroy them. So it went to great length to explain and justify its every decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="31j0ty"&gt;That diligence paid off. The court’s majority (the panel voted 2 to 1) examined a long list of arguments against the regulations and found each and every one of them to be without merit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7fV8tJ"&gt;A lot of opponents’ arguments focused on allegations that the FCC had failed to follow proper procedures in enacting the new regulations. The law requires an agency to give clear notice of proposed rules and give the public time to comment on them. Challengers argued that the FCC failed to do this because its final regulation different in significant ways from its original proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZTFqTB"&gt;But this argument proved to have a big problem: While critics &lt;em&gt;claimed&lt;/em&gt; they hadn’t had sufficient opportunity to comment on the FCC’s decisions, the record told a different story. During the FCC’s comment period, network neutrality opponents filed extensive comments addressing exactly the issues that challengers subsequently complained they hadn’t had an opportunity to address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="HJjd1c"&gt;The ruling means expanded FCC authority to regulate broadband markets&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Democratic Presidential Candidate Hillary Clinton Campaigns In Cleveland, Ohio" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ZVrztcPWHmH_nfg-mkg_kRCZh5k=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6647367/539913058.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Photo by Angelo Merendino/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;If Hillary Clinton wins the White House, her FCC chair will have broad latitude to regulate broadband service.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="bwpRc6"&gt;The crucial legal issue in the case was whether the FCC had the power to apply a legal framework originally designed for monopoly telephone providers to the internet. When Congress passed the Telecommunications Act of 1996, it drew a distinction between "telecommunications services," which provide the capability to move information from one place to another, and "information services" that allow users to store, access, and manipulate information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6h5Jjd"&gt;The reasoning here was simple: Telecommunications services have a tendency toward monopoly (local phone service is a telecommunications service, for example), so Congress wanted the FCC to have broader authority to regulate them in the public interest. In contrast, online services were a more competitive market and a market that was still in its infancy, so Congress wanted to shield it from excessive FCC regulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="brLk59"&gt;When broadband service emerged in the late 1990s, many people assumed it would be classified as a telecommunications service, and that’s how the early DSL-based broadband services provided by telephone companies were regulated. But under the George W. Bush administration, the FCC changed its approach and started classifying broadband as an information service — a move that freed it from most regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v3LuKE"&gt;The Supreme Court upheld this approach in 2005 in a &lt;a href="https://www.law.cornell.edu/supct/html/04-277.ZS.html"&gt;6-3 decision&lt;/a&gt;. The three dissenting justices argued that the statute &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; the FCC to keep broadband under the more regulated legal framework. But the six-justice majority found that the law was ambiguous and therefore the FCC could decide how to regulate it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tQjCdI"&gt;In 2015, the FCC decided to switch back to regulating broadband as a telecommunications service, a move that expands its authority over these services. But critics now argued that this move was illegal — that the law not only &lt;em&gt;allowed&lt;/em&gt; the FCC to treat broadband as an information services but &lt;em&gt;required&lt;/em&gt; it to do so. Significantly, neither side in the Supreme Court’s landmark 2005 ruling went this far.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aoe6Pa"&gt;Their main argument was that many internet service providers bundled online services like email access and web hosting along with basic broadband service. If you sign up for Verizon broadband service, for example, you might get a &lt;a href="http://Verizon.net"&gt;Verizon.net&lt;/a&gt; email address. Everyone agrees that email is an information service, and big telecommunications companies argued that the FCC should treat the entire bundle — including broadband connectivity — as an information service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ap9TuQ"&gt;But the DC Circuit majority wasn’t convinced. Following the Supreme Court’s precedent, the judges ruled that it’s up to the FCC to decide how to regulate broadband service. The decision to treat it as an information service from 2005 to 2015 was allowed under the statute. So was its decision to treat it as a telecommunications service today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wUkbr9"&gt;That might sound fairly arcane — and it is — but it also has big implications for the future of internet regulation. The reason the FCC has faced such an uphill battle regulating the internet over the past decade is that the agency was trying to protect the open internet while maintaining the highly restrictive "information service" classification. The courts found that the rules governing information services simply didn't allow the kinds of regulations the FCC wanted to impose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lACNVL"&gt;But the laws governing telecommunications services are different, and far more favorable to FCC authority. At the time of the 1996 Telecommunications Act, the breakup of the old AT&amp;amp;T monopoly was only 12 years in the past — Congress wanted to make sure the FCC had the authority to deal with those kinds of monopolies in the future. So Congress gave the FCC broad authority to regulate telecommunications services to promote competition and protect users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0pm6db"&gt;That means the FCC now has a new, broader set of tools to regulate big broadband providers like Comcast and Verizon. If Hillary Clinton captures the White House this fall, we could see an activist FCC aggressively enforcing Wheeler's rules over the next four years — or even expanding on them. And even if Donald Trump takes the White House and his FCC reverses Wheeler’s rules, the door will be open for stronger regulations under more liberal administrations in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Correction:&lt;/b&gt; The 2005 &lt;i&gt;Brand X&lt;/i&gt; Supreme Court decision was decided 6-3, not 5-4 as I originally stated.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11933326/net-neutrality-ruling-obama"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11933326/net-neutrality-ruling-obama</id>
    <author>
      <name>Timothy B. Lee</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T13:00:04-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T13:00:04-04:00</updated>
    <title>The AR-15, the gun behind some of the worst mass shootings in America, explained</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/NDRQuCC1UbNVJ48kE534avmmm_0=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49852973/158539059.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="DeIOzC"&gt;Some of the worst mass shootings, the ones that turn the names of American towns into a universal shorthand for tragedy, have all used similar guns: versions of the AR-15 assault rifle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="M0s3EQ"&gt;The 20 children and six adults who died in Newtown were killed, in part, by a version of the AR-15. So were the 12 who died in an Aurora, Colorado, movie theater. So were the 14 who died in San Bernardino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wyQ7uK"&gt;After Sunday's shooting in Orlando, carried out with the Sig Sauer MCX, a military-style assault rifle that looks much like the AR-15, calls to ban the&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;AR-15 are surging. The Boston Globe described it as &lt;a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/news/nation/2016/06/12/gun-used-orlando-shooting-becoming-mass-shooters-weapon-choice/8CsglZoMR1jbkoWcKGQZ6H/story.html"&gt;“&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/news/nation/2016/06/12/gun-used-orlando-shooting-becoming-mass-shooters-weapon-choice/8CsglZoMR1jbkoWcKGQZ6H/story.html"&gt;mass shooters’ weapon of choice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.bostonglobe.com/news/nation/2016/06/12/gun-used-orlando-shooting-becoming-mass-shooters-weapon-choice/8CsglZoMR1jbkoWcKGQZ6H/story.html"&gt;."&lt;/a&gt; The New York Daily News called it &lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/orlando-club-shooter-ar-15-rifle-newtown-article-1.2670739"&gt;“&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/orlando-club-shooter-ar-15-rifle-newtown-article-1.2670739"&gt;a mass murderer’s best friend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.nydailynews.com/news/national/orlando-club-shooter-ar-15-rifle-newtown-article-1.2670739"&gt;.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lzU0nr"&gt;The AR-15 has come to stand in for an entire category of military-style assault rifles developed for combat that many believe have no place in civilian life. The irony is that the outrage will almost certainly boost AR-15 sales. Historically, the more the AR-15 and other assault weapons are criticized, the more guns their supporters buy. And the more AR-15s there are in American hands, the harder it gets to regulate them, both politically and practically. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="eGuw1f"&gt;The AR-15 is a military-style rifle that civilians can use&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="AR-15 at Florida gun store" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/YP1hICeDXLss7tkh3bMvaZfaXKU=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6646865/159576904.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Joe Raedle/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;An AR-15 for sale at a gun store in Florida.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="5aIsyF"&gt;The AR-15, a trademark owned by Colt but applied to wide range of near-identical guns from different manufacturers, is a civilian version of the M16, a weapon designed for military combat in Vietnam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="r4UGd9"&gt;It's very difficult for civilians to own an M16. The gun, which can shoot up to three bullets in a single burst, is strictly regulated by the National Firearms Act, the 1934 law that restricted the possession of machine guns. The AR-15, though, is semiautomatic — you have to pull the trigger for each bullet — and so has no such restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hs2DkL"&gt;Since 2009, gun manufacturers have preferred to call these guns “modern sporting rifles,” a name that conjures up hunters in the woods rather than soldiers shooting at the enemy. But &lt;a href="http://www.offthegridnews.com/survival-hunting/turning-the-ar-15-into-a-great-hunting-rifle/"&gt;even enthusiasts agree that the AR-15 doesn’t shine while hunting&lt;/a&gt;. It’s better at killing people than it is animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7RURMJ"&gt;So there’s another name for AR-15s and guns like them: assault weapons. While exact definitions of the term vary, it typically means a military-style weapon adapted for civilian use, with modifications that can make it more lethal. This graphic shows some of those modifications:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BSEGuzFM4qzFTIhtoSYqDaFslmE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/4339313/assault-weapon2.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Javier Zarracina / Vox&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="SIHeuc"&gt;And since the federal assault weapons ban expired in 2004, AR-15-style rifles and similar guns, including the gun that Orlando shooter Omar Mateen used, have become astronomically popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yqhX19"&gt;The more you try to ban the AR-15, the more popular it gets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="hVQyx8"&gt;The federal assault weapons ban, which went into effect in 1994, banned the sale of AR-15-style guns and high-capacity magazines. It was the first example of a phenomenon that’s driven the AR-15’s popularity for two decades: The more gun owners fear their guns will be taken away, the more assault rifles they want to own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0fAM0V"&gt;As Congress debated the assault weapons ban in 1993, production of assault rifles soared, according to a&lt;a href="https://www.ncjrs.gov/pdffiles1/nij/grants/204431.pdf"&gt; 2004 report from the University of Pennsylvania&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VyfojABCfSP-2zqFbyJxYWcwBxQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6643399/Screen%20Shot%202016-06-13%20at%205.52.29%20PM.png"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="jijJ5e"&gt;Even while the ban was in effect, barring the production of certain kinds of assault weapons, gun manufacturers got around it by creating new “postban” models of guns that went by different names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ha4dYZ"&gt;Olympic Arms began selling a version known as the PCR — &lt;a href="http://www.olyarms.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=31:what-does-the-model-prefix-qpcrq-stand-for&amp;amp;catid=7:general-questions"&gt;“&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.olyarms.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=31:what-does-the-model-prefix-qpcrq-stand-for&amp;amp;catid=7:general-questions"&gt;politically correct rifle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.olyarms.com/index.php?option=com_content&amp;amp;view=article&amp;amp;id=31:what-does-the-model-prefix-qpcrq-stand-for&amp;amp;catid=7:general-questions"&gt;”&lt;/a&gt; — that lacked a threaded barrel and a bayonet lug, two of the features Congress objected to. Colt stopped making the AR-15, but it made the &lt;a href="http://www.guns.com/reviews/colt-match-target/"&gt;Colt Match Target&lt;/a&gt;, which looks pretty similar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L5KiQs"&gt;This has happened at the state level, too: California has an assault weapons ban, but entrepreneurial gun manufacturers &lt;a href="https://www.thetrace.org/2015/12/san-bernardino-shooting-bullet-button/"&gt;have found ways to modify the AR-15&lt;/a&gt; to get around it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SzFotp"&gt;The 1994 assault weapons ban banned the AR-15 by name, including identical versions made by other manufacturers. So as calls to ban the AR-15 intensified this week, some gun defenders argued that the Sig Sauer MCX that Mateen used &lt;a href="http://hotair.com/archives/2016/06/14/about-that-orlando-ar-15-it-wasnt/"&gt;wasn't an AR-15 at all due to slight technical differences&lt;/a&gt;. (Orlando’s police chief, John Mina, initially described the weapon as an AR-15. &lt;a href="http://dailycaller.com/2015/11/02/gun-test-sig-sauer-mcx/"&gt;Reviews of the gun&lt;/a&gt; from before the Orlando shooting often compare it to AR-15-style weapons but also highlight the ways in which it differs from standard AR-15s, such as firing several calibers of bullets.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FE3nxK"&gt;That's unlikely to convince anyone whose real concern is civilian access to military-style weapons. But when it comes to writing precise legislation, those differences matter, which is one reason the movement to protect guns has seized on them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="RYmNXN"&gt;Obama’s election made the AR-15 and other assault weapons a lot more popular&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="wGnHUu"&gt;Gun manufacturers started making more AR-15s again after the assault weapons ban expired. They became more popular as part of a trend for military-style weapons, in part because they’re endlessly customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XLKzLq"&gt;But sales didn't really take off for four more years, until President Barack Obama was elected in 2008, when &lt;a href="http://www.mcclatchydc.com/news/nation-world/national/article24742864.html"&gt;gun sales of all kinds began to soar&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hLYIrQ"&gt;Smith and Wesson manufactured nearly 10 times as many M&amp;amp;P15s, its AR-15 equivalent, in 2008 than in 2006. Their output tripled again in the next year. By December 2012, when the AR-15 became the focus of a debate after the Newtown shootings, there were about 3.8 million AR-15s in circulation in the US, &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/blogs/crime/2012/12/20/assault_rifle_stats_how_many_assault_rifles_are_there_in_america.html"&gt;Slate’s Justin Peters&lt;/a&gt; estimated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Wra4hn"&gt;Then, for a brief moment after the Newtown shootings, additional gun control in the US seemed possible. Obama called for new gun control legislation, including a renewal of the federal assault weapons ban. Connecticut, New York, and Maryland expanded their own state bans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LvXw7I"&gt;And sales of AR-15s went nuts. &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/02/03/business/the-ar-15-the-most-wanted-gun-in-america.html"&gt;Retail stores doubled or tripled prices in the first months of 2013&lt;/a&gt;, finding that desperate gun owners, worried the weapons would be banned, would pay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XbFge1"&gt;The more popular the guns get, the harder it becomes to actually ban them. There are so many AR-15s now owned in the US that gun aficionados argued in summer 2013 that the market was saturated. That means that if a new assault weapons ban, like the 1994 version, grandfathered in guns that people already owned, there would still be millions of AR-15s available in the US. A buyback could get some of those guns off the street, but it would also be expensive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="02PmXK"&gt;Still, AR-15 owners are still outnumbered. Assault rifles are a tiny slice of the more than 300 million guns in circulation in the US. The majority of Americans don’t own guns at all, and the&lt;a href="http://www.gallup.com/opinion/polling-matters/187511/american-public-opinion-guns.aspx"&gt; majority of Americans favor stricter gun laws&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tTwhsB"&gt;But the rush to buy AR-15s every time a politician mentions gun control illustrates why the National Rifle Association has so much political clout. Its 5 million members care deeply about their guns, &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/12/4/9844502/why-is-the-nra-so-powerful"&gt;a combination of campaign money, political power, and a single focus&lt;/a&gt; that gun control supporters don't have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="7bhNtM"&gt;The other hurdle to banning AR-15s: the Supreme Court&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id="Z7Xweb"&gt;
&lt;div id="gun-homicides-by-type-of-gun__graphic"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src="http://apps.voxmedia.com/graphics/vox-gun-homicide-type/javascripts/pym-de345a28.js" type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;!--
new pym.Parent('gun-homicides-by-type-of-gun__graphic', 'http://apps.voxmedia.com/graphics/vox-gun-homicide-type/', {xdomain: '.*\.voxmedia\.com'});
// --&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="I7kkLk"&gt;Assault rifles aren’t the only weapon of choice in mass shootings: The Virginia Tech and Charleston mass shootings were tragic and traumatizing, and the shooters in each only used handguns. But they get special attention both because those weapons formerly were banned and because the number of mass shootings appears to have risen since the assault weapons ban expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CIxuom"&gt;Between 1984 and 1993, according to the 2004 University of Pennsylvania study on the assault weapons ban, there were 15 mass shootings that killed at least six people or wounded at least 12. Assault weapons were used in only six of these shootings, but those shootings killed and injured more people than the other nine combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="2RlAAd"&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.motherjones.com/politics/2012/12/mass-shootings-mother-jones-full-data"&gt;Mother Jones&lt;/a&gt;, which tracks mass shootings that meet specific criteria, counts 46 mass shootings since 2004, when the assault weapons ban expired. Of those 46 shootings, 14 featured assault rifles, including Newtown, Aurora, and San Bernardino. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SDwxG0"&gt;And assault rifles appear to be becoming more popular among mass shooters. In 2015, five of the seven mass shootings Mother Jones logged featured a shooter carrying an assault rifle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DDg7PI"&gt;In the wake of Newtown, a few states did tighten their gun laws, including bans on AR-15s. The Supreme Court might soon have to weigh in on whether those bans are constitutional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fp2IDh"&gt;A case against Maryland’s assault weapons ban is making its way through the courts, and in the most recent development, the Fourth Circuit sent that case, &lt;a href="http://michellawyers.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/10/Kolbe-v.-Hogan_Opinion.pdf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kolbe v. Hogan&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;,&lt;/em&gt; back for stricter review at the trial court level. Two conservative justices seemed very skeptical that banning the AR-15 was constitutional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7fuZKS"&gt;The reason the Fourth Circuit judges cited was from &lt;em&gt;District of Columbia v. Heller &lt;/em&gt;— the 2008 decision that found a constitutional right to own a handgun for self-defense — which included a line saying that, constitutionally, “dangerous and unusual” weapons could still be prohibited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yVqWNB"&gt;The AR-15 is certainly dangerous. But it isn’t necessarily unusual. If there were nearly 4 million AR-15s in the hands of American gun owners in 2012, before the Sandy Hook-induced panic, there are almost certainly more now. The specter of a federal ban could make them more popular still. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WouEzg"&gt;So the AR-15 is caught in a cycle. The more it’s used in high-profile mass shooting cases, the more people want to ban it. The more people want to ban it, the more AR-15s are sold. And the more AR-15s are sold, the harder it becomes to create a ban that would be able to stop the next tragedy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr id="99swhX"&gt;
&lt;p id="rE4yJu"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Correction:&lt;/strong&gt; A previous version of this article misstated the year the National Firearms Act was passed.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11924544/ar-15-orlando-assault-weapons"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11924544/ar-15-orlando-assault-weapons</id>
    <author>
      <name>Libby Nelson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T12:46:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T12:46:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>A highly accurate simulation of what it’s like to be a Republican in the age of Trump</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/VgBZEMgWwx3SsnRFFkusZIFfsBc=/0x0:2040x1360/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49793889/466939435.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;If it wasn't clear to Republicans before, it should be clear now: Donald Trump doesn't care what you say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can strongly hint that he needs to tone it down. He'll amp it up. You can call his comments&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/7/11875850/donald-trump-racist-paul-ryan" target="_blank"&gt;"the very definition of racism."&lt;/a&gt; He'll say them louder and tell his surrogates to back him up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One argument for Republican establishment leaders to endorse Trump was that they'd be able to guide his campaign better from the inside — that he'd understand constructive criticism was intended to be constructive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the reverse is happening. Republican establishment leaders aren't controlling Trump's message; he's controlling theirs, by providing an endless stream of controversies for them to respond to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sen. Lindsey Graham (R-SC) has proposed the nuclear option: He's asking his fellow Republicans to withdraw their endorsements of Trump. But Trump is still the party's presumptive nominee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's easy to understand why Republicans who've endorsed Trump don't feel like they have any good options. Here, see if you can do better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="autotune" data-analytics-label="vox-when-donald-trump-says-something-offensive-what-do-you-do:2669" id="vox-when-donald-trump-says-something-offensive-what-do-you-do__graphic"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;!--
 (function() { var l = function() { new pym.Parent( 'vox-when-donald-trump-says-something-offensive-what-do-you-do__graphic', 'https://apps.voxmedia.com/at/vox-when-donald-trump-says-something-offensive-what-do-you-do/'); }; if(typeof(pym) === 'undefined') { var h = document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0], s = document.createElement('script'); s.type = 'text/javascript'; s.src = 'https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/pym/0.4.5/pym.js'; s.onload = l; h.appendChild(s); } else { l(); } })();
// --&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/7/11876198/republicans-respond-trump"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/7/11876198/republicans-respond-trump</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dara Lind</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T12:00:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T12:00:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Girls is a beautiful new novel about cults and teen girl friendships</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/qQtpbV_U8urZsekyNuewuPIS-mc=/0x299:713x774/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49852241/CLINE_TheGirls_final_20jacket.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="CPh3iY"&gt;Emma Cline’s newly released, widely acclaimed debut novel &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.amazon.com/Girls-Novel-Emma-Cline/dp/081299860X/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1465836325&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=the+girls"&gt;The Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is ostensibly based on the Manson family murders. But as I read it, I was reminded of nothing so much as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108872/?ref_=nv_sr_1"&gt;My So-Called Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;the cult teen TV series that ran for all of 19 episodes in 1994. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wAf833"&gt;At the heart of &lt;em&gt;My So-Called Life &lt;/em&gt;is the alternately vicious and tender relationship between the show’s protagonist, middle-class and average Angela, and her new best friend, the wild and unpredictable Rayanne. Here’s how another character describes the two of&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote id="CB3rft"&gt;&lt;p&gt;No, don't you remember, there would be like this one person who had like perfect hair, or perfect breasts, or they were just so funny, and you just wanted to eat them up? Just live in their bed. Just be them. Like everybody else was in black and white and that person was in color. Well, Rayanne thinks Angela is in color. &lt;em&gt;Major&lt;/em&gt; color.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="VfMPXK"&gt;Theirs is a classic teen girl friendship dynamic, in which two girls become absorbed in each other to the exclusion of all else, creating their own insular world. It’s an intense type of relationship, one whose edges tremble with both resentment (Is that other girl so wonderful that I want to be her? Do I in fact hate her for that?) and eroticism (Is she so wonderful that I want to sleep with her?). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3K0HFt"&gt;That mixture of resentment and eroticism is what finally leads Rayanne to sleep with Angela’s ex-boyfriend on &lt;em&gt;My So-Called Life&lt;/em&gt;,&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;and it’s what leads Evie, the protagonist of &lt;em&gt;Girls&lt;/em&gt;, to come dangerously close to committing&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;murder&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt; As Cline makes clear, this sort of friendship can hew&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;unnervingly close to the experience of being in a cult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sjds42"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Girls,&lt;/em&gt; meeting Suzanne adds color to Evie’s black-and-white life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="vP6433"&gt;Evie is 14 years old as &lt;em&gt;The Girls &lt;/em&gt;opens, and she’s stuck in one of those pockets of dead time that can afflict you at that age. School’s out for the summer. She’s too old for summer camp, too young for a job. Her parents are divorced and subsequently have no time for her. She’s grown estranged from her best friend. She’s in a dull, black-and-white period. So it makes perfect sense that when Evie first meets older, worldlier Suzanne, Suzanne is in &lt;em&gt;major &lt;/em&gt;color:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote id="qqkine"&gt;&lt;p&gt;As soon as I’d caught sight of the girls cutting their way through the park, my attention stayed pinned on them. The black-haired girl with her attendants, their laughter a rebuke to my aloneness. I was waiting for something without knowing what. And then it happened. Quick, but still I saw it: The girl with black hair pulled down the neckline of her dress for a brief second, exposing the red nipple of her bare breast. Right in the middle of a park swarming with people. … The sight of them; the gruesomely fetal quality of the chicken; the cherry of the girl’s single nipple. All of it was so garish, and maybe that’s why I kept thinking of them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="8AgntA"&gt;Evie is immediately infatuated with black-haired Suzanne, and yearning to be close to Suzanne is what leads her to the headquarters of &lt;em&gt;The Girls&lt;/em&gt;’ Manson Family analogue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="CKCLGP"&gt;Evie’s bond with her cult leader has less to do with him than with her desire to be close to Suzanne&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="9ZZeJR"&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The Girls&lt;/em&gt;, Charles Manson is named Russell, but he’s still an aspiring musician who surrounds himself with lonely, impressionable people, promising that he understands their pain and their problems and that through him they can be healed. And like Manson, Russell surrounds himself mostly with young girls he can use for sex — for his own gratification, and to trade to other men as a bargaining chip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GzcdCI"&gt;Evie isn’t all that hung up on Russell. Like everyone else at the squalid, trash-ridden ranch where he camps out, she admires his overwhelming charisma, and when the others tell her he can do anything, she believes them. But the platitudes Russell offers her — that she has smart eyes, that she seems sad — are so banal that even sheltered, naive Evie isn’t really impressed by them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NJJCkV"&gt;So when she fools around with Russell, it’s not entirely because she’s under his spell. It’s a way to be closer to Suzanne. “I let myself feel like Suzanne,” she thinks as Russell approaches her, “the kind of girl a man would startle at, would want to touch.” Afterward, she feels a kind of conspiratorial glee, the giddiness of being in on a secret, of sharing &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with Suzanne. The next morning, when Suzanne says, “We need gas,” the infatuated Evie echoes in her mind, “We … &lt;em&gt;we &lt;/em&gt;need gas.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KhcBBK"&gt;Before long, Evie is volunteering to steal gas money for Suzanne. She would do anything for Suzanne. She wants to &lt;em&gt;be &lt;/em&gt;Suzanne, so beautiful and worldly and unselfconscious, and her desire occasionally blurs itself into a kind of romantic longing. When Evie finally loses her virginity to one of Russell’s seedy musician friends, Suzanne is in the bed with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="i0LRVF"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The Girls&lt;/em&gt;’ cult plot heightens the stakes of a familiar teen girl friendship dynamic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="2PGABB"&gt;The first line of &lt;em&gt;My So-Called Life &lt;/em&gt;sees Rayanne whispering, “Go, now! Go!” to Angela, urging her to ask strangers for change, but Angela is cracking up too hard to do it. It’s a harmless adolescent prank, barely even a prank, and miles less dangerous and transgressive than the things Suzanne asks Evie to do — but the patterns of the two relationships are the same. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Jj8QAP"&gt;The worldlier girl urges her more innocent friend to do something illicit, and then the worldlier girl can bask in her friend’s admiration and vicariously reexperience the sense of childishness; meanwhile, the more innocent girl embraces the chance to feel wise and experienced, like her worldlier friend. It’s a potent and attractive relationship. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Hl3P0"&gt;What &lt;em&gt;The Girls &lt;/em&gt;does with this familiar friendship story is up the stakes. In a normal American high school, the emotional wreckage of Rayanne and Angela’s friendship is necessarily limited. When Angela learns that Rayanne has betrayed her, it &lt;em&gt;feels &lt;/em&gt;like life and death, even though it’s not. But Evie and Suzanne aren’t in high school. They’re in a cult. It really &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a matter of life and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ee2ibZ"&gt;When Russell finally sends Suzanne and a carful of his other followers off to kill, Evie tags along without really knowing what’s happening. She just wants to be close to Suzanne. And that is, ultimately, what saves Evie from the crime. “Suzanne must have seen the needy swarm of love [in my face],” she thinks. “Must have taken the measure, like a stone dropped in a well.” And in her own ultimate act of love, Suzanne kicks Evie out of the car and leaves her alone on the side of the highway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FKPHFQ"&gt;Looking back on the cult murders as an adult, Evie can’t be sure she wouldn’t have gone along with them if Suzanne hadn’t sent her away. She could have done what Suzanne did, she thinks, very easily: “The hatred she must have felt … hatred like that was not unfamiliar to me.” And so adult Evie comes to the conclusion that in sending her away, Suzanne was performing one last act of identification. “She set me loose into the world like an avatar for the girl she would not be.” &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="jlIVO6"&gt;This slippery kind of teen girl love — by turns solipsistic and selfless, quasi-romantic, and utterly absorbing — is more dangerous than the magnetism of a Russell or a Charles Manson, but it is also the only emotional bond that offers Evie and Suzanne the possibility of redemption. It is &lt;em&gt;The Girls&lt;/em&gt;' beating heart&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11925192/girls-emma-cline-cults-teen-girl-friendships"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11925192/girls-emma-cline-cults-teen-girl-friendships</id>
    <author>
      <name>Constance Grady</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T11:40:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T11:40:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Medicare’s system for chronic illness failed my parents. Here’s how I want to fix it.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/t-m-5MzksXTd4ASiXZKYG5PN3nE=/60x0:5700x3760/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49851321/GettyImages-478658073.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="mqTCRz"&gt;With all the theatrics surrounding presidential politics, the rare media questions on health care tend to spotlight one issue: Are you for or against the Affordable Care Act? Left unasked is how to help the millions of Americans who suffer from chronic illnesses such as heart disease, cancer, diabetes, or stroke — which now make up an astounding 93 percent of Medicare spending.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="k1atVQ"&gt;Chronic illness is a personal issue for me: It was a challenge for both of my parents. My father, an acclaimed journalist of historical nonfiction, suffered from heart disease. My mother, who earned a master’s degree from Yale at a time when few women got master’s degrees, struggled with dementia in her later years. Watching the two of them try to navigate America’s non-system of managing chronic illnesses is something I will never forget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="PEOEb0"&gt;I have been on the front lines helping older Americans make sense of their health care. When I was in my 20s, not long after the program got up and running, I was the co-director of the Oregon Gray Panthers, an advocacy and service organization for the elderly. I spent a lot of time visiting older people in their homes, helping them get through any number of issues — things like finances and health care. Back then, it was common to see a senior bring out a shoebox full of Medicare supplemental insurance policies that weren’t worth the paper they were written on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c3XsG1"&gt;The people who were victimized by these scams, older people who were a part of America’s greatest generation, would shamefully tell me they should have known better. They were ripped off by fast-talking health insurance hucksters; it was clear this was the health care challenge of the day for seniors. It was a lesson that complacency, when it came to the Medicare guarantee, was dangerous. While Medicare brought in a new era of comprehensive medical security to older Americans, it was clear to me the work would not stop there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="J1mkhx"&gt;That experience, and that realization, was one of the reasons I ran for office, and throughout my time representing Oregonians in Congress I have been committed to updating Medicare to stay ahead of tomorrow’s health care challenges and do right by older Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why it's essential to update the Medicare guarantee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since 1965, Medicare has been built around the guarantee to seniors of defined, secure, and high-quality health benefits. Now Medicare must be updated and modernized to meet the challenges of chronic illness, a task for lawmakers that has gone woefully unaddressed in today’s political debate. That means addressing the lack of coordinated, purposeful care, payments that encourage more, possibly unnecessary, services, and the singular focus on medical needs and not the underlying circumstances that lead to those health problems. At a time when 10,000 Americans enter the program every day, seniors have a right to know how the candidates plan to update the Medicare guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aeqvDu"&gt;The crux of the chronic care challenge is this: Millions of American seniors who worked hard on factory lines, in classrooms, or in uniform on the beat now suffer from one or more chronic health conditions. These patients should not have to spend hour after hour of their own time struggling to navigate an overwhelming and byzantine health care system. That is not the true promise of the Medicare guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;How the current system fails people with chronic illness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="4C3xID"&gt;The struggles that people with chronic illness face are manifold. One problem is coordinating care.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;It’s hard enough for somebody who’s perfectly healthy to assemble medical records for a new doctor; consider how difficult it must be for an elderly woman who recently suffered a heart attack. Think about her journeying to a doctor appointment across town in the middle of the day. Or filling a hard-to-find prescription and adding it to an already-daunting battery of pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America’s health care system tells millions of seniors they’re on their own when it comes to managing their chronic illnesses. The result is a full-time job and far too many chances for dangerous errors and missteps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9gImRG"&gt;Today, Medicare inexplicably charges older Americans a copay just to coordinate care among all their doctors. Doesn’t it defy common sense for seniors to pay extra for care coordination that holds costs down? In my view, this charge should be junked, and care coordination should begin right after seniors receive their free physical provided by the Affordable Care Act. This is one of many commonsense changes to Medicare that could improve the lives and health of seniors with chronic diseases, many of whom have stories all too familiar to every American family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="s7410s"&gt;Another problem is the type of care that people with chronic illness have access to. Take a grandmother dealing with arthritis and the early onset of Alzheimer's. Perhaps she’s a cancer survivor, too. Instead of being driven to her doctor every two weeks, let that physician provide her care where she wants to be — at home — rather than in an unfamiliar and antiseptic hospital. Expanding an exciting pilot program, Independence at Home, will allow her to receive care in the comfort of her own home. Early results from this pilot show it saving Medicare $3,000 per beneficiary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="sTJPDk"&gt;Or consider an elderly grandfather with diabetes and heart disease who’s shopping for a Medicare Advantage plan. In a lot of communities, all the options on the menu before him will look largely the same and often insufficient. It's time to make the rules more flexible so that he can get a Medicare Advantage plan tailored to his unique needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yfswNM"&gt;Or take the example of a favorite uncle suddenly hit by a stroke. In that moment, every second counts, and a minute saved can prevent irreparable brain damage. However, some hospitals may not have immediate access to a neurologist, delaying care exactly when it’s needed most. Access to telemedicine — innovative technology that connects doctors and patients even when they are miles away — must be expanded as part of an updated Medicare guarantee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NG7ivR"&gt;It’s not just the presidential race that has overlooked this chronic care challenge. Both parties in Congress have largely missed this dramatic health care transformation. During the congressional debate over the Affordable Care Act in 2009 and 2010, the focus centered on expanding access to health coverage, but there was virtually no mention of the burdens faced by seniors now that Medicare has been largely transformed into a program for treating chronic illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Why I'm hopeful about reform&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="L1yszW"&gt;The good news is there is growing, bipartisan interest in Congress in tackling chronic diseases in Medicare. In the Senate, Finance Committee Chair Orrin Hatch and I, along with Sens. Mark Warner and Johnny Isakson, are working on bipartisan chronic care reform. In the House, Congress members Peter Welch and Erik Paulsen have written legislation that updates the Medicare guarantee to cover chronic illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CkGwPj"&gt;Heart disease, cancer, diabetes, stroke — these conditions are America's health care future. So the next time a presidential or congressional candidate is asked about health care, listen closely for one straightforward question: How would you update the Medicare guarantee?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="USZZhe"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ron Wyden is the senior United States senator from Oregon.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11932128/update-medicare-guarantee"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11932128/update-medicare-guarantee</id>
    <author>
      <name>Ron Wyden</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T11:30:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T11:30:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why crude oil prices have started creeping upward again</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/rQd95reTGJ177ttn5M8Qb68QXx8=/0x71:5683x3860/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49852059/shutterstock_261320069.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="NwCiOW"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/1/12/10755754/crude-oil-prices-falling"&gt;collapse of global crude oil prices&lt;/a&gt; in 2014 was easily one of the biggest energy stories on the planet. By early 2016, oil had slid to $33 per barrel, a level not seen since 2003. Gasoline was dirt cheap, SUVs were coming back in style, Venezuela was imploding, and the US fracking boom started fizzling. It was &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2014/12/16/7401705/oil-prices-falling"&gt;a really big deal&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YrtyTF"&gt;Lately, however, prices have started to creep back up again, rising to &lt;a href="http://www.nasdaq.com/markets/crude-oil-brent.aspx?timeframe=10y"&gt;$50 per barrel&lt;/a&gt; this week. We're still nowhere near the levels seen before the recent crash, but it’s a noticeable uptick, with potentially important ripple effects around the world. So what’s going on?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IliaUuBOPFd19cVLyerZqbvTFNY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6645937/Screen%20Shot%202016-06-14%20at%2010.06.28%20AM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.nasdaq.com/markets/crude-oil-brent.aspx?timeframe=10y"&gt;Nasdaq&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="Dok0F4"&gt;Because oil is so easily shipped and traded around the world, prices (mostly) depend on just two things: global supply and global demand. And the best place to get a handle on these two factors is the International Energy Agency’s monthly &lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/oilmarketreport/omrpublic/"&gt;Oil Market Report&lt;/a&gt;. The graph below, from the latest edition, tells the tale:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/ngp7RrWzFncl95mK4FuD_XVGYNo=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6645985/Ck6DcKtXIAALQrq.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Oil production and consumption noted in millions of barrels per day. (&lt;a href="https://www.iea.org/oilmarketreport/omrpublic/"&gt;IEA Oil Market Report&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="HbjE6d"&gt;As you can see, between 2014 and 2016 the world was pumping out far more oil than anyone needed, causing prices to crash. Oil production (the green line) was surging, driven in large part by the US fracking boom, Iraq’s postwar recovery, and Saudi Arabia’s &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2014/12/16/7401705/oil-prices-falling"&gt;decision to keep its own output high&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, oil consumption (the yellow line) was slowing, held back by economic weakness in China and Europe. All that surplus oil was being stored in inventories (in blue) for later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hFZrRv"&gt;But as of mid-2016, production and consumption are finally coming back into balance, which has pushed prices up. The IEA lists several important factors here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tANRdt"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) A few key sources of oil have &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;been cut off&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; due to disruptions. &lt;/strong&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.cfm?id=26572"&gt;massive wildfires&lt;/a&gt; in Fort McMurray, Alberta, have taken more than 700,000 barrels per day of oil sands production offline. In Nigeria, militants have stepped up their attacks on oil and gas infrastructure. Violence in Libya has hindered oil exports there. And Venezuela’s political situation&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/26/11774482/venezuela-socialist-collapse"&gt;has deteriorated so drastically&lt;/a&gt;, the IEA says, that it may soon hinder oil operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KimC0K"&gt;The US Energy Information Administration &lt;a href="http://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.cfm?id=26592"&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt; that "unplanned global oil supply disruptions" are at their highest level since at least 2011. This has even overwhelmed the fact that Iran &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/JavierBlas2/status/742636870497107968"&gt;has lately added 700,000 barrels per day&lt;/a&gt; to world markets after the US and EU sanctions lifted sanctions as part of the nuclear deal. The net effect is to push prices up:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Qj0tEJE0uQ7fltlc4RcxXlSbXgk=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6646277/chart2.png"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;(&lt;a href="http://www.eia.gov/todayinenergy/detail.cfm?id=26592"&gt;Energy Information Administration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="xRU4at"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Global oil demand is growing faster than expected. &lt;/strong&gt;In part because oil is so cheap, countries are using more of it. The IEA now expects global oil demand to grow by an extra 1.3 million barrels per day in 2016. Partly that’s due to fast-growing developing countries like India. But, surprisingly, US oil demand is also expected to grow this year, by about 255,000 barrels per day. Americans have been taking advantage of cheap gasoline to &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/11/25/9800614/peak-car-driving-rebound"&gt;drive more miles this year&lt;/a&gt; than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oUJx5K"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Low prices are starting to cramp the US shale boom. &lt;/strong&gt;What makes crude oil markets so tricky is that prices depend on production — but production also depends on prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="L0enKK"&gt;Back in the early 2010s, when global crude prices were hovering around $100 per barrel, US energy companies decided it would be profitable to go after costly and hard-to-extract sources of crude, &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/cards/fracking"&gt;using fracking&lt;/a&gt; to get at the oil locked away in the shale formations of Texas and North Dakota. The resulting "shale boom" basically doubled US crude oil production and helped precipitate the global price crash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="67pZqb"&gt;But now those low prices are forcing US drillers to cut back, laying off thousands of workers and idling their drilling rigs. US field production of oil has finally started falling in 2016, as &lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/dnav/pet/hist/LeafHandler.ashx?n=PET&amp;amp;s=MCRFPUS1&amp;amp;f=M"&gt;the chart below shows&lt;/a&gt;. And, overall, the IEA expects US shale production to drop by 500,000 barrels per day this year:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/BbDPmoECg4fsZVS4gm_Yz6EPPlg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6646293/chart.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.eia.gov/dnav/pet/hist/LeafHandler.ashx?n=PET&amp;amp;s=MCRFPUS1&amp;amp;f=M"&gt;Energy Information Administration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Monthly totals shown.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="0kZdpy"&gt;US shale drillers &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/3/27/8301165/oil-production-low-prices"&gt;have been trying to fend off&lt;/a&gt; this day of reckoning by slashing their costs and making their operations more efficient. But at a certain point, economic reality bites down. The shale wells that they’ve already drilled are rapidly becoming depleted (there’s only so much oil a given well can produce), and it will no longer be profitable to drill new wells. (It costs more to extract shale oil than it does for, say, Saudi Arabia or Kuwait or Iraq to pump oil, which is why US production falls first.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4VbURM"&gt;Now here’s where things get really&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;tricky: As US shale producers cut back, global oil production will fall and oil prices will start rising. But at a certain point, if prices rise high enough, those shale drillers will fire up their rigs again and resume drilling. It’s a complicated game of ping-pong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fVpC8Z"&gt;No one knows for sure how high prices have to rise to convince US shale companies to start drilling again. Is it $50 per barrel? $60 per barrel? Some companies may feel burned by last year’s short-lived price rally and are wary about jumping back in to drill only to then lose money when prices consequently fall. Others &lt;a href="http://www.houstonchronicle.com/business/energy/article/Oil-companies-finally-tapping-long-dormant-shale-7044865.php"&gt;may decide to open up wells&lt;/a&gt; that they’ve already drilled but haven’t yet tapped. And if companies &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;start increasing production, what happens to prices? Where is the equilibrium?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yRc6nb"&gt;So if you want to figure out where oil prices will go next, you have to take this all into account. Some of the factors propping up oil prices right now, such as Canada’s wildfires, are only temporary. Others, like violence in Libya and the deterioration of Venezuela, seem more likely to stick around for a while. And then there’s the ever-tricky question of how the US oil industry responds to prices. Plus the fact that the world still has some 3 billion barrels of oil tucked away in storage. No wonder oil prices &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/4/13/11401564/crude-oil-prices-predictions"&gt;are always so tough to predict&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="sR9lev"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Read more:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/4/13/11401564/crude-oil-prices-predictions"&gt;Why crude oil prices keep taking us by surprise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931854/crude-oil-prices-rising"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931854/crude-oil-prices-rising</id>
    <author>
      <name>Brad Plumer</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T11:25:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T11:25:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>"You're Shakespeare, but you're playing Hamlet as well": Gregory Rabassa on translation</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/xwdfJROOByKFWJErpKQ3UbLll60=/0x0:2039x1359/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/31831919/98585259.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Gregory Rabassa, who died Tuesday, was a literary translator, specializing in English translations of Spanish and Portuguese original works. He is perhaps best known for his work with Gabriel Garcia Marquez, who called Rabassa's translation of &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt; &lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;One Hundred Years of Solitude&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt; better than the Spanish original. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;We spoke to him on the phone in 2014, after Marquez' death. The then 92-year-old Rabassa was still sharp, but his wife asked us to print out the interview and send it to him — he didn't use the internet. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;A lightly edited transcript, interspersed with excerpts from Rabassa's memoir &lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.amazon.com/If-This-Treason-Translation-Dyscontents/dp/0811216195"&gt;If This Be Treason&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;, follows.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;Dara Lind: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;When did you first meet Garcia Marquez?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gregory Rabassa: &lt;/b&gt;I haven't had much physical contact with him, because he's living in Mexico and he travels a lot, but I saw him in New York when he was up here. It was very brief. But I had a correspondence with him, mainly to do the translation. And I'd get news back and forth from Julio Cortazar, who I knew quite well. But I didn't have much personal contact with Gabo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;When you did meet him in person, did it confirm your impression from his writing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I knew he was an affable person, which he was. And warm-hearted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the last time he was able to come to the States, I think, because of his Cuban position. The State Department was down on him because of his friendship with Fidel (Castro).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;In your correspondence, what language did you use?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I wrote Spanish. Because I wasn't sure of his English. But I think his English was better than he made it out to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="width: 250.390625px;" class="align-left"&gt;&lt;img style="width: 235.390625px;" src="http://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/imported_assets/2154981/9780060882860_medium.jpg" class="photo" alt="9780060882860_medium"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;A word that Gabo enjoys throwing about in a lot of his writing as an expletive but more often than not as a descriptive term is &lt;/i&gt;mierda&lt;i&gt;, excrement. [.…] It was a favorite word of the novel’s unnamed patriarch and as such it was absolutely essential that it appear in English in its correct earthy and expressive translation. This is how I did it, causing great distress at &lt;/i&gt;The New Yorker.&lt;i&gt; I was given to understand that any number of high-level editorial meetings were held to decide what to do about the word, which had never appeared in the magazine before. [...] Since then I have liked to trumpet the news that in a triumph even greater than his winning the Nobel Prize, García Márquez broke the shit barrier at The New Yorker.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—from &lt;i&gt;If This Be Treason&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cover via &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style="background-color: #ffffff; font-size: 0.8em; text-align: inherit; line-height: 1.5;" href="http://www.harpercollins.com/harperimages/isbn/large/0/9780060882860.jpg"&gt;www.harpercollins.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Have you traveled to Colombia?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I didn't get to his birthplace, but I did go to Cartagena, which he knew very well, and to Bogota. I met some friends of his there — we had a lot of friends in common. It was a long time ago, it must have been twenty years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;So, after you had translated his works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;Did you see anything that you recognized from what you'd translated, or that shed a new light on his work?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I didn't find Colombia that different from other Latin American countries which I knew. If you're familiar with the Hispanic culture, you'll find it in most of the countries. Here and there, the geography is different. But that's regional. There wasn't anything peculiar, shall we say, in Colombia. The stories could take place in Venezuela or Mexico itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;So you'd disagree with those who say that Garcia Marquez is an ineffably Colombian writer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;Oh, yes. He's universal. He reminds me very much of Cervantes. The Quijote is very Spanish — but it's universal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;Did Gabo ever write you with complaints, or corrections?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;No. In fact, he said that (One Hundred Years of Solitude) was better in English. I took that to be a compliment to the English language. He should have written the book in English.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;When you read his later works, do you read the English translation or the Spanish?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I read the Spanish. I look at the English version. Edie Grossman (Garcia Marquez' later translator) does a good job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;Any differences between her style and yours?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;Maybe tone — I think I tended to be a little more lyrical, perhaps a little more adventurous. Other than that, I always let the text lead me, so it's hard to say. I didn't do a page-by-page comparison, with the Spanish in front of me. I didn't think that was proper. I'll leave that to Professor Horrendo &lt;i&gt;(Rabassa's name for the pedants who nitpick his translations).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="width: 250.390625px;" class="align-left"&gt;&lt;img style="width: 235.390625px;" alt="Cover_medium" class="photo" src="http://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/imported_assets/2155017/cover_medium.jpg"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;In Spanish it had been &lt;/i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cronica de una muerte anunciada &lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;and my title immediately fell prey to the pedantic pecking of cocksure commentators. It was pointed out that it should have been "Chronicle of an &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;Announced Death." I hadn't heard a clinker like that in a long time. I could only think of the late Penn Station and a booming voice announcing the departure of some poor soul to the nether world. [...] Quite often I come across the cutesy phrase "chronicle of a ____ foretold" used in some way or another. I can't see how "announced" could possibly have ever caught on like that.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—from &lt;i&gt;If This Be Treason&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="text-align: start;" class="caption"&gt;Cover via &lt;a href="http://www.randomhouse.com/images/dyn/cover/?source=9781400034710&amp;amp;width=300&amp;amp;alternate=images%2Fdyn%2Fcover%2Fno_cover_kdd.gif"&gt;www.randomhouse.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;Were there any of his works that you wished you had been the translator for, or that you caught yourself translating as you read?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I'm essentially lazy, and I'm glad someone else did them. But that is a terrible drawback for a translator who wants to sit down and have a good read. All of a sudden you start translating a phrase here, a phrase there. It slows you down. You have to separate the language. If I'm reading French, I want to read French, and not an English translation, as I go along. And if I'm reading an English translation, I'd rather just read the translation. (Translating while reading) is just too damn pedantic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;But you've said that you can see the original language '"lurking behind" a translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I can feel it sometimes. I can't put my finger on it, but I feel that if you translate a phrase into English from Spanish, it's different from what the phrase would be in Spanish. Grammar may be an influence, part of this. Spanish grammar, in English, it might sound a little archaic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's actually my mythical project that I want to do, is translate &lt;i&gt;One Hundred Years &lt;/i&gt;into Virgilian pentameter and make it a Latin epic. That's what Borges would like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="align-left"&gt;&lt;img alt="9780060531041_medium" class="photo" src="http://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/imported_assets/2154963/9780060531041_medium.jpg" style="width: 235.390625px;"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;I &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;knew I had something good before me. People who had read the novel in Spanish were talking about it intelligently, sometimes not so intelligently, but always with a kind of awe. I suppose that this should have scared me off, but in matters of translation and a few other things I don't frighten easily.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—from &lt;i&gt;If This Be Treason&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="caption"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Cover via &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a style="background-color: #ffffff; line-height: 1.5;" href="http://www.harpercollins.com/harperimages/isbn/large/1/9780060531041.jpg"&gt;www.harpercollins.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;DL:&lt;/b&gt; You've compared translation to music at times, to acting at other times. What's the best metaphor for what translating Gabo was like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;The strongest would be acting. You're playing a role. When you do Shakespeare, you are Shakespeare in a way, because you're coming out with the lines he wrote. But you're playing Hamlet as well. A novel is closest to acting, because you're saying his words — but he has characters as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's most like acting in mood, and word choice. And sometimes you have to ad lib. There are some things you can't do directly — if you get the proper translation, and it just doesn't seem right, you have to add your own words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="line-height: 1.5;"&gt;DL: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;Any last thoughts?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;GR: &lt;/b&gt;I only wish that I had known him better personally. I sort of miss that contact. I didn't have that much. The occasional letter. Some of my authors I got to know, like Julio Cortazar. Gabo seems like a good person to &lt;i&gt;know. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2014/4/20/5628860/hes-universal-a-eulogy-for-gabriel-garcia-marquez-from-his-translator"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2014/4/20/5628860/hes-universal-a-eulogy-for-gabriel-garcia-marquez-from-his-translator</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dara Lind</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T11:10:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T11:10:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch: the Red Hot Chili Peppers sing show tunes, wrestle, and go shirtless on Carpool Karaoke</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/n7TKGIqDJmdni1B6U9jzaaYQ7Bs=/132x0:1304x781/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49851169/Screen_20Shot_202016-06-14_20at_2010.28.08_20AM.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="J7TyQ3"&gt;This just in: The Red Hot Chili Peppers are dorks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JL8QDh"&gt;Granted, appearing on James Corden’s Carpool Karaoke is maybe not the most rock 'n' roll move to begin with. But they kicked off their installment of the &lt;em&gt;Late Late Show&lt;/em&gt; franchise in fine old-school style with a head-banging rendition of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BfOdWSiyWoc"&gt;"Can’t Stop."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KvORB0"&gt;And then bassist Flea launched into an unprompted, a cappella performance of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ly7PONiKGUs"&gt;"Food, Glorious Food,"&lt;/a&gt; from the 1960 musical &lt;em&gt;Oliver!&lt;/em&gt;. It’s such a deep-cut theater nerd song that even Corden — who, let’s all remember, &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11917782/2016-tony-awards-winners-and-losers"&gt;just hosted the Tonys&lt;/a&gt; — didn’t know all the lyrics as he gamely tried to sing along.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="LlFchL"&gt;Flea followed up the excerpts from &lt;em&gt;Oliver! &lt;/em&gt;by forcing Anthony Kiedis to join him in singing "Heemy Leemy," a song the two wrote when they were 15 years old, high, and hiking through the mountains — which contains a whole lot more yodeling than you probably thought was part of the RHCP repertoire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3cWD2a"&gt;And then, after a quick sing-through of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Mr_uHJPUlO8"&gt;"Give It Away"&lt;/a&gt; ("What have you got that you’re going to give to my mum?" demanded a perturbed Corden), they pulled over so that Corden and Kiedis could wrestle on a stranger’s lawn. "I love a good man wrestle!" Corden declared, just before Kiedis pinned him. (Not shown: the homeowner marching out of the house in high dudgeon, demanding to know why minor celebrities were rolling around on the grass, locked in an embrace.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="90TXvW"&gt;You might think the segment couldn’t get weirder or nerdier after that, but following renditions of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YlUKcNNmywk"&gt;"Californication,"&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZKapVmknD74"&gt;"Easily,"&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lwlogyj7nFE"&gt;"Under the Bridge,"&lt;/a&gt; Flea, Kiedis, and Corden all decided to take off their shirts to sing &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0fcRa5Z6LmU"&gt;"The Zephyr Song."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1GHWZs"&gt;"As soon as I took my top off," Corden mused, "it just made me feel &lt;em&gt;great." &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ebH6VX"&gt;"You got elevated," Kiedis said knowingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7yPmNi"&gt;Elevation aside, the group put their shirts back on to conclude with &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JnfyjwChuNU"&gt;"By the Way."&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lkCN2a"&gt;Throughout the whole segment, guitarist Josh Klinghoffer, who joined the band in 2009, watched the rest of the RHCP with barely concealed horror, his face frozen in a rictus of despair, and spoke only to declare that he would &lt;em&gt;never &lt;/em&gt;take his&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;shirt off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TZvBLj"&gt;All the while, Flea was happy as can be, singing along to the bass line of every song, throwing out show tunes, and ripping off his shirt with glee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v0t9Ae"&gt;So if the RHCP are going to be dorks on national television, at least some of them will be having fun.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11932356/watch-red-hot-chili-peppers-carpool-karaoke-james-corden"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11932356/watch-red-hot-chili-peppers-carpool-karaoke-james-corden</id>
    <author>
      <name>Constance Grady</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T11:00:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T11:00:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Why average people decide to become terrorists</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/cMGVb-MBv3o20KaIfB8yjvmfkAE=/0x0:2400x1600/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850925/shutterstock_71131600.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="JosXtZ"&gt;The&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911962/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-orlando-updates-news" target="_blank"&gt;Orlando nightclub&lt;/a&gt; shooter, Omar Mateen, reportedly called 911 and pledged his allegiance to ISIS and its leader, Abu Bakr al-Baghdadi, at some point during Sunday's attack. Now once again we are asking ourselves&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;how an average American could suddenly become capable of committing such a terrible act against his fellow countrymen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DxmcjT"&gt;This threat is often shorthanded as "radicalization." But how it happens, what drives it, and whom it can affect are all commonly misunderstood. And seeing the gap between the way we often talk about radicalization and how it actually works is the first step to understanding and combating it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Lza8xo"&gt;The key thing to understand about "radicalization": It's not exclusive to any one group or religion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="96CvHZ"&gt;Radicalization is the process by which individuals (or groups) come to adopt extremist views, particularly sociopolitical or religious views. But becoming "radicalized" is not the same thing as becoming a terrorist. Not all individuals who adopt radical or extremist views will decide to engage in violence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mwiehJ"&gt;Nor is radicalization unique to any one religion, ethnicity, nationality, or gender identity. As terrorism analysts &lt;a href="http://www.fpri.org/articles/2012/12/us-strategy-countering-violent-extremism-assessment"&gt;William McCants and Clint Watts put it&lt;/a&gt;, "Anyone can potentially sympathize with a terrorist organization if the conditions are right."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CyhkNI"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.britannica.com/event/Oklahoma-City-bombing"&gt;1995 Oklahoma City bombing&lt;/a&gt;, for example, was perpetrated by two white former US Army buddies who held views associated with the extreme right-wing and militantly anti–federal government Patriot movement. As reported by the &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/06/25/us/tally-of-attacks-in-us-challenges-perceptions-of-top-terror-threat.html"&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, a recent study by &lt;a href="http://securitydata.newamerica.net/extremists/deadly-attacks.html"&gt;New America&lt;/a&gt; found that since September 11, 2001, "nearly twice as many people have been killed by white supremacists, antigovernment fanatics and other non-Muslim extremists than by radical Muslims."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HV5AP5"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.fbi.gov/news/pressrel/press-releases/final-report-of-the-william-h.-webster-commission"&gt;The FBI's own report&lt;/a&gt; on terrorist acts in the United States between 1980 and 2005 "identified 318 events (including bombings, arson and malicious destruction, and shootings); only 7% of those events were attributed to Islamic extremists."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="3oKfcB"&gt;The point is while it seems Mateen may have been influenced in part by Islamic extremist ideology, and that this form of radicalization must be taken seriously, radicalization in general can and often does occur in many other forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="TUZLLF"&gt;Adopting extremist views and committing horrendous acts of violence in the name of some "righteous"&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;cause, be it religion or politics or just plain old hatred, isn't something that only Muslims, or Arabs, or immigrants, or any other group of people do. It's something humans do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="4rlcCu"&gt;Are there root causes of radicalization?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="kVV9lW"&gt;There are, broadly speaking, two kinds of factors that might make it more likely for someone to radicalize and adopt a violent jihadist ideology: societal factors and individual factors. None of those mean someone will radicalize for sure, nor do the absence of those factors mean it won't happen, but they're the things that typically coincide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PicENu"&gt;First, here are a few of the societal factors that are typically associated with a higher risk of radicalization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="3J9Mop"&gt;The presence of a large minority population that is socially, politically, and economically marginalized&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="HD9UPC"&gt;Treatment of certain groups as "suspect communities" that are subjected to invasive and overbearing counterterrorism efforts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="rhAHHJ"&gt;A cultural or political hostility toward religion in general or Islam in particular&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="qnMaE0"&gt;Unpopular foreign policies, such as support for repressive regimes or involvement in a military campaign, especially in a predominantly Muslim country (or several of them)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="RkfAjl"&gt;The presence of preexisting recruitment networks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p id="Rqbl8Z"&gt;And here are a few of the individual risk factors. Again, it's not an exhaustive list, and people still have individual agency, but this is meant to help you get a sense of what the experts look for: &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li id="5APFBI"&gt;Personal ties to an already radicalized individual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="10KhS2"&gt;A sense of personal failure, often tied with a yearning to do something important and meaningful with one's life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="OXIsVl"&gt;A desire for adventure, rebellion, and life experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="vHOE0B"&gt;The need to belong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="u0pkhc"&gt;Feelings of compassion and concern for the suffering of others with whom one feels some kind of personal connection, such as one's co-religionists&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id="tnzJjM"&gt;And, of course, good old-fashioned teenage angst &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dq5XSJ"&gt;Who gets radicalized, and how does it happen?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="YQH5zi"&gt;I have bad news: There is no standard model of the radicalization process — although (understandably) that hasn't stopped &lt;a href="http://ann.sagepub.com/content/618/1/80.short"&gt;scholars&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.nypdshield.org/public/SiteFiles/documents/NYPD_Report-Radicalization_in_the_West.pdf"&gt;law enforcement agencies&lt;/a&gt; from trying to construct one. The process differs by individual, and since there is also no standard profile of the "typical" radicalized individual, there is no one single model of how individuals radicalize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wCapo3"&gt;Even if we focus just on Westerners who become violent jihadists, those individuals tend to come from wildly different backgrounds. They’re typically attracted to an extremist ideology for a whole host of different reasons, and take any number of different paths to get there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UoWUkf"&gt;You probably have an image in your head of the "typical" radicalized individual: male, 18 to 24 years old, angry, devout, ultra-conservative Muslim, etc. You know, this guy:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r1eUF0ywp1JUHFrUilmANzAWaZM=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6641223/Nusra_Fighter_Gun_Flag.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;RAMI AL-SAYED/AFP/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="ZrTyBW"&gt;But that's not the whole picture. Not even close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6NW0bU"&gt;The profiles differ even more depending on whether you're looking at the United States or Europe, and even from one country to another within Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RkqgH6"&gt;Just consider, as examples, these three individuals. As you read their stories, you may start to see that there's no such thing as a standard path to radicalization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ii1wXM"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.ibtimes.co.uk/muslim-convert-former-raf-gunner-manchester-admits-trying-join-isis-syria-1559579"&gt;Stephen Gray&lt;/a&gt; is a 32-year-old former British air force serviceman who served in the Iraq War in 2004. Gray, who was born to Christian parents, &lt;a href="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-3245327/Former-RAF-serviceman-converted-Islam-serving-Iraq-admits-trying-travel-Syria-join-terror-group.html"&gt;eventually became disillusioned&lt;/a&gt;, left the air force, converted to Islam, and began working as a bricklayer. He was jailed last month for terrorism offenses after trying twice to travel to Syria to fight with either ISIS or the al-Qaeda-affiliated Nusra Front (apparently he wasn’t particularly concerned which).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8lcVDp"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2015/02/23/world/scottish-teen-isis-recruiter/"&gt;Aqsa Mahmood&lt;/a&gt; is a young woman from a wealthy neighborhood in Scotland who in 2013, at age 19, dropped out of Glasgow University to marry an ISIS fighter in Syria and is now one the group's top recruiters, extolling the virtues of being a jihadist bride on Tumblr and Twitter. As reported by &lt;a href="http://www.thedailybeast.com/articles/2014/09/03/the-bride-of-isis-revealed.html"&gt;the Daily Beast&lt;/a&gt;, "At [age] 15 a process of radicalization appears to have started — apparently hidden from her parents and most of her friends — and she spent increasing amounts of time locked away in her bedroom and interacting on radical Muslim chat forums."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NRg5j0"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.theguardian.com/world/2009/nov/06/fort-hood-shooter-alive?DCMP=EMC-thewrap08"&gt;Nidal Malik Hasan&lt;/a&gt; was a 39-year-old US Army psychiatrist when in 2009 he opened fire at a military base in Fort Hood, Texas, killing 13 people and wounding 28. As an Army psychiatrist, part of his job was to counsel soldiers with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) from their combat tours in Iraq and Afghanistan. It seems the constant deluge of stories got to him, as he was &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2013/08/29/us/jury-weighs-sentence-for-fort-hood-shooting.html"&gt;reportedly&lt;/a&gt; motivated to kill by "a hatred of American military action in the Muslim world and a desire to protect Taliban leaders in Afghanistan."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JMtVdr"&gt;Prison, the internet, social media, and personal ties to friends and family members who are already radicalized are the most common ways people become exposed to extremist ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wYmCVo"&gt;Whether a person is exposed to these ideas sitting alone in her bedroom reading the latest issue of ISIS's propaganda magazine and gradually being persuaded by the violent words and images on the screen; by spending time with a cellmate, friend, or loved one who is already indoctrinated and is eager to spread the "truth" of his newly acquired beliefs; or by interacting on social media with strangers whose ideas and beliefs seem profound and exciting, the common element is exposure to the ideology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="knacz0"&gt;Terrorist groups like ISIS know this, which is why they focus so much on spreading their propaganda in multiple formats — digital magazines, brutally violent videos, an army of useful idiots who parrot their ideology constantly on social media, and individual recruiters who actively seek out people susceptible to radicalization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="Zkl7Uq"&gt;The common perception is that radicalization happens at the mosque. But in fact, with a few &lt;a href="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/uk/home-news/finsbury-park-mosque-emerging-from-the-shadow-of-abu-hamza-9428300.html"&gt;notable exceptions&lt;/a&gt;, individuals are likely not exposed to violent extremist ideology from the imam at the local mosque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qR5pti"&gt;In fact, it is much more likely that an imam who sees someone in his mosque heading down the path to violence will try to intervene to &lt;em&gt;correct &lt;/em&gt;that person's misconceptions about Islam, get the person's family involved, or even report the person to the authorities. For this very reason, people who do embrace a violent jihadist ideology tend to stop going to the mosque.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="fe7VZk"&gt;Even when security services &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; able to identify the radicalized individuals in their communities, it can still be difficult to predict which of those individuals are likely to take the next step and engage in terrorist violence (and thus should be watched closely) versus which are just passive sympathizers. The latter category is just too large for everyone in it to be watched, and in any case, sympathizing is not a crime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6mVp6p"&gt;This seems to have been the case with the Orlando shooter, Omar Mateen. The FBI&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/06/13/us/omar-mateen-early-signs-of-promise-then-abuse-and-suspected-terrorist-ties.html?ref=liveblog"&gt;previously investigated&lt;/a&gt; Mateen several times, including in 2014 when it learned of his connection to &lt;a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/from-florida-boy-to-alleged-suicide-bomber-in-syria-1401579937"&gt;Moner Mohammad Abusalha&lt;/a&gt;, a fellow Floridian who had traveled to join the Nusra Front, ISIS’s al-Qaeda-affiliated rival in Syria, and become the first American suicide bomber in Syria. However, each time the FBI ended up clearing Mateen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QwaHb9"&gt;Here’s the bottom line: People are influenced by more than just external factors. Any one person who decides to join a group like ISIS or carry out attacks in its name is going to be driven most of all by his or her own personal and internal motivations. And that's exactly what makes dealing with radicalization so hard.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11923514/terrorist-radicalization-orlando"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11923514/terrorist-radicalization-orlando</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jennifer Williams</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T10:50:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T10:50:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Do terrorist attacks make a Trump win more likely? Here’s what the research suggests.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/7sr-elD7TyBBdf_L60_BUzAhFrw=/0x0:4672x3115/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850855/GettyImages-539381830.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="3hsKBM"&gt;For some time, political observers have wondered — or feared — whether a major terror attack on American soil could sweep Donald Trump into the White House.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NVH7Q9"&gt;And now, in the wake of the &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know"&gt;mass shooting at the Pulse nightclub&lt;/a&gt; in Orlando — and &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11925122/trump-orlando-foreign-policy-transcript"&gt;Trump’s speech in response&lt;/a&gt; to it, which was filled with anti-Muslim, anti-immigrant rhetoric — the question of what effect terror could have on the presidential campaign seems more urgent than ever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tTwynM"&gt;"Clinton wants to allow radical Islamic terrorists to pour into our country," Trump said &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11925122/trump-orlando-foreign-policy-transcript"&gt;in his Monday speech&lt;/a&gt;. "If we don't get tough and if we don't get smart, and fast, we're not going to have our country anymore."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MzgYYN"&gt;Yet commentators have tended to disagree about how the aftermath of an attack is likely to play out. On the one hand, political scientist Norm Ornstein &lt;a href="https://chorus.voxmedia.com/editor/e4f15d1d-5096-42d0-be37-2b9c7a080386"&gt;suggested&lt;/a&gt; to me that attacks could greatly improve Trump's poor prospects of winning, and &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/blakehounshell/status/712233418390687744"&gt;Politico’s Blake Hounshell tweeted in March&lt;/a&gt; that "America may be one major terrorist attack away from Donald Trump as president."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="spzvyx"&gt;On the other, Trump is an erratic celebrity with no foreign policy experience, and the public could well instead turn to Hillary Clinton, as &lt;a href="http://www.slate.com/articles/news_and_politics/politics/2016/03/why_terrorism_doesn_t_help_donald_trump.html"&gt;Jamelle Bouie&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/plum-line/wp/2016/03/22/dont-assume-terror-attacks-will-help-donald-trump/"&gt;Greg Sargent&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/26/opinion/campaign-stops/the-fears-trump-needs.html?rref=collection%2Fcolumn%2Fross-douthat&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;contentCollection=opinion&amp;amp;region=stream&amp;amp;module=stream_unit&amp;amp;version=latest&amp;amp;contentPlacement=2&amp;amp;pgtype=collection"&gt;Ross Douthat&lt;/a&gt; have argued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NGnyRb"&gt;So over the past few months, I've spoken with several top political scientists who have done research on this question, and reviewed their work to see what implications heightened fears of terror tend to have on voters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q5qiPx"&gt;And according to &lt;a href="http://politicalscience.ucr.edu/people/faculty/jennifer-merolla/"&gt;Jennifer Merolla&lt;/a&gt;, a political scientist at UC Riverside who has long studied how terrorism impacts voters, her research suggests there's more reason to believe Trump would benefit than that Clinton would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xyxQ3F"&gt;"On average, our findings suggest Trump may be advantaged," Merolla told me back in April. (Though she hastened to add that, due to the experience discrepancy, "Hillary Clinton may not be as disadvantaged as other Democrats.")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AiU7bC"&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="Z5qYUl"&gt;Trump’s biggest strengths on the terror issue are that he is a member of the more hawkish party, he uses more aggressive rhetoric, and he may be perceived as a "stronger leader." Plus, sadly enough, some research indicates that even his gender could be an advantage over Clinton when voters’ fear of terror is high. So in a vacuum, there are many reasons to expect Trump to benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3vgMdF"&gt;"Whenever terrorism is in the news, one way people cope with their anxiety and anger is to look for a leader to protect them — and, in a crisis context, to rescue them," Merolla said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JwNZ8N"&gt;Still, it’s inarguable that Trump isn’t a typical Republican candidate, and that he might not benefit to the same degree that ordinary Republicans might.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pSAvCV"&gt;For instance, on Monday morning Trump &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11919998/trump-orlando-muslim-obama-conspiracy"&gt;conspiratorially implied&lt;/a&gt; that President Obama may sympathize with the attackers — an accusation many voters could well recoil from. "The problem is that Trump is kinda this animal that doesn’t behave how people running for president usually behave," &lt;a href="http://people.tamu.edu/~mtkoch/index2_files/Page388.html"&gt;Michael Koch&lt;/a&gt;, a political scientist at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, told me in April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OOndNE"&gt;Of course, every terror incident has its own specific circumstances, and we can’t know whether any particular one — even the Orlando attack, which was the largest mass shooting in US history — will strike a chord with the public in any particular way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CtIfIS"&gt;"It depends on the details, and on&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924648/donald-trump-terrorism-speech"&gt;how these things are spun&lt;/a&gt;," Koch, speaking when the question was still hypothetical, said. "But especially if you could spin it as a Democratic failure, or link it to failures of the Obama administration, it might advantage Trump."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eKEu9r"&gt;And that’s just &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924648/donald-trump-terrorism-speech"&gt;what Trump is trying to do&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="ED5mfZ"&gt;The partisanship factor: Terror attacks often help the more hawkish party&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="George W. Bush" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nxn6OP1BBJusO28bnn_Xxsvv4Q0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2533318/173218695.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="George W. Bush" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Nxn6OP1BBJusO28bnn_Xxsvv4Q0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/2533318/173218695.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Brendan Smialowski / AFP / Getty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="099cBY"&gt;Perhaps the biggest reason to expect that Trump's support would rise after a terror attack is, simply, the party he belongs to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bTKARF"&gt;Polls consistently show that more Americans trust the Republican Party to effectively deal with terrorism than the Democrats. For instance, &lt;a href="http://www.people-press.org/2016/05/05/public-uncertain-divided-over-americas-place-in-the-world/"&gt;a Pew poll earlier last month&lt;/a&gt; gave Republicans a 9-point advantage on the question of which party would more effectively deal with "the terrorist threat at home." (Forty-six percent of respondents thought the GOP would do a better job, and just 37 percent thought Democrats would.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ulzolb"&gt;Furthermore, both experimental and real-world studies have tended to show that in the US and abroad, the major party with a more hawkish reputation usually benefits when international terror becomes a major concern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="LePOmI"&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="ce0MLD"&gt;For instance, Koch, Laron Williams, and Jason Smith studied how quickly various parliamentary governments lost their majority coalitions after transnational terrorist attacks in &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1528-3585.2012.00498.x/abstract"&gt;a 2012 paper&lt;/a&gt;. What they found was that right-leaning governments had an easier time holding on to power than left-leaning governments did. It seems that the left gets more blame for terrorist attacks that occur under their watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="f8yUaS"&gt;Then there's evidence from Israel that indicates that terror helps the right at the ballot box. &lt;a href="http://www.rand.org/content/dam/rand/pubs/working_papers/2008/RAND_WR477-1.pdf"&gt;Claude Berrebi and Esteban Klor found&lt;/a&gt; that a terror attack in an Israeli locality shortly before the election causes, on average, "an increase of 1.35 percentage points on that locality’s support for the right bloc of political parties." And &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2014/7/18/5915543/rocket-israel-elections-likud-right-gaza-hamas-study"&gt;Anna Getmansky and Thomas Zeitzoff found&lt;/a&gt; that after rockets are fired into areas of Israel, even if there are no casualties, support for right-wing parties spikes in those areas by 2 to 6 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xLoxwm"&gt;Finally, you might think the "rally 'round the flag effect" — the idea that public approval of the incumbent shoots up when terror becomes a major issue, &lt;a href="http://www.gallup.com/poll/116500/presidential-approval-ratings-george-bush.aspx"&gt;as occurred for George W. Bush after 9/11&lt;/a&gt; — could benefit Democrats, since they're the party that holds power right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nDHFpU"&gt;Yet Merolla and Elizabeth Zechmeister have found evidence suggesting that Democrats, as the more dovish party, wouldn't necessarily get that boost. &lt;a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayAbstract?fromPage=online&amp;amp;aid=8948586"&gt;In a 2013 paper&lt;/a&gt;, they looked at both survey data comparing times when terror fears are high with times when they aren't, and findings from a lab experiment "priming" only some subjects with the topic of terror. "We find consistent evidence that evaluations of President Obama’s job performance at worst suffer, and at best are unaffected, when people are worried about terrorism," they concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="WbHY8S"&gt;Now, there are occasional examples that cut the other way. The Spanish elections of 2004, three days after the Madrid train bombings, seem to have hurt the right and &lt;a href="http://www.econ.upf.edu/docs/papers/downloads/1000.pdf"&gt;swept a left-wing challenger party&lt;/a&gt; to power. These do appear to be the exception, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="X3lxR3"&gt;The "leadership" and charisma factors&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Trump hat" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/r8ijurXwmdR5wLAgNEH44V8YXF0=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3956550/GettyImages-482347250.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(Jeff J Mitchell/Getty Images)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="yoPIVQ"&gt;Recently, even the polls that show Donald Trump ahead tend to have &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/24/11747294/donald-trump-ahead-poll"&gt;lots of bad news for him&lt;/a&gt; — most voters think he doesn't have the right temperament to be president, is unqualified for the office, and would mainly look out for the interests of the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="4aH7HM"&gt;But Trump's outspokenness and bluster do appear to have accomplished something important — they've convinced many voters that he's "tough."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OsHGUO"&gt;Two recent polls, for instance — from &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/20/us/politics/donald-trump-hillary-clinton-poll.html"&gt;CBS/New York Times&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/page/2010-2019/WashingtonPost/2016/05/22/National-Politics/Polling/release_426.xml?uuid=v4d0jh_REeaCwqfcsxMofQ&amp;amp;tid=a_inl"&gt;ABC/the Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; — show Trump and Clinton essentially tied on the question of which would be a stronger leader. A third, from &lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/interactive/2016/05/18/fox-news-poll-2016-national-release-may-18/"&gt;Fox News&lt;/a&gt;, found Trump heavily advantaged on the question compared with Clinton — 59 percent of respondents in that poll thought he was a "strong leader," compared with just 38 percent who thought he wasn't. (Clinton's split was 49 to 50.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="SeUqLb"&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="lxfvMk"&gt;Merolla and her colleagues have found that when a terror threat looms, this question of "leadership" becomes paramount. In three experimental studies involving three different elections between 2004 and 2008, &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1468-2508.2007.00492.x/abstract"&gt;they found&lt;/a&gt; that when undergraduate subjects were primed to think about the threat of terrorism (by either viewing a short video or reading an article), they were more likely to say they'd vote for the candidate they viewed as a better "leader."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9h0Jd7"&gt;"Crisis situations evoke feelings of distress, anxiety, and hopelessness, which draw citizens to leaders who promise to deliver better times," Merolla and her co-authors &lt;a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1468-2508.2007.00492.x/abstract"&gt;have written&lt;/a&gt;. "Charismatic leaders surface in times of crisis because they are seen as saviors and are perceived to have a unique ability to improve a critical situation."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ytiorq"&gt;Furthermore, in &lt;a href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/40064057?seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents"&gt;a 2004 study&lt;/a&gt;, psychologist Florette Cohen and several co-authors found that if subjects were spurred to think of their own mortality, they then said they'd be more likely to support a hypothetical politician with a charismatic leadership style — one who stresses the importance of bold risk-taking as well as "vision" and "identity of the group." Sound familiar?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EdrhlW"&gt;In Cohen’s study, this "charismatic" leader is contrasted with a hypothetical "task-oriented leader" whose strengths are about effectively achieving goals, and a "relationship-oriented" leader whose strengths are "treating followers compassionately and respectfully" — both of which have often been used &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/1/28/10858464/hillary-clinton-bernie-sanders-political-realism"&gt;to characterize&lt;/a&gt; Hillary Clinton’s &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/7/11879728/hillary-clinton-wins-nomination"&gt;style of leadership&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mZPdLQ"&gt;When people are thinking about their own deaths, they apparently have little time for such niceties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Kw1Uzg"&gt;The gender factor&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UjUyN131eUMdVIdFdrbgfRa_yxA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6640167/GettyImages-538698098.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Katie Falkenberg/Los Angeles Times via Getty&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="iT5Kz5"&gt;When fears of terrorism and death come into people's minds, all sorts of primal feelings can come with them. And Merolla says gender stereotypes might be among them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6Npw19"&gt;"We’ve done some work on what effect terrorism has on evaluations of female candidates," Merolla told me. "And in some of that work, we’ve found that Democratic female candidates are particularly disadvantaged when terrorism is in the news.  Because of party stereotypes and gender stereotypes, they're perceived as being weaker."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PCibTj"&gt;In a study &lt;a href="http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/1554477X.2011.589283"&gt;conducted in 2005&lt;/a&gt;, Merolla and two co-authors again primed terror fears for certain groups of undergraduates. They asked whether their subjects believed that "[m]en make better political leaders than women do," and found that those who viewed a brief presentation about terrorism were more likely to say they did.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="h4DEUH"&gt;The researchers went on to ask respondents what they thought of various political figures — but the results didn't show a simple sexist swing. On the Republican side, both George W. Bush and Condoleezza Rice were viewed more favorably when terrorism was primed. Yet on the Democratic side, views of John Kerry didn't change all that much — but views of Hillary Clinton became sharply worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lp04it"&gt;But the news isn't all bad for Clinton here. Keep in mind that this was before she served as secretary of state — so it's possible that it was mainly her relative lack of experience, not sexism, that explains the different effects for her and Kerry here. (Kerry had, after all, served in the military and had been his party's presidential nominee.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JV8Xf2"&gt;Indeed, Merolla told me that she and her colleagues conducted a similar follow-up study in 2012, after Clinton had gained foreign policy experience. "We have not published this result yet, but we do not find the same negative effect on Clinton as we did in our earlier study," she says. (She did, however, find a negative effect on views of Nancy Pelosi.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uLLTR0"&gt;Still, perceptions of Clinton didn't significantly &lt;em&gt;improve&lt;/em&gt; either — Clinton didn't get the same boost that Bush or Rice did in the earlier study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="by6JLr"&gt;Trump thinks the issue will work in his favor&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="9B2Xxj"&gt;Now, there are limitations to studies like Merolla's — they take place in an artificial lab setting instead of the far more complex real world, and the usual subjects (undergraduates) aren’t representative of the electorate as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bSrITa"&gt;Still, they are bolstered by that real-world evidence that terrorism often benefits the right politically, like the studies of Israel and parliamentary governments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W8v60Y"&gt;Furthermore, if merely bringing up the &lt;em&gt;possibility&lt;/em&gt; of terrorist attacks is enough to produce these effects in a lab among liberal-leaning undergraduates, the response to an &lt;em&gt;actual &lt;/em&gt;attack in the country could well be even more pronounced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="gCXOJR"&gt;The bigger drawback is, unavoidably, that Trump’s uniqueness as a candidate gives us very little precedent for evaluating how his singular features — his erraticism, his penchant for conspiracy theories, and the fact that he's never held political office — could help or hurt him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="EwmTrK"&gt;Still, to be confident that Trump &lt;em&gt;wouldn't&lt;/em&gt; be helped by a terror attack, you basically have to assume he's not an ordinary Republican candidate and that the electorate won't view him as such. Even though, since he’s clinched the nomination, the &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/23/11745036/donald-trump-hillary-clinton-polls"&gt;polls have gotten closer&lt;/a&gt; and the vast majority of GOP voters &lt;a href="http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/gop-voters-are-rallying-behind-trump-as-if-he-were-any-other-candidate/"&gt;have fallen behind him&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rb64Cr"&gt;And keep in mind Michael Koch's comments that "if you could spin it as a Democratic failure, or link it to failures of the Obama administration, it might advantage Trump." That’s just &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924648/donald-trump-terrorism-speech"&gt;what Trump is trying to do&lt;/a&gt;, painting President Obama’s failure to condemn &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/11/16/9745334/obama-radical-islam-isis"&gt;"radical Islam"&lt;/a&gt; as emblematic of a deeper refusal to be "tough" enough to protect Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="JHdIQA"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p dir="ltr" lang="en"&gt;What has happened in Orlando is just the beginning. Our leadership is weak and ineffective. I called it and asked for the ban. Must be tough&lt;/p&gt;
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/742096033207844864"&gt;June 12, 2016&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script charset="utf-8" src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p id="1SXzDa"&gt;Again, no one can say for sure how the politics of the Orlando attack, or any possible future attack, will play out. Perhaps the simplistic solution of an immigration crackdown that Trump is peddling &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924648/donald-trump-terrorism-speech"&gt;will in fact prove popular&lt;/a&gt;. Or perhaps the public will be repelled by Trump's &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11919998/trump-orlando-muslim-obama-conspiracy"&gt;conspiratorial rumblings&lt;/a&gt; that Obama might be sympathetic to the terrorists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Qwftyb"&gt;Still, the underlying research here suggests it certainly could have the &lt;em&gt;potential&lt;/em&gt; to be a perilous moment for the Clinton campaign — if Trump’s own shortcomings don't hold him back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The political science that predicted Trump's rise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="The political science that predicted Trump's rise | 8184" data-volume-uuid="0c353db39" data-volume-id="8184" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" id="volume-placement-1330" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11380320/donald-trump-terrorism-election-political-science"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11380320/donald-trump-terrorism-election-political-science</id>
    <author>
      <name>Andrew Prokop</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T10:30:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T10:30:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch: Samantha’s Bee’s blistering, angry response to the Orlando shooting</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/IrUjkDSPmt47ZT_7-JNQPzHe6gI=/166x0:1275x739/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850635/Screen_20Shot_202016-06-14_20at_2012.18.24_20AM.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;"Love does not win until we start loving each other enough to fix our fucking problems."&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s understandable if you don’t know quite how to feel about &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911962/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-orlando-updates-news"&gt;the latest&lt;/a&gt; mass shooting in America, a deeply horrifying event during which a man killed almost 50 people at an Orlando gay club during&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911960/orlando-shooting-lgbt-pride/in/11676003" target="_blank"&gt;pride weekend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6ZVGB8"&gt;But when Samantha Bee had to film a new episode of her show &lt;em&gt;Full Frontal &lt;/em&gt;less than 48 hours afterward, the emotion she chose to express was anger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dgm01k"&gt;The late-night host stood on her stage in exhausted fury. "Hey, is it okay if instead of making jokes, I just &lt;em&gt;scream&lt;/em&gt; for seven minutes?" she asked the audience, before delivering a blistering monologue on gun laws, complacency, and the inexcusable &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11923290/orlando-shooting-gun-violence-us"&gt;new normal&lt;/a&gt; of mass shootings in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="opRSet"&gt;While most late-night hosts tend to stick with somber respect when addressing something horrific, Bee stayed true to the &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/3/8/11176780/full-frontal-samantha-bee-late-night-host"&gt;tone she’s set throughout&lt;/a&gt; the first season of &lt;em&gt;Full Frontal&lt;/em&gt; by unleashing without restraint:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="1IpS2t"&gt;After a massacre, the standard operating procedure is that you stand on stage and deliver some well-meaning words about how we will get through this together, how love conquers hate. And that is great! That is beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qFaR6K"&gt;But you know what? &lt;em&gt;Fuck it.&lt;/em&gt; I am too angry for that. Love does not win until we start loving each other enough to fix our fucking problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="2el44O"&gt;From there, Bee was off, though she focused less on potential reasons for this particular tragedy (and how it targeted patrons of an LGBTQ club), and more on just &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/a/mass-shootings-sandy-hook"&gt;how many&lt;/a&gt; mass shootings continue to occur in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="b7JkTt"&gt;Even by Bee’s own reliably furious standards, the segment is scorching — and she's the only late-night host who would have done something like this with quite so much unabashed rage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7RmiC4"&gt;She pointed out just how easy it was for the Orlando shooter to buy an assault rifle despite a documented history of abuse and questions about his possible ties to terrorism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="nfRwb7"&gt;She called out Florida Gov. Rick Scott for shrugging at gun control and Florida Sen. Marco Rubio for saying that the shooting "could have happened anywhere in the world" and that "unfortunately, today was Orlando's turn," displaying obvious disgust. ("Mass shootings are so normalized now that we’re taking &lt;em&gt;turns?&lt;/em&gt;")&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="B8NZj8"&gt;She questioned the usefulness of offering &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2015/12/3/9842458/gun-violence-thoughts-prayers/in/11676003"&gt;"thoughts and prayers"&lt;/a&gt; without accompanying action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SAENtX"&gt;But she was perhaps most effective when she preemptively addressed the criticism she might receive in response. "‘Sam Bee wants to take your guns away,’" Bee faux-whined, before turning serious. "&lt;em&gt;Yes.&lt;/em&gt; The ones that mow down a room full of people in seconds? Yes, I &lt;em&gt;do &lt;/em&gt;want to take those guns away."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The Orlando mass shooting is a reminder of why Pride is so important&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class="volume-video" id="volume-placement-3222" data-volume-placement="article" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-id="8945" data-volume-uuid="e076eb9f6" data-analytics-label="The Orlando mass shooting and history of Pride | 8945" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-viewport="video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11930030/samantha-bee-orlando-shooting"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11930030/samantha-bee-orlando-shooting</id>
    <author>
      <name>Caroline Framke</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T10:29:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T10:29:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>Donald Trump’s idea of what “American” means is itself un-American</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/y9pvn-ZcrZQoVftNtGcNVWs-LkM=/0x19:3516x2363/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49845299/GettyImages-499670390.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;From his Muslim ban to his attacks on the “Mexican” judge, Trump assumes you can’t be loyal to America and to your immigrant heritage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="3426AU"&gt;Donald Trump believes the best way to prevent the mass shooting in Orlando is to go back in time and block shooter Omar Mateen’s parents from coming to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="db32fg"&gt;"The bottom line," Trump said in a &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11925122/trump-orlando-foreign-policy-transcript"&gt;major speech&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, "is that the only reason the killer was in America in the first place was because we allowed his family to come here."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lB5Mk8"&gt;This was all, Trump continued, that could have been expected — once Muslim immigrants are admitted into the US, their descendants will inevitably become terrorists. Under President Hillary Clinton, he said, "you'd be admitting hundreds of thousands of refugees from the Middle East with no system to vet them, or to prevent the radicalization of their children."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="V78G6x"&gt;"Or their children’s children," he added, in an apparent ad lib.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rZIsYU"&gt;Trump has called repeatedly to ban Muslim immigration to the United States. As his policy speech Monday in response to the Orlando shooting made clear, he sees the ban as his cardinal foreign policy proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="S88ok1"&gt;But he’s not being honest about it. Donald Trump has shown, time and time again, that he doesn’t believe the descendants of immigrants — whether they come from the Muslim world or from Mexico — are necessarily Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="iS8ou4"&gt;At best, he needs them to prove their loyalty. At worst, he sees non-European immigrant heritage and Americanness as a zero-sum identity game — someone with the former can never truly claim the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tzMXps"&gt;For more than 200 years, "American" has been about something more than blood and surname. By accusing second-generation Americans of being un-American, Donald Trump, the son of an immigrant mother, is engaging in a little second-generation un-Americanness himself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="TtOK8T"&gt;Trump consistently treats some Americans as not fully American&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Ied904"&gt;An instructive counterpoint: Here is &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/10/2/9441957/trump-gun-control"&gt;what Donald Trump said&lt;/a&gt; during an interview about a mass shooting at Umpqua Community College in October, conducted by Christopher Harper-Mercer, a US citizen whose parents &lt;em&gt;weren’t&lt;/em&gt; immigrants (emphasis added):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are going to slip through the cracks [...] oftentimes this happens and the neighborhood’s just, you know, we sort of saw that about him, it really looked like he could be a problem but it’s often &lt;strong&gt;hard to put someone in an institution for the rest of their lives based on the fact that he looks like he could be a problem.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="A3Uf46"&gt;The contrast couldn’t be clearer. Some people get the benefit of the doubt: The suspicions of their neighbors aren't enough to punish them for something they haven’t yet done (and may never do). Other people don’t. The fact of their heritage not only puts them under suspicion of radicalization but makes them such a threat to the American homeland that it's worth banning their parents from the US just to prevent them from being born here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QGymk0"&gt;The difference between the two groups isn't whether they’re American. Both Omar Mateen and Christopher Harper-Mercer were American in the eyes of the law. But in the eyes of Donald Trump — who said Monday that he wanted to be the president of "all Americans," even as he harped on the dangers of second-generation Americans — Mateen simply doesn’t count as American because of who his parents were.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9B9418"&gt;"He was born an Afghan of Afghan parents who immigrated to the United States," Trump said during his Monday speech (in another apparent ad lib).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dAo5sK"&gt;We’ve seen this distinction before. Gonzalo Curiel is a federal judge. Before being appointed to the federal bench, he was a distinguished prosecutor. Curiel is a second-generation American. He was born in Indiana; his parents were born in Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="GpEymR"&gt;Shortly before the Orlando attack, &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/31/11818964/trump-judge-university-mexican"&gt;Donald Trump spent &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/31/11818964/trump-judge-university-mexican"&gt;more than &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/31/11818964/trump-judge-university-mexican"&gt;a week saying that Curiel couldn't be objective toward Trump&lt;/a&gt; in a class-action suit because Trump wanted to build a wall with Mexico — implying, in a &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/7/11878468/trump-racist-curiel-apology"&gt;not-even-veiled way, that Curiel would put Mexico's interests in front of America’s&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="G4X3eG"&gt;Trump and his supporters pointed to Curiel’s membership in a Latino lawyers association, calling it a "radical" Latino organization. So Curiel, too, in his way, was accused of being a member of the radicalized second generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dRR0II"&gt;Literally all of American history has been about immigrants becoming American&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="h3KA3u"&gt;The equality of all citizens is the cornerstone of American law. It is certainly the cornerstone of American immigration policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6pzyQp"&gt;Not all people in the US have the same rights. Legal immigrants, even permanent residents, don’t have the full rights of citizens — they can be deported for committing a crime (and &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/4/28/11515132/iirira-clinton-immigration"&gt;thousands of them are&lt;/a&gt;). Once an immigrant is naturalized as a US citizen, that stops. Citizens who commit crimes are punished by the US legal system; they're not sent out of the country — no matter where they’re from.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="CzCHV3"&gt;Any child born on US soil to parents living in the US is a citizen upon birth. (Even the Republicans who have floated restrictions on birthright citizenship haven’t gone so far as to withhold birthright citizenship &lt;em&gt;to the children of US citizens&lt;/em&gt;, even if the parents weren’t born here.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="A9BYsd"&gt;This is fundamental to how Americans understand their country. Most Americans (certainly most white Americans) believe in the idea of their country as a "nation of immigrants": the place where generations of people came from other countries to build a better life for themselves and their families, where the heritages of the "old country" were quietly subsumed by a broader American identity. America is where you go to become an American; if you want to become an American, the doors are (in theory) open to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ooqrdv"&gt;Because the debate over immigration to the US (prior to the presidential candidacy of Donald Trump) focused on unauthorized immigrants, it's often been characterized as a debate over the "rule of law." (As a matter of fact, one of the most common lines heard among opponents of legalizing unauthorized immigrants is, "My ancestors came here the right way" — an acknowledgment that someone can become American from immigrant stock.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NQcjYm"&gt;Trump &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/7/29/9060427/nativism-research-immigration-trump"&gt;has blown the cover off that&lt;/a&gt;, by impugning the Americanness of legal immigrants and American citizens just as much as he’s attacked unauthorized ones. He's shown that many Americans are anxious, more than anything, about the threat immigrants pose to their values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HFchjy"&gt;These Americans suspect there are some cultures that cannot simply be subsumed into American culture — that are completely inimical to Americanness. Immigrants from these cultures can't be expected (or shouldn't be trusted) to choose American values over the values of their home countries. If allowed to take root in American communities, they will simply promote pockets of separatism — cultural &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/3/24/11298634/ted-cruz-muslim-islamophobia"&gt;"no-go zones."&lt;/a&gt; And if their home countries come into conflict with America, they — and their children, and their children’s children — will choose heritage over patriotism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ERDW9R"&gt;The &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/1/12/7474897/immigration-america-maps#list-item-30"&gt;fear of a fifth column&lt;/a&gt; is nothing new, either: For as long as Americans have held up the ideal of the integrated or assimilated immigrant, they’ve been afraid that some immigrants are simply occupying America without joining it. These fears gave us &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/1/12/7474897/immigration-america-maps#list-item-27"&gt;anti-Catholic discrimination&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/1/12/7474897/immigration-america-maps#list-item-28"&gt;riots&lt;/a&gt; in the 19th century. In the early 20th century, it gave us surveillance of German-American communities — and forced &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/1/12/7474897/immigration-america-maps#list-item-31"&gt;120,000 Japanese&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/1/12/7474897/immigration-america-maps#list-item-31"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/1/12/7474897/immigration-america-maps#list-item-31"&gt;Americans&lt;/a&gt;, many of them US citizens, into concentration camps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="OrPvNd"&gt;Radicalization is a problem. Isolation helps feed it.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="Gqu19C"&gt;Second-generation radicalization of Muslim immigrants is a problem, both in the US and in many European countries. A federal court in Minneapolis is currently hearing the case of three Somali-American teenagers accused of having become radicalized by ISIS. Many other young men (some of whom immigrated at a young age themselves, others of whom are second-generation Americans) have been brought up on similar charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Omoopb"&gt;The question of how to prevent second-generation Americans (or Belgians, or Brits) from becoming radicalized is a tough one. It’s something that many people — specifically, Muslim community leaders — in both the US and Europe are working on. There aren’t good answers yet. Nor are there easy answers for how people become radicalized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="00QsZo"&gt;The evidence is suggestive, however, that one of the factors that makes young people most vulnerable to recruitment by radicals is &lt;a href="https://www.start.umd.edu/sites/default/files/files/publications/Weine_BuildingResiliencetoViolentExtremism_SomaliAmericans.pdf"&gt;social isolation. &lt;/a&gt;In particular, when young people feel disconnected from both the culture of their heritage &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the culture of their countries, they are more likely to find a home in a radical ideology instead. One &lt;a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/263602847_Determinants_of_Radicalization_of_Islamic_Youth_in_the_Netherlands_Personal_Uncertainty_Perceived_Injustice_and_Perceived_Group_Threat"&gt;2013 study of Dutch Muslims&lt;/a&gt; found that "a feeling of being disconnected from society" was an "important determinant of a radical belief system."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PAE7V4"&gt;It’s nowhere near as simple as "if Americans don’t embrace second-generation immigrants, they’ll get radicalized." These are just factors in a larger matrix. But discriminating against second-generation young people on the basis of their heritage is certainly &lt;a href="https://behavioralpolicy.org/wp-content/uploads/2016/1-2/BSP_vol1no2_Lyons.pdf"&gt;correlated with social isolation&lt;/a&gt; and radicalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Tykewr"&gt;More broadly, when second-generation young people feel that their identity is a zero-sum game — that the heritage of their parents is in conflict with the heritage of the country in which they live — they’re more likely to turn to radicalism to resolve the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="akQMCa"&gt;A &lt;a href="http://www.scilogs.com/next_regeneration/dual-identity-and-radicalism-among-immigrants/"&gt;2013 study &lt;/a&gt;of Turkish (Muslim) and Russian immigrants in Germany found that the more religious the immigrants were (or, in the case of Russian immigrants, the more attuned to ethnic identity), the &lt;em&gt;less &lt;/em&gt;likely they were to be sympathetic to radical action. But when immigrants felt they would have to give up their Turkish or Russian identities in order to become German, they were more likely to nurture radical sympathies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nk6IvO"&gt;Identity doesn’t &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to be a zero-sum game. Just look at Judge Curiel — who’s spent the bulk of his career working for the American government while remaining active in a group that celebrates his Latino heritage. Most studies of immigrant integration suggest that the most successful children of immigrants are those who manage to retain connections to both the heritage of their parents and the culture of the country in which they live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="6OK0AC"&gt;But to Donald Trump (and many of his supporters), Curiel’s "pride" in his Mexican heritage was a threat of greater loyalty. The only way an immigrant — or the child of an immigrant, etc. — can prove she is truly American is to reject the identity of her ancestry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VfcTZI"&gt;Short of that, second-generation Americans are all equally deserving of scrutiny — they’re all, to some extent, impostor Americans, whose enemy loyalties will eventually come to the fore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="OS2Rx1"&gt;When you regard Gonzalo Curiel and Omar Mateen with exactly the same degree of suspicion, you give second-generation immigrants very few reasons to aspire to be Gonzalo Curiel. You give second-generation immigrants just one more reason to suspect that maybe the Omar Mateens of the world have it right after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9HEceS"&gt;It’s a pinched, insecure, petty way of looking at America. It’s what you might get if you looked at America and saw only a reflection of Donald J. Trump.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11920520/donald-trump-immigrants-muslim"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11920520/donald-trump-immigrants-muslim</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dara Lind</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T10:10:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T10:10:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>My 6-year-old daughter died at Sandy Hook. You never move on.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/UkfxDXv4t-qy88wWeZCVSB3Bm8I=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850557/GettyImages-159497005.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="CMf62H"&gt;"Are you okay? "Where are you?" "I'm praying for you!" "I love you!" My phone was buzzing like crazy on Sunday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aiYAJT"&gt;I didn't understand why at first. I no longer have a personal Facebook, and the TV wasn't on. I went on Twitter and saw:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know" target="_blank"&gt;a shooting in Orlando&lt;/a&gt;. I watched the numbers rise in real time. First some dead, then multiple, then 20, now 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Ym49Sm"&gt;My reaction was visceral. I know the horror of waiting to hear — that was me, four years ago, when a shooter attacked my 6-year-old daughter’s elementary school in&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://abcnews.go.com/topics/news/newtown-connecticut-school-shooting.htm" target="_blank"&gt;Newtown, Connecticut&lt;/a&gt;. A helicopter flew overhead. It made everything too real. Too familiar. I panicked. I called my friend. I cried. Fifty people. I was reliving being one of the family members in wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="xDtD9d"&gt;My friend told me the details. An attack against people who are gay. A specific group.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/6/17/8802547/mass-shooting-emmanuel-charleston-sc" target="_blank"&gt;Just like last year&lt;/a&gt; around this time. The 17th of June. A black church. My head was spinning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="RT51P6"&gt;I was tired. I was scared. I wanted to curl up in a fetal position on the sofa and watch &lt;i&gt;Harry Potter&lt;/i&gt; movies with my son. I thought: &lt;em&gt;Perhaps I will build a bulletproof barrier around my house and just order groceries from Peapod all summer. Or for the rest of our lives.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="wkXSDi"&gt;How do I tell my son that 49 people all died the way his sister did? And in one of our favorite places: Orlando, Florida?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="JAVjFl"&gt;I am waiting for the church to be as outraged about gun violence as much as we seem to be about&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/5/11592908/transgender-bathroom-laws-rights" target="_blank"&gt;who pees where&lt;/a&gt; in a Target bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="p5TWVG"&gt;"I am sorry that our tragedy here in Sandy Hook wasn't enough to save your loved ones"&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="O44T4g"&gt;Here is my message to those families in Florida:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ztjT81"&gt;I am sorry. I am so, so sorry. I am sorry that our tragedy here in Sandy Hook wasn't enough to save your loved ones. I tried, and I won't stop trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5WI0fw"&gt;Don't you dare even listen to even one person who may insinuate that somehow this is your loved one’s fault because they were gay or any other reason. Nor is it God's wrath. They did that to us in Sandy Hook, too. And it broke my heart. You will receive love from a million places. Embrace it. Take good care of yourself. This will be a forever journey.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yLUmFX"&gt;Some ugly will come your way too. When you speak up about gun violence in America, you get death threats. You get made fun of. You get people telling you your child's death isn't even real. You have to close down your personal Facebook account because you get tired of harassing messages. You block enough people on Twitter to fill a football stadium. You have to hire security at fundraising events because you don't know who will show up. Delete. Ignore. Let it go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="19fJ3v"&gt;Your loss on Sunday will bring out the worst &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; the best in all of us. May we commit to being our best selves in honor of what you now bear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="t9j0az"&gt;I am going to continue to fight to spread the message that love wins. In honor of your loved ones. Because hate, ugliness, evil, and prejudice cannot silence love, courage, good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="z63CZE"&gt;I will commit to learning about each and every one of your loved ones. And we will commit as a family to learning about their lives and the legacies you build in their memory.  My son will learn about your loved ones. And we will not forget. We will say their names out loud. We will remember your children. As you remembered and learned about ours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="IXbhfq"&gt;I am so sorry. Because you shouldn't have to be doing this. You should be planning summer outings to the beach and barbecues and birthdays and graduations. And I know it will never be the same. You never move on. You do move forward. One weighted leg after the other. One heavy heartbeat after the next. You move forward for your surviving children and those who depend on you. And you are never the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="VgH1Fb"&gt;"You are either a part of the problem or a part of the solution"&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="X0F5EQ"&gt;Here is my message to friends who want to help:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="oQsuBa"&gt;Please wait to donate until you know for sure that your hard-earned dollars will be received by victims and not by individuals, groups, and organizations designed to benefit from tragedies. Millions were poured into Sandy Hook.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.courant.com/news/connecticut/hc-sandy-hook-shooting-two-years-later-20141214-story.html"&gt;Very little reached the families directly&lt;/a&gt;. And victims of gun violence will have a lifetime of need. Before you give, ask where your dollars will go. Specify that you want it to go to victims’ families.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XfqsCI"&gt;Aside from money, you are either a part of the problem or a part of the solution. Victims cannot bear the burden of this alone. Please help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="FpiRdV"&gt;Bring up gun violence in your house of worship or community group. Join &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/MomsDemandAction/"&gt;Moms Demand Action for Gun Sense in America&lt;/a&gt; or any other group like it that speaks to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="lnnwDO"&gt;And if someone is hurting you or bullying you because you are gay, please visit &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/TheTrevorProject/"&gt;the Trevor Project&lt;/a&gt; or&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.itgetsbetter.org" target="_blank"&gt;It Gets Better&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tZUbH6"&gt;If you know someone who shows extreme hate of a group or individual, has access to weapons, and you feel there is inherent risk of harm, please call your local police immediately. Let's be more than bystanders. Let's save lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5SvmBq"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nelba Márquez-Greene started the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://anagraceproject.org/"&gt;Ana Grace Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt; to honor the memory of her daughter, Ana Grace Márquez-Greene, who died in the 2012 Sandy Hook shooting.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931484/orlando-shooting-sandy-hook"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931484/orlando-shooting-sandy-hook</id>
    <author>
      <name>Nelba Márquez-Greene</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T10:07:00-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T10:07:00-04:00</updated>
    <title>This graphic shows why it is so impossible to get gun reform through Congress</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5mf_ky39mt3osqGCkqeauY-YRQg=/114x0:1059x630/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850707/congress-fb-share.0.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="mj61BU"&gt;The mass shooting in &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know/in/11676003"&gt;Orlando, Florida&lt;/a&gt;, was the deadliest mass shooting in modern American history. But the chances that Congress will pass meaningful gun control reform as a result are highly unlikely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="c34vi2"&gt;The Senate is highly polarized around gun policy: The National Rifle Association gives 56 senators an A grade — and 36 senators an F. That leaves 11 senators somewhere in between, with scores ranging anywhere from a B+ to a D-.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="0OmOMp"&gt;This makes it really tough to see any proposed gun control reform legislation moving through the Senate. A simple majority for a bill to pass requires only 51 votes, and, as we can see in the chart above, there are already 56 senators that are unlikely to vote for comprehensive gun control reform. And this, of course, is assuming that the proposed legislation makes it past the House in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8wKs2D"&gt;I wasn't able to access the NRA’s report card ratings for House members, as the NRA does not make its rankings publicly available (even to a member of the media who requested the information repeatedly). The only way to gain access to the NRA’s ratings is to become a paying member, so I relied heavily on 2012 work by the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/the-fix/wp/2012/12/17/where-the-senate-stands-on-guns-in-one-chart/"&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; and press releases from the NRA to fill in the gaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="scf1Ic"&gt;But if you look at the New York Times’s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2012/12/19/us/politics/nra.html"&gt;analysis of the 113th Congress in 2012&lt;/a&gt;, you’ll note the divide between pro-gun lawmakers and anti-gun lawmakers is similarly divided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="bK3wqc"&gt;Of the 435 members of the House, the Times reported that 242 legislators received a score of A- or higher and 146 received a score of a D or F. Only 47 had a score in the middle or no score reported at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="qUtRbW"&gt;It’s not just Congress. Public opinion on gun control doesn’t shift after a mass shooting either.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="oo7yOK"&gt;In 2012, the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.people-press.org/2012/07/30/views-on-gun-laws-unchanged-after-aurora-shooting/"&gt;Pew Research Center&lt;/a&gt; found that public support for gun control doesn't appear to be impacted by high-profile shooting incidents like what happened in Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XGKkcI"&gt;Polling people immediately after the mass shooting at a movie theater in Aurora, Colorado, in July 2012, that killed 12 and injured 70 others, Pew found no significant change in public opinion on the issue of gun control and gun rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p id="q9w5NJ"&gt;In fact, &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/12/4/9845146/mass-shootings-gun-control"&gt;growing evidence&lt;/a&gt; suggests that immediately following a mass shooting is not the time to discuss increased gun control measures, period. There’s &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/12/7/9859802/democrats-gun-control"&gt;little compromise&lt;/a&gt;, and opposing political parties often stick to their lines of rhetoric — Republicans call for "thoughts and prayers" while Democrats call for gun control. But it does invite the question: If not now, when will we address the issue of gun violence as a nation?&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11922064/gun-control-impossible-congress-graphic"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11922064/gun-control-impossible-congress-graphic</id>
    <author>
      <name>Sarah Frostenson</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T10:00:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T10:00:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>This comprehensive Targaryen family tree explains Game of Thrones' most complicated dynasty</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/pqszhsOm7YfNnX8PDh-vRKh20MY=/0x266:1280x1119/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49846141/dareon_ii_family_by_poly_m-d95v94z.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="lEIWpR"&gt;Maryon B. is a 27-year-old French freelance artist and video game developer currently living in Helsinki. She’s also a die-hard &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; fan, which might explain why she’s illustrated the entire lineage of House Targaryen (home of one Daenerys, Mother of Dragons) from George R.R. Martin’s &lt;em&gt;A Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/em&gt; series of novels — even though, as she says in her description of the project on&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/art/House-Targaryen-complete-Family-Tree-614284707" target="_blank"&gt;DeviantArt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, "I DON'T EVEN LIKE HOUSE TARGARYEN WHY DID I DO THIS[?]"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XWjwpa"&gt;"I actually started the Tree out of spite because all their descriptions (and fan representations) make them look the same — beautiful, silver-haired and purple eyes," she told Vox via email, "and it frustrated me to see them as elf-clones."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MFFMtH"&gt;The result is a&lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/art/House-Targaryen-complete-Family-Tree-614284707"&gt; gorgeous take&lt;/a&gt; on the complicated, once-mighty dynasty of the Targaryens. As &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; fans have heard time and again, this powerful family unified the Seven Kingdoms and ruled over the fictional land of Westeros until Robert Baratheon overthrew the "Mad King," Aerys II, better known as Daenerys’s deceased father.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0EaM7m"&gt;But if you think that portion of the Targaryens’ legacy is confusing, consider that the full family tree contains more than 100 characters and spans 16 generations of entirely fictional history (click &lt;a href="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6642301/house_targaryen_complete_family_tree_by_poly_m-da5q943.jpg"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the full-size version):&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/-ruwPamb2YxpJcQ2PnLWxGPyWPY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6642301/house_targaryen_complete_family_tree_by_poly_m-da5q943.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a look at only one character from this broad tapestry: the second Rhaenys Targaryen. Known in the annals of Westeros history as the "queen who never was," Rhaenys was a dragon rider whose claim to the throne was passed over in favor of her brother. She married Corlys Velaryon and died fighting a battle on dragonback at the age of 52:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/auUK-y5b0XdP_4mY3ZP1041389I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6642241/Screen%20Shot%202016-06-13%20at%203.24.39%20PM.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/art/The-Queen-Who-Never-Was-589377884"&gt;poly-m&lt;/a&gt; (deviantART)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Rhaenys Targaryen.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="Fq6yPi"&gt;Rhaenys’s great-grandmother was Alyssa Velaryon, who joined the Targaryen dynasty by marrying Aenys I, a politically wily man who took the throne amid great upheaval. They had six children before Aenys was killed and Alyssa taken hostage by her husband’s half-brother Maegor. (And from there, things get &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; complicated.)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/fMK_fd7nZ_krvTBbLw-HZO4-2Qw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6642311/aenys_i_family_by_poly_m-d9sge5k.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/art/Aenys-I-Family-591989672"&gt;poly-m&lt;/a&gt; (deviantART)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Aenys I’s lineage.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="eEQPA4"&gt;Further down the family tree, there’s House Blackfyre, an illegitimate house sanctioned by the lust-ridden King Aegon Targaryen IV, who’s generally considered the worst king ever. His decision to legitimize all of the bastard children he fathered with his &lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/art/Royal-Mistresses-577926819"&gt;many mistresses&lt;/a&gt; — announced from his deathbed — prompted five generations of battles for the throne known as the Blackfyre Rebellions.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/gb80IQ2p9Stlt8sqFpK587jR_6M=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6642413/house_blackfyre_by_poly_m-d9wn3rv.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;&lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/art/House-Blackfyre-599021275"&gt;poly-m&lt;/a&gt; (deviantART)&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;House Blackfyre.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="YltU0Z"&gt;Maryon says she got into Martin's novels and related writing during the long hiatus between seasons two and three of &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/i&gt;. She started the Targaryen family tree project more or less on accident after drawing Baelor, Breakspear, and Maekar, three characters who figure prominently in &lt;i&gt;Tales of Dunk and Egg&lt;/i&gt;, Martin's collection of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tales_of_Dunk_and_Egg"&gt;related novellas&lt;/a&gt; set in the &lt;i&gt;Song of Ice and Fire&lt;/i&gt; universe. Naturally, the project spiraled:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[I]t got me interested in their ancestors, so I worked from there. At first I never thought I'd do the whole bunch, but it's when I realized that I was already halfway through just by making Maekar's descendants that I gave in: "While I'm at it, might as well do the rest…"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maryon says the project turned out to be "a very challenging artistic exercise, to keep on coming up with facial variety all while maintaining the same 'silver hair-purple eyes' features and some genetic similarities."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I had to find inspiration and study some real people's faces so I learned a lot since I started."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Above all, a look at the full family tree reveals how often and how strategically the Targaryens secured the future of their line by marrying into other powerful families like the Martells, the Baratheons, and the Velaryons, just as many figures in real-world history have done. And when Maryon was finished, she says she'd actually become fonder of the Targaryens than she was when she began:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"[I]n the end it made me appreciate House Targaryen much more since now I share a personal story with each and every one of them, and I would suggest anyone who likes &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/i&gt; to be curious about them because they have a lot of stories to tell."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see these and many more excerpts from the Targaryen family tree, as well as other &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; portraits, on &lt;a href="http://poly-m.deviantart.com/gallery/44214023/Game-of-Thrones"&gt;Maryon’s DeviantArt page&lt;/a&gt;. She’s &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ImaginaryWesteros/comments/4ncnf9/there_it_is_the_complete_targaryen_family_tree_by/d43ay59"&gt;stated&lt;/a&gt; she hopes to eventually produce a print version of the full family tree, but in the meantime she's also started another ambitious project for another complicated &lt;i&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/i&gt; clan: a family tree for &lt;a href="https://67.media.tumblr.com/68a50d32a8f991d661ad555330e58b26/tumblr_o8m9eqMG3g1rb7ph3o1_1280.jpg"&gt;the Freys&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Game of Thrones' time travel, explained&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="Game of Thrones' time travel, explained | 8572" data-volume-uuid="61b111db2" data-volume-id="8572" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" id="volume-placement-3362" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11924146/house-targaryen-fan-art"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11924146/house-targaryen-fan-art</id>
    <author>
      <name>Aja Romano</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T09:50:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T09:50:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Donald Trump revives his bogus claim that American Muslims "cheer" terrorism</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/f6S3r7FUrrPSUz7gED4ltIhQrdM=/0x74:2984x2063/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850573/GettyImages-539920710.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="H3xP6V"&gt;Donald Trump established his foreign policy platform on the inflammatory premise that Muslims &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/03/09/politics/donald-trump-islam-hates-us/index.html"&gt;"hate"&lt;/a&gt; the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="cWp0Fy"&gt;Early in his campaign, he repeated a long-debunked myth:&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;After the 9/11 attacks, Trump said, Muslims in New Jersey poured out onto the streets, celebrating the death of Americans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v8Av2J"&gt;"I watched in Jersey City, NJ, where thousands and thousands of people were cheering as that building was coming down," Trump said in November. "Thousands of people were cheering."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="9KLDU4"&gt;It’s a story that has been disproven time and time again. Now, in light of the &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know"&gt;mass shooting in Orlando&lt;/a&gt; by a gunman who reportedly pledged allegiance to ISIS, Trump revived the story to prove he was "right" about Muslims and 9/11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rhFGY6"&gt;Trump shared a story from &lt;a href="http://nypost.com/2016/06/13/orlando-killer-cheered-911-attacks-former-classmates-say/"&gt;the New York Post&lt;/a&gt; — citing reporting originally from the &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/post-nation/wp/2016/06/13/on-911-omar-mateens-classmates-mourned-some-say-he-celebrated/?utm_term=.592031eb37a7"&gt;Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; — recounting stories from former classmates of the gunman, Omar Mateen, who recalled him "saying some really rude stuff. Stuff like, 'That’s what America deserves.'"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id="zmPyGG"&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;I thought people weren’t celebrating? They were cheering all over, even this savage from Orlando. I was right. &lt;a href="https://t.co/DrVa65X9rI"&gt;https://t.co/DrVa65X9rI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
— Donald J. Trump (@realDonaldTrump) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/realDonaldTrump/status/742464647878561794"&gt;June 13, 2016&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id="JY9GwL"&gt;Trump has a fixation on being right, especially when it pushes his narrative&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="xlacH2"&gt;Trump has spread a vast number of &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/13/11924448/donald-trump-lies-speech"&gt;falsehoods&lt;/a&gt; throughout the campaign — especially when it comes to his immigration policy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dhUG07"&gt;In the case of Muslims allegedly cheering 9/11, several outlets proved Trump wrong almost immediately: &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fact-checker/wp/2015/11/22/donald-trumps-outrageous-claim-that-thousands-of-new-jersey-muslims-celebrated-the-911-attacks/"&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/a&gt; reported Trump was not in New Jersey on 9/11; the mayor of Jersey City and the police commissioner of Paterson, New Jersey, said there were no cheering throngs in their town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="W90nX3"&gt;But Trump, in Trump fashion, continues to repeat it, grabbing onto one instance of fabricated hatred to define a community and ultimately validate his past claims. This isn’t the first time Trump has touted how "right" he's been with the Orlando shooting, &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11912348/donald-trump-islam-comment-orlando-shooting"&gt;thanking his supporters&lt;/a&gt; for congratulating him on being "right on radical Islamic terrorism."&lt;/p&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931338/donald-trump-muslims-cheering-terrorism"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931338/donald-trump-muslims-cheering-terrorism</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tara Golshan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T09:35:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T09:35:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Watch: Anderson Cooper’s heartbreaking tribute to Orlando’s victims</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vgYG356oF2RBh9J-dX0rCpvHzgU=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850499/GettyImages-540059994.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;blockquote class="twitter-video" data-lang="en"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;"They are more than a list of names. They are people who loved and who were loved." - &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/andersoncooper"&gt;@andersoncooper&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/Orlando?src=hash"&gt;#Orlando&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="https://t.co/DkxxPC1XtW"&gt;https://t.co/DkxxPC1XtW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;— Anderson Cooper 360° (@AC360) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AC360/status/742509343078244352"&gt;June 14, 2016&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In the wake of the mass shooting at Orlando’s gay nightclub Pulse, there’s been an effort to piece together all the moving parts, to try to make sense of this senseless tragedy.&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know"&gt; We’re slowly &lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know"&gt;learning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911616/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-in-orlando-what-we-know"&gt; more about&lt;/a&gt; the shooter, the gun he used, Florida’s gun laws, and other nuggets of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="MKWjKq"&gt;What shouldn’t be forgotten through all of this, though, are the lives of the 49 people lost that day. And &lt;a href="http://www.cnn.com/2016/06/13/us/anderson-cooper-reads-orlando-shooting-victims-names/"&gt;CNN anchor Anderson Cooper&lt;/a&gt; reminded us of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1WiSih"&gt;In an emotional opening to his show, Cooper read off the names of all the victims murdered in the shooting and, in instances where pictures were available, the segment showed their faces. He also spoke about what these people meant to their loved ones, including brief anecdotes about each person — what they did for a living, how they helped their families, who they were dating, and where they worked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="edfgib"&gt;"They are more than a list of names," Cooper said. "They are people who loved and who were loved."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="3Je2Dz"&gt;You can hear the heartbreak in his voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ePxHUj"&gt;Cooper’s tribute really drives home the humanity of this story. These are men and women who had lives full of families, co-workers, friends, boyfriends, girlfriends, jobs, challenges, and triumphs —  all of that disappeared in an instant. Each person possessed potential for more moments with their families, more brightness in their work, more love with their partners. Now it’s all gone. As we move forward, we can’t forget these men and women, their lives, and all that was lost on Sunday.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931318/orlando-shooting-victims"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931318/orlando-shooting-victims</id>
    <author>
      <name>Alex Abad-Santos</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T09:30:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T09:30:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>The Orlando mass shooting is a reminder of why pride is so important</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/LGWVIko-Ym9YPm0sTzhbt4yQiJk=/0x0:2000x1333/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850459/GettyImages-539755812.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;June is Pride Month, a&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.gaypridecalendar.com/"&gt;worldwide&lt;/a&gt; commemoration of the pro-LGBTQ uprising that began at the Stonewall Inn in New York City. Like many gay and queer bars of the time, the Stonewall Inn was often raided by police. And anyone, especially people the police suspected were part of the LGBTQ community,&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;was arrested.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;The deadliest anti-LGBTQ violence in American history, until Sunday, happened &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.vox.com/2015/6/24/8840905/lgbt-stonewall-inn-upstairs-lounge-history"&gt;four years after Stonewall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, at the Upstairs Lounge in New Orleans, Louisiana. Between June 24, 1973, when that attack occurred, and the attack on the Orlando gay nightclub this past Sunday, the LGBTQ community has seen significant &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.vox.com/marriage-equality"&gt;civil rights progress&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;. However, t&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;he message this act of terror and hate sends is clear: There are still no truly safe spaces for LGBTQ people, and it will still be a long journey until we see a time when there are.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931430/orlando-shooting-pride-important"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931430/orlando-shooting-pride-important</id>
    <author>
      <name>Estelle Caswell</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T09:20:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T09:20:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Hollywood’s long history of turning good video games into bad movies, from Super Mario Bros. to Warcraft</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bIOGOmHrvifkUewgFdG4a4mzKhU=/0x0:1473x982/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49844679/warcraftorcs.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;Why is it so difficult to make a decent movie based on a video game? &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p id="1XcOlp"&gt;For more than 20 years, Hollywood has tried and failed to make a good movie based on a video game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="rjfVuT"&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0803096/"&gt;Warcraft&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the latest and perhaps the biggest effort to date, is yet another in a long line of failures. Director Duncan Jones — the filmmaker behind the small-scale sci-fi pleasures &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1182345/"&gt;Moon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;a href="http://m.washingtontimes.com/news/2011/mar/31/movie-review-source-code/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Source Code&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;— tries mightily to rise above the genre’s limitations, but in the end he delivers a lumbering, often bewildering film weighed down by two decades’ worth of video game lore and the expectations that lore has created. The result is simultaneously too devoted to its source material and too unwilling to seriously engage with it in a truly cinematic fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tocaq6"&gt;It’s a movie, in other words, that illustrates the challenges of adapting a popular video game to the big screen, and just how hard it is for Hollywood to get it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="2E14lp"&gt;Hollywood has a long history of making bad movies out of good video games&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="O8YTGJ"&gt;In many ways, of course, &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; represents a step up for video game movies: It boasts a promising director with a reputation for bringing strong characters and emotional textures to science fiction storytelling, an array of impressive &lt;a href="http://www.artofvfx.com/warcraft/"&gt;special effects&lt;/a&gt; (in particular its motion-capture orc characters), a budget reported at north of $150 million, and a prime summer release date. It’s a no-expense-spared tentpole epic aimed at true mass appeal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="chorus-snippet s-related" data-analytics-action="link:related" data-analytics-category="article"&gt;
&lt;span class="s-related__title"&gt;Related&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/10/11893004/warcraft-review-movie-orcs-humans"&gt;Review: &lt;i&gt;Warcraft&lt;/i&gt; is the critical bomb of the summer. I kinda liked it.&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous attempts at video game movies, in contrast, have typically been more modest.  The mid-1990s saw a handful of video game adaptations, including movies based on the popular fighting games &lt;em&gt;Street Fighter&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Mortal Kombat&lt;/em&gt;. Both were &lt;a href="http://www.boxofficemojo.com/movies/?id=mortalkombat.htm"&gt;reasonably&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.boxofficemojo.com/movies/?id=streetfighter.htm"&gt;successful&lt;/a&gt; at the box office after factoring in foreign returns, but they were modestly budgeted affairs designed to cater mostly to people who were already fans of the games by imagining the two properties as generic schlocky action flicks. They took fighting games and turned them into low-brainpower fighting movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UaP4Sq"&gt;The decision to target fans instead of the masses made sense, however, given what had happened with one of Hollywood’s earliest attempts at a video game adaption, the 1993 production of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0108255/"&gt;Super Mario Bros&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. That film boasted an expensive-for-its-time budget of almost $50 million, and a cast that included Bob Hoskins, John Leguizamo, and Dennis Hopper. Predicated on a truly bizarre decision to translate the &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PsC0zIhWNww"&gt;colorful, whimsical world&lt;/a&gt; of Shigeru Miyamoto’s incredibly popular and influential Mario games into &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wtMZKYnLg5c"&gt;a dark, weird, and uncharacteristically violent sci-fi dystopia&lt;/a&gt;, the movie was a critical failure and a box office bomb, bringing in just $20 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="dL2XY1"&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="k8NdCr"&gt;In the years since, Hollywood has continued to churn out video game–based movies. But from the forgettable (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0131646/"&gt;Wing Commander&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0317676/"&gt;House of the Dead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) to the truly awful (&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0383222/"&gt;BloodRayne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;) to the flat-out bizarre (&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TNrKqxZuMDo"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dead or Alive&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;), few have attempted much beyond low-level fan service. And the ones that have — &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0146316/"&gt;Lara Croft: Tomb Raider&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, the first couple of&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0120804/"&gt;Resident Evil&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; films — have been positioned largely as mundane genre films dressed up in video game garb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Gvg20y"&gt;For the most part, video game movies have been designed as quick cash-ins, intended to sell tickets primarily to people who bought the games — and almost no one else. Games were adapted because they were popular, not because they offered intriguing cinematic possibilities, which is how we ended up with low-grade movie versions of &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0419706/"&gt;Doom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0465494/"&gt;Hitman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0467197/"&gt;Max Payne&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="YOQ1Qi"&gt;Perhaps more than anything else, what connects all of these films is their dismal quality. Look at the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_films_based_on_video_games"&gt;Rotten Tomatoes scores&lt;/a&gt; for a bunch of video game movies and you won’t find a single one that breaks the 50 percent mark. By and large, they are all some combination of badly produced, badly designed, badly acted, badly written, and badly conceived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bigger-budget films tend to look slicker, yes — but with few exceptions, there’s little if any craftsmanship or imagination on display. At best, there’s a good-faith effort to competently dramatize some representative scenes from the source material; not one of these films has a memorable story. In fact, Angelina Jolie’s portrayal of Lara Croft may be the most notable thing to come out of any of these movies, mostly because it proved that she was a star, even in a movie that didn’t shine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0IIOVi"&gt;Essentially, Hollywood has spent 20-plus years making movies based on video games, and every single one of them is bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="aSLaJZ"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; is the latest example of how seemingly promising game material gets bungled on the way to the big screen&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="C2bq9A"&gt;Why is it so difficult to make a decent movie based on a video game? Why is it so hard to translate players and pixels to script and screen? After all, video games would seem to offer plenty of raw material for great — or at least enjoyably entertaining — movies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s games are driven by visual spectacle set against the backdrop of heavily developed fictional worlds. They feature high-velocity action set pieces and casts of easily recognizable, even iconic, characters. Lots of games now feature dramatic cut scenes — interstitial material that fleshes out the story in ways that are &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2015/11/3/9660602/halo-5-guardians-plot-story-review"&gt;inherently cinematic&lt;/a&gt;, at least on the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yiqXob"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; offers some insight into how such seemingly promising material can go so wildly wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7u9ive"&gt;The movie’s visuals, for example, are consistently stunning, with intricately detailed orcs that come across as eerily lifelike, despite being created via digital wizardry. Yes, they’re just pixels, but their bodies move with an organic logic, as if connected by the muscles and tendons you can see moving under their porous skin. But if the creatures look real, they also look, well, kind of silly, dressed in over-the-top bone armor and covered in goofy claw trinkets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The photorealism of the imagery only emphases the ridiculousness; it’s like watching a movie in which half the cast is made up of rejected members of &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RFBCpgEB8dc"&gt;joke metal band Gwar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside id="AiOSNi"&gt;&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;p id="92mUII"&gt;The armor and trinkets are there, of course, because such items are integral to the game. I’m far from a deep student of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; franchise — I prefer single-player role-playing games (RPGs) — but I know that like many RPGs, &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; is a game about collecting stuff for your character to wear and use: magic hats and glowing axes, armored boots and fantastical potions. Inside the game, all these accoutrements have a gameplay function, altering your character’s ability to attack, move, and defend. In many ways, the game is fundamentally about the quest to collect more and better stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="AMr6AS"&gt;In the movie, though, it’s just there because it exists in the game. Far too often, then, &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; plays like a catalog of shiny objects — shields and swords, gloves and cauldrons, staffs and gems, armories and map rooms. It’s the first movie I’ve ever seen that felt like it needed an inventory system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dAEpZo"&gt;Few of these items have any particular value to the story, and their various properties are barely explained. Late in the film, there’s a gag in which one of the characters turns an unsuspecting guard into a sheep. A sheep? What? Why a sheep? If you’re a &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; player, you know that it’s because the guard was hit with the &lt;a href="http://www.wowhead.com/spell=118/polymorph"&gt;polymorph spell&lt;/a&gt;, which renders enemies useless for a moment by transforming them into harmless farm animals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="pOyXVW"&gt;A beat like that could be an opportunity for a funny bit of story and character building, for explaining the sheep spell and its background and cultural context, or even just a running joke about the oddities of magic. Instead it’s just a random, confusing sight gag meant to please gamers at everyone else’s expense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ZMH91b"&gt;This sort of gamer fan service even affects the action scenes, several of which are staged in ways designed to lightly mimic the sort of complex combat strategies that teams of &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; players often use in the game, with mages standing behind energy shields&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;while they wait for spells to charge up to full power&lt;/span&gt; and sword slingers moving in close. But while those strategies work in the game world, they don’t make sense onscreen because they lack meaningful story context.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PnbFmZ"&gt;A movie version of &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; should have been an opportunity to flesh out the story and characters of the game world, to ground the game’s strategic systems and fragments of lore in recognizable emotion and motivation — the stuff that movies do well and video games generally don’t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But while you can occasionally see Jones, who co-wrote the screenplay with Charles Leavitt, attempting to accomplish as much in a handful of scenes that emphasize orc family life, those efforts are ultimately swamped by the dull demands of basic fan service. &lt;em&gt;Warcraft&lt;/em&gt; loves its game lore but can’t figure out how to share that love with anyone who doesn’t already feel it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="sRmfyG"&gt;There’s still a chance for someone to get the balance right&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="zxBwuH"&gt;Will Hollywood ever make a good movie based on a video game? The results so far aren’t promising, but I don’t think it’s impossible. Several unmade video game films suggest the genre’s promise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ewCjir"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pirates of the Caribbean&lt;/em&gt; director Gore Verbinski spent years developing a movie based on &lt;em&gt;BioShock&lt;/em&gt;. The game itself boasts one of the strongest narratives in modern video games, and Verbinski’s pitch — a &lt;a href="http://screenrant.com/bioshock-movie-budget-rob-101274/"&gt;dark, R-rated action-horror picture&lt;/a&gt; set in the game’s underwater city — was compelling, as was the &lt;a href="http://www.polygon.com/2014/12/31/7472827/bioshock-film-concept-art-farahani"&gt;concept art for the unproduced film&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5JVZIK"&gt;Similarly, a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6yp5jN6kRO0"&gt;short concept film&lt;/a&gt; for a movie based on Microsoft’s &lt;em&gt;Halo&lt;/em&gt; franchise, which &lt;a href="http://www.wired.com/2012/04/halo-movie-generation-xbox/"&gt;was to be produced&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;em&gt;Lord of the Rings&lt;/em&gt; director Peter Jackson and directed by &lt;em&gt;District 9&lt;/em&gt;’s Neill Blomkamp, suggests that the final product might have been something genuinely spectacular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="yGYLkf"&gt;I’m even tentatively hopeful about the forthcoming &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Xw-WXisyl3g"&gt;adaptation&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;em&gt;Assassin’s Creed&lt;/em&gt;, provided it can depart from the silly writing and repetitive storytelling of the game franchise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aFfuTy"&gt;In the meantime, video game concepts have already seeped into Hollywood’s DNA. With its quest-driven structure and its acrobatic shootouts, &lt;em&gt;The Matrix&lt;/em&gt; felt like the product of a sensibility shaped by video game tropes and attitudes. Jones’s previous film, &lt;em&gt;Source Code&lt;/em&gt;, worked more than a little like a game, with a protagonist who plays an eight-minute sequence, dies, then restarts from the same point over and over again while taking orders from a guide character.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="5keUtH"&gt;And, of course, there’s Doug Liman’s &lt;em&gt;Edge of Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;, a clever, surprisingly entertaining, and woefully underseen Tom Cruise sci-fi vehicle that is also structured almost exactly like a game, with a character who repeatedly dies and returns on the way to achieving a series of objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="dSIgTZ"&gt;So maybe the lesson is that Hollywood can produce good video game films — just so long as they’re not based on actual video games.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11908176/warcraft-bad-video-game-movies"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11908176/warcraft-bad-video-game-movies</id>
    <author>
      <name>Peter Suderman </name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T09:00:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T09:00:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>One of the best election models predicts a Trump victory. Its creator doesn't believe it.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/mF6XMsOZyWi8SpT7nK1Eml263So=/0x0:3000x2000/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49811497/538708212.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p&gt;One of the most respected and accurate forecasting models in political sciences says that Donald Trump will win the 2016 presidential election, and by a fairly comfortable margin at that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's just one problem: Its creator doesn't believe his own forecast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emory political scientist Alan Abramowitz's &lt;a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/ezra-klein/files/2012/08/abramowitz.pdf"&gt;"Time for Change"&lt;/a&gt; makes predictions by considering how the economy is doing (measured by the GDP growth rate the second quarter of the election year), how popular the incumbent is (measured by his Gallup approval rating at the end of June), and whether the incumbent is running for reelection. It has correctly predicted every presidential election since 1992.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the tepid &lt;a href="http://www.bea.gov/newsreleases/national/gdp/gdpnewsrelease.htm"&gt;first quarter GDP growth rate of 0.8 percent&lt;/a&gt; keeps up, as does &lt;a href="http://elections.huffingtonpost.com/pollster/obama-job-approval"&gt;Gallup's current +9 net approval rating&lt;/a&gt; for Obama, then the model suggests a Trump victory, 51.3 percent to Hillary Clinton's 48.7 percent. Even if GDP growth shot up dramatically to 3 percent, the model would still project a Trump win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alarmed? Well, Abramowitz isn't — in fact, he thinks Clinton will win easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;blockquote class="twitter-tweet"&gt;
&lt;p lang="en" dir="ltr"&gt;Trump's nomination means Hillary Clinton now almost certain to win in November and by a comfortable margin.&lt;/p&gt;
— Alan Abramowitz (@AlanIAbramowitz) &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/AlanIAbramowitz/status/727694951950114817"&gt;May 4, 2016&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abramowitz just thinks his model is wrong this year. "The model is based on the assumption that the parties are going to nominate mainstream candidates who will be able to unite the party, and that the outcome will be similar to a generic vote, a generic presidential vote for a generic Democrat versus a generic Republican," he told me. "That's usually a pretty reasonable assumption and produces pretty accurate predictions."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Usually a pretty reasonable assumption" doesn't mean it's always a reasonable assumption, though, and Abramowitz thinks this is a year when it clearly, obviously, isn't. Since Trump isn't a mainstream candidate, he breaks the models. "It would not shock me if he ends up losing," Abramowitz said, and "if Clinton wins the election by a very comfortable margin."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the consistent message I got from talking to experienced election forecasters. They each have their own models and believe in them under normal circumstances. The models that already have estimates — or that can be used for preliminary estimates, like Abramowitz's — are all over the place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="autotune" data-analytics-label="vox-political-science-forecasts-are-split-on-whether-clinton-or-trump-will-win:2677" id="vox-political-science-forecasts-are-split-on-whether-clinton-or-trump-will-win__graphic"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script type="text/javascript"&gt;&lt;!--
 (function() { var l = function() { new pym.Parent( 'vox-political-science-forecasts-are-split-on-whether-clinton-or-trump-will-win__graphic', 'https://apps.voxmedia.com/at/vox-political-science-forecasts-are-split-on-whether-clinton-or-trump-will-win/'); }; if(typeof(pym) === 'undefined') { var h = document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0], s = document.createElement('script'); s.type = 'text/javascript'; s.src = 'https://cdnjs.cloudflare.com/ajax/libs/pym/0.4.5/pym.js'; s.onload = l; h.appendChild(s); } else { l(); } })();
// --&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But as the election nears, forecasters are emphasizing that 2016 could be a year when their forecasts fare poorly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Election models are valuable so long as the election is broadly similar in terms of candidate quality, campaign tactics, and party coalitions to the elections that have happened before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is, election models are good at predicting elections that are like past elections. They are bad at predicting elections that are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; like past elections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here's the question: Is 2016 genuinely different from the elections that came before it? Or do the modelers just want to believe it is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What we talk about when we talk about election models&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By "model," I don't mean poll averaging and weighting of the kind that Nate Silver and FiveThirtyEight, or the team at the Upshot, do. I mean the kind of formal academic forecasting that political scientists and economists have been doing since around the late 1970s, which uses factors like economic variables, presidential approval ratings, and horse race polls to predict general elections months in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which factors, exactly, vary considerably. There are &lt;a href="http://www.douglas-hibbs.com/HibbsArticles/Hibbs-2012-Post-mortem.pdf"&gt;ones that almost exclusively rely&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="http://uwf.edu/media/university-of-west-florida/colleges/cas/departments/government/cdocs/I.A.29-Cuzan-2012-2012-Fiscal-Model-Failure-A-Measurement-Problem.-An-Assessment.pdf"&gt;economic data&lt;/a&gt;, which provide a tidy explanation for &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; particular candidates win but don't have a great predictive track record. More reliable are polls like Abramowitz's that use at least some polling — in Abramowitz's case, presidential approval ratings. Still more straightforward models, like the well-regarded one from&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://papers.ssrn.com/sol3/papers.cfm?abstract_id=2110791"&gt;Columbia's Robert Erikson and UT Austin's Christopher Wlezien&lt;/a&gt;, actually incorporate horse race polling, albeit well in advance of the general election.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2012, the journal &lt;em&gt;PS: Political Science &amp;amp; Politics &lt;/em&gt;organized a &lt;a href="http://journals.cambridge.org/action/displayIssue?jid=PSC&amp;amp;volumeId=45&amp;amp;seriesId=0&amp;amp;issueId=04"&gt;symposium&lt;/a&gt; of forecasts for the election. Each was attempting to guess what percentage of the two-party vote Obama would get; ultimately, he got 52 percent to Romney's 48.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The convener of the symposium, SUNY Buffalo professor and &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://press.princeton.edu/titles/10846.html"&gt;Polarized: Making Sense of a Divided America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; author James Campbell, shared this chart summarizing how close various models got last cycle. This isn't a perfect gauge of their accuracy; all models have error, and it's possible a model that's generally good flubbed it last time. But it's a decent way to get a shortlist of models to consider this time around:&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/H61vhVufarrJLrDkSfTc-3FYnhQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6602507/2012PresidentialElectionGreatBritain.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;James Campbell&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Why the models might not hold in 2016&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few of these forecasters have issued predictions for 2016 yet; most of them require more information than is presently available. And those that &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; come out, or that can be used for preliminary predictions, are all over the place. The&lt;span&gt;re's Abramowitz's model, predicting a Trump win. Wlezien and Erikson passed along an estimate to me, based on current horse race polling and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.conference-board.org/data/bci.cfm" style="font-size: 1.3em; line-height: 1.65; background-color: #ffffff;"&gt;leading economic indicators&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;, that Clinton would get 51.8 percent of the two-party vote, a nearly 4-point win over Trump.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"This is a black swan election," Erikson says. "The economy is middling, the president is around 50 percent approval, so that suggests a close race. But there is variance due to the candidates, and both Clinton and Trump can have big effects."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, these models are built for generic, typical candidates like John McCain or Mitt Romney, who are well within the Republican mainstream on immigration, not someone who thinks a &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/7/11878468/trump-racist-curiel-apology"&gt;guy with Mexican ancestry who was born in Indiana is unfit to judge him&lt;/a&gt; in federal court and who wants to ban all Muslims from entering the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More generally, some forecasters argue that open-seat races are harder to predict than incumbent reelection years. "Presidential approval, quite understandably, is a weaker predictor when the incumbent is not running," Campbell notes. &lt;a href="http://www.acsu.buffalo.edu/~jcampbel/documents/JOPConditionalRetro2010.pdf"&gt;Campbell's research with collaborators Bryan Dettrey and Hongxing Yin&lt;/a&gt; confirmed that both presidential approval ratings and economic factors are less influential in open-seat contests. "In open-seat contests," they write, "economic effects on the vote were consistently weaker and never achieved statistical significance."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This makes sense. Presidential approval ratings and the state of the economy seem, intuitively, relevant to whether voters will want to reelect an incumbent. They're not likely to reelect someone they disapprove of, whom they hold responsible for a poor economy, etc. But it's less clear that a president's popularity would rub off on another person his party nominated, or that that person would get credit for a good economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Since they basically ignore information about the candidates themselves, econometric models are based on the theory of retrospective voting (which assumes that elections are a referendum on the incumbent party’s past performance)," political scientist Andreas Graefe of &lt;a href="http://pollyvote.com/en/components/econometric-models/"&gt;PollyVote&lt;/a&gt; says. "This is a useful theory, but if may be less useful if the candidates and their campaigns 'break the rules,' as is the case in 2016."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Models are basically based on 17 elections. That makes predicting tough.&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/srjDX2gL6Aq6XKBnCGO5xEk3B_s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6326935/GettyImages-494167257.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;Herb Snitzer/Michael Ochs Archive/Getty Images&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Was Dukakis an unusually bad candidate? Maybe!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abramowitz says he's agnostic about whether forecasts perform worse in open-seat races; there are just too few data points. That's fair — the brute fact of the matter is that there have only been 17 presidential elections since World War II upon which political scientists can build predictive models. Even if you were to include &lt;em&gt;every&lt;/em&gt; presidential race (and you shouldn't, given how little the process that selected, say, John Adams, has in common with modern elections) that'd only be 57.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's a small sample size, which makes nailing down model specifications tricky. For example, the major factor in Abramowitz's model that gives Trump a strong edge is the advantage he gives to incumbent presidents (and implicit disadvantage he gives to open-seat contenders of the incumbent's party).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This variable is based on comparing 10 races (1948, 1956, 1964, 1972, 1980, 1984, 1992, 1996, 2004, 2008) with the other seven. But that's really not a lot to go on. If you were to read a medical study, say, where the control group had a sample size of 10 and the treatment group had only seven people, you'd be cautious in interpreting the findings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or consider what happened in 2012, when Abramowitz adjusted his model to attempt to account for the fact that general elections have been getting closer since 1980. He added a new variable that takes away some of the incumbency advantage and that hurts members of the outgoing incumbent's party in open races when the incumbent is popular (like, say, Hillary Clinton). But that new variable resulted in a worse prediction than his regular model made, so he's back to the original.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, this isn't a criticism of Abramowitz specifically, or indeed of any modeler. This stuff is &lt;em&gt;hard&lt;/em&gt;. And to his credit, Abramowitz acknowledges that, and tries to identify cases where inferring from limited past patterns can steer you wrong. Candidates have under and overperformed relative to what his model would expect before, he notes. He identifies three cases in particular: the underperformance of George McGovern in 1972, Michael Dukakis in 1988, and Al Gore in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He interprets the McGovern case as indicating the importance of party unity, and the Dukakis and Gore cases as indicating weak candidates and poorly conducted campaigns. "You can't really build these into the model, because they're pretty subjective," he notes. But just because something's not readily quantifiable doesn't mean it's unimportant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some quantifiable factors also give Abramowitz pause about the model. Past nominees have followed normal trends in the partisan preferences of different racial groups. But Donald Trump's vocal anti-immigration rhetoric has led to abnormally low levels of support from Latinos and &lt;a href="http://www.politico.com/story/2016/05/donald-trump-asian-american-223502"&gt;Asian Americans&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/20/opinion/stop-the-polling-insanity.html?_r=0"&gt;Abramowitz has argued&lt;/a&gt; that Trump's true level of support from Latinos is in the low 10s, if measured from high-quality surveys with Spanish-language options. That seems almost certainly like a consequence of Trump's specific rhetoric and reputation on racial issues, a candidate effect that normal political science forecasts couldn't capture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, all this doubt might be overblown. The entire 2016 primary cycle involved pundits and political scientists discounting what the numbers were telling us — Donald Trump was the most popular Republican candidate and set to win by a wide margin — on the basis that Trump was different, that his lead was less real than past candidates' leads because he's too extreme or inexperienced or alienated from the Republican Party. And yet at the end of the day, the simple interpretation was right: The poll lead wasn't a fad — it was a sign that Donald Trump was going to be nominated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, the best political science models, like Abramowitz's, have served us well in the past, providing fairly reliable predictions of the victor in November well ahead of time. It's tempting to look at Trump and say that this time is different. But maybe we're once again trying to explain away perfectly valid numbers. Maybe Abramowitz's model is just right, and Trump is set to surprise all of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;The political science that predicted Trump's rise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div data-analytics-viewport="video" data-analytics-action="volume:view:article:middle" data-analytics-label="The political science that predicted Trump's rise | 8184" data-volume-uuid="0c353db39" data-volume-id="8184" data-analytics-placement="article:middle" data-volume-placement="article" id="volume-placement-1935" class="volume-video"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11854512/trump-election-models-political-science"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11854512/trump-election-models-political-science</id>
    <author>
      <name>Dylan Matthews</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T08:50:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T08:50:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>Most Americans don't view Hillary Clinton's presidential nomination as "historic"</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/bNwlQZwbnBSPutDqcs9R93r6dlc=/0x0:1280x853/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850119/GettyImages-515773080.0_2.0.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="PKmDSo"&gt;Hillary Clinton will soon become the first female presidential nominee of a major party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xMZnAN"&gt;But only a little more than a third of Americans think her securing of the nomination marks a "historic" moment — and whether you agree depends a lot on what party you are in, according to a &lt;a href="https://morningconsult.com/2016/06/14/poll-less-half-voters-view-clintons-nomination-historic/"&gt;new poll&lt;/a&gt; released on Tuesday from Vox and the nonpartisan technology and media company&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://morningconsult.com/about" target="_blank"&gt;Morning Consult&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;It turns out that the majority of Americans disagree with the idea that Clinton’s nomination is "historic." Overall, only 38 percent of the country says it is.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9LYyji"&gt;Party determines whether you think of Clinton’s achievement as "historic"&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="kIRAGV"&gt;The poll found 52 percent of Democrats say Clinton's nomination is "historic," as do 40 percent of independents, while just 19 percent of Republicans would say the same. And though a majority of Democrats agree with this descriptor, it’s hardly an overwhelming one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="hGcEVK"&gt;It might be tempting to think that women are willing to cross party lines on this front, but the poll didn’t bear this out. Only a small portion of Republican women (also just 19 percent) think of Clinton’s nomination as historic, compared with just 20 percent of Republican men.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/aYoTva3tW1-yBr3gxuNQpPrxWcY=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/3964154/shutterstock_155865410_Hillary.0.jpg"&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="ED7s1n"&gt;Of course, "historic" is a pretty squishy term — there’s no immediately clear definition for what it means, and it’s subject to a range of interpretations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0TzSYb"&gt;But overall, far fewer people appear to think it’s a big deal that a woman was nominated for president than you might expect. After Clinton became the presumptive nominee last week, the &lt;a href="http://www.thenation.com/article/hillary-clinton-will-claim-a-historic-victory-tuesday-night-and-the-media-should-cover-it-that-way/"&gt;media&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.latimes.com/world/la-fg-world-clinton-20160608-snap-story.html"&gt;widely&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href="http://townhall.com/columnists/derekhunter/2016/06/12/hillary-clinton-is-historic-n2176903"&gt;referred&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href="http://www.pennlive.com/news/2016/06/hillary_clintons_historic_mome.html"&gt;her nomination&lt;/a&gt; as "historic." Even Clinton’s harshest critics in the press seemed to buy that shared premise. (A good example via Fox News: &lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/opinion/2016/06/13/hillarys-historic-nomination-isnt-victory-for-women-its-betrayal.html"&gt;"Hillary’s historic nomination isn’t a victory for women, it’s a betrayal."&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="SBbYzC"&gt;But for whatever reason — perhaps a long and drawn-out primary fight, hyperpolarization in American life, or general dislike of Hillary Clinton — Americans just aren’t feeling the historic nature of the #ImWithHer movement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="dDW5D6"&gt;Republican women won’t vote for Hillary Clinton because she’s a woman&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Donald Trump Hillary Clinton heads side by side" src="https://cdn3.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/Lp-KG00rS_MwrCeYtHSj9xSZNu8=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/5934811/1453822967352.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(Getty Images)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="uKgQ6a"&gt;Of course, it’s no surprise that Republican women don’t love Hillary Clinton. After all, more than 70 percent of them plan to vote for Trump in the general election, according to the &lt;a href="http://www.foxnews.com/politics/2016/06/09/fox-news-poll-trump-drops-now-trails-clinton.html?intcmp=hpbt1"&gt;latest Fox News poll&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="12Trem"&gt;But one could still have imagined that Clinton’s gender would help make her at least somewhat more appealing to women across the aisle, and that it might open the door for Clinton to try winning over a slice of female Republicans in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Nfislh"&gt;Indeed, that idea appears to be playing into the Clinton campaign’s electoral strategy. The prospect of the first woman president — coupled with Trump's track record of insulting women — has Clinton’s team&lt;a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/hillary-clinton-aims-for-gop-women-1462841586"&gt; laying the groundwork&lt;/a&gt; to win "moderate Republican women put off" by  Trump, according to the Wall Street Journal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ba4MZD"&gt;But the new poll suggests that the overriding law of American politics is still partisanship, not gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="UTb54v"&gt;Both Democratic men and women, for instance, are significantly more likely than Republicans of either gender to think of Clinton’s nomination as "historic." About 45 percent of Democratic men and 58 percent of Democratic women think so, according to the new poll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="v6C00M"&gt;Perhaps Democratic women will be slightly more energized about Clinton’s campaign than Democratic men. But by a pretty healthy margin, party allegiance is much more closely tied to views about the "historic" nature of Clinton’s nomination than gender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="GSOgtB"&gt;If Clinton wins, it won’t be because of her gender&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="ydIvcj"&gt;Now, it’s not just Republicans and Democrats whose views on Clinton herself may be influencing their responses on the significance of a female presidential nominee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7X00X7"&gt;Young people overwhelmingly backed Bernie Sanders during the primary, and are &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/4/25/11505126/poll-hillary-clinton-donald-trump"&gt;generally distrustful&lt;/a&gt; of Clinton herself. They’re also the least likely age group to find Clinton’s nomination "historic" — just 29 percent do so, compared with 52 percent for the oldest voters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U1080379498887UGC"&gt;Part of the age gap here could be explained by cultural changes. "We see it as inevitable that one day a women [sic] will occupy the one that is oval-shaped," &lt;a href="https://subscribe.washingtonpost.com/acquisition/?prompt=1&amp;amp;promo=digital03_paywall&amp;amp;oscode=RPWH&amp;amp;wpsrc=CM0000446&amp;amp;page=opinions:article%20-%20e9bc84a2c8e4%20-%2020160607%20-%20why-millennials-are-yawning-at-the-likely-first-female-major-party-nominee-for-president&amp;amp;section=wp%20-%20opinions&amp;amp;prev=&amp;amp;geo=&amp;amp;ctype=article&amp;amp;signedin=logged%20out&amp;amp;mcount=5&amp;amp;sub=0&amp;amp;ismetered=1&amp;amp;destination=https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/why-millennials-are-yawning-at-the-likely-first-female-major-party-nominee-for-president/2016/06/07/11de9428-2cee-11e6-b5db-e9bc84a2c8e4_story.html&amp;amp;action=3&amp;amp;sub=0&amp;amp;mtr=1&amp;amp;mtrct=5&amp;amp;mtfn=1&amp;amp;t=10002&amp;amp;st=200&amp;amp;loc=1&amp;amp;mvw=5&amp;amp;wa=3&amp;amp;fr=0&amp;amp;dt=0&amp;amp;mx=0&amp;amp;pwo=1&amp;amp;rwb=0&amp;amp;sgn=0&amp;amp;v=2.3&amp;amp;acq_test=1#/paywall/offers/promo/digital03_paywall/oscode/RPWH?wpsrc=CM0000446&amp;amp;page=opinions:article%20-%20e9bc84a2c8e4%20-%2020160607%20-%20why-millennials-are-yawning-at-the-likely-first-female-major-party-nominee-for-president&amp;amp;section=wp%20-%20opinions&amp;amp;prev=&amp;amp;geo=&amp;amp;ctype=article&amp;amp;signedin=logged%20out&amp;amp;mcount=5&amp;amp;sub=0&amp;amp;sub=0&amp;amp;ismetered=1&amp;amp;destination=https:%2F%2Fwww.washingtonpost.com%2Fopinions%2Fwhy-millennials-are-yawning-at-the-likely-first-female-major-party-nominee-for-president%2F2016%2F06%2F07%2F11de9428-2cee-11e6-b5db-e9bc84a2c8e4_story.html&amp;amp;action=3&amp;amp;mtr=1&amp;amp;mtrct=5&amp;amp;mtfn=1&amp;amp;t=10002&amp;amp;st=200&amp;amp;loc=1&amp;amp;mvw=5&amp;amp;wa=3&amp;amp;fr=0&amp;amp;dt=0&amp;amp;mx=0&amp;amp;pwo=1&amp;amp;rwb=0&amp;amp;sgn=0&amp;amp;v=2.3&amp;amp;acq_test=1"&gt;writes&lt;/a&gt; Molly Roberts at the Washington Post of Clinton securing the number of delegates necessary to get the nomination. "The notion of the first female major-party presidential nominee is greeted with a collective millennial yawn."&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="Clinton at a rally in New Hampshire on Monday. (Scott Eisen/Getty Images)" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/puF0w01UV86LGcPHbXvHfEen0J4=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6120373/496422048.0_2.0.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Clinton at a rally in New Hampshire. (Scott Eisen/Getty Images)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="nKwFSp"&gt;Still, as Roberts says, young people’s attitudes toward Clinton the individual are almost certainly a factor here, too. And, as with the Republican women, the polls suggest it’s highly unlikely Clinton will win over millennials on the basis of her "historic" candidacy alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="XgSDVX"&gt;All of this confirms what Vox’s Kay Steiger &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/5/5/11571446/hillary-clinton-donald-trump-gender-woman-card"&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; back in May: Research suggests that voters don’t let gender guide their decisions at the ballot box.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="QwVLIk"&gt;And that may be the silver lining here for Clinton boosters. Clinton looks likely to win the White House in November. If she does so, it almost certainly won’t be because the voters were simply taken with the groundbreaking prospect of a woman president.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11926090/hillary-clinton-historic-americans"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11926090/hillary-clinton-historic-americans</id>
    <author>
      <name>Jeff Stein</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T08:40:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T08:40:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>Stephen Colbert on Orlando shooting: "Hate wants us to be too weak to change anything"</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/5-dKeGeoagyOMCVByOX2WlMWDmQ=/50x0:1221x781/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49850211/Screen_Shot_2016-06-14_at_8.34.55_AM.0.0.png" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="ggtCYh"&gt;"It has been said too many times before," Stephen Colbert said at the start of his &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-1VZGUJ8GtY"&gt;show Monday night&lt;/a&gt;, speaking to the deadliest mass shooting in America, which left 49 dead and injured dozens more at a &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11911962/pulse-gay-nightclub-shooting-orlando-updates-news"&gt;gay nightclub in Orlando&lt;/a&gt; early Sunday morning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="1jlzOv"&gt;There have been at least &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/a/mass-shootings-sandy-hook"&gt;1,000 mass shootings&lt;/a&gt; in the United States since a gunman killed 20 children at Sandy Hook Elementary School in 2012: Isla Vista, California; Roseburg, Oregon; Charleston, South Carolina; San Bernardino, California; and now Orlando, Florida, to name a few that made big headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="DKTR6e"&gt;"You have a pretty good idea of what most people are going to say; you know what the president, whoever it is, will probably say; you know what both sides of the political aisle will say; you know what gun manufacturers will say," Colbert said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="C5D85k"&gt;It’s the "national script": the same dialogue people turn to time and time again after tragedy strikes. But the danger in the script, he says, is accepting it as status quo:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By accepting the script, we tacitly accept that the script will end the same way every time with nothing changing. It’s easy, it's almost tempting, to be paralyzed by such a monstrous hateful act, to despair, to say 'well this is this is the way the world is now.'&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don't know what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I do know that despair is a victory for hate. Hate wants us to be too weak to change anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[...]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Love in response to hate. Love does not despair. Love makes us strong. Love gives us the courage to act. Love gives us hope that change is possible. Love allows us to change the script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p id="C5qkev"&gt;As Vox’s Zack Beauchamp explained, the United States has a &lt;a href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/12/11912012/mass-shootings-gun-reform-nothing/in/11676003"&gt;long history&lt;/a&gt; of mourning without acting after mass shootings. Time and time again, policy changes to curb the proliferation of such violence have been proposed — a gun background check bill, a proposal to give the CDC a budget to research gun violence, another background check bill, and multiple attempts at gun control reforms — and failed or fizzled out, Beauchamp writes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Rifle Association, and its allies in Congress, have taken a hard-line position on gun restrictions. They believe that even minor laws designed to make it harder to get firearms, or even to figure out what works to stop gun violence, are unacceptable infringements on individual freedom. They have enough muscle in Congress to make action on gun control impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of us have to live with the consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;




</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931002/colbert-national-script-orlando"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11931002/colbert-national-script-orlando</id>
    <author>
      <name>Tara Golshan</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T08:20:03-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T08:20:03-04:00</updated>
    <title>BrainDead, from the creators of The Good Wife, mixes political drama with brain-eating bugs. It’s … confusing.</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/79nKKJsBlf7wipV1jLG2f0tb_WI=/0x0:600x400/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49846751/108213_briandead02411b.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="qUe1wp"&gt;If I ever let myself fall asleep to cable news, I suspect the ensuing nightmares would look a whole lot like &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt4877736/"&gt;BrainDead&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="48k0jk"&gt;From &lt;em&gt;The Good Wife &lt;/em&gt;creators&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;Michelle and Robert King, the new "political thriller" follows Laurel (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0935541/?ref_=ttfc_fc_cl_t4"&gt;Mary Elizabeth Winstead&lt;/a&gt;), a disillusioned Washington, DC, native who tried to build a career out of making searing documentaries until her scheming father and senator brother drew her into the fraught world of polarized politics, with the promise of paying off her student loans if she helps out her brother during a government shutdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Vh2C0q"&gt;So far, so typical, right? "But wait! There’s more!" says &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;, gleefully throwing a startling twist into the partisan fray. Laurel has joined the roiling eddy of Washington politics right at the moment when mysterious alien ants have started stealthily attacking people's brains for … some nefarious reason.  (More on what that reason might be later.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="ByRs3J"&gt;As presented by &lt;em&gt;BrainDead — &lt;/em&gt;which tries to skew more comedic than dramatic — these brain-eating bugs are either the worst thing to ever befall the world, or the most hilarious. (The fact that I can’t tell after watching two full episodes should give you an idea of just how confused &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; is.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Q4nplR"&gt;As Laurel tries to dig into the mystery of what’s going on while struggling with her new job as a constituent case worker, she winds up caught between her Democrat family and Gareth (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm3117836/?ref_=ttfc_fc_cl_t14"&gt;Aaron Tveit&lt;/a&gt;), a charming Republican aide whose infamously stubborn boss (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0001724/"&gt;Tony Shalhoub&lt;/a&gt;) keeps getting in her brother’s way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there’s a whole lot of backroom dealing and congressional intrigue happening in addition to the threat of having bugs make a buffet of your brain; it’s a lot for &lt;em&gt;anyone&lt;/em&gt; to handle, let alone a half-drawn character whose defining characteristic is that she made a documentary once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="kVFaLr"&gt;To its credit, &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;’s supernatural-tinged premise is at least somewhat interesting, thanks to its determination to make the endless back and forth of partisan politics both prescient and funny. Throw in the aforementioned brain-ravaging insects, and the show could be incredibly entertaining — if only &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; had any idea of what it wanted to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="3eX5me"&gt;
&lt;em&gt;BrainDead &lt;/em&gt;takes on politics with the confused enthusiasm of a Facebook rant&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt=" " src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/HpyKRKaas0_SFF07SDL5iq2PS4s=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6643929/107970_d-0255b.jpg"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;CBS&lt;/cite&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Red Wheatus (Tony Shalhoub) is Part of the Problem. (CBS)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="YHZpqu"&gt;Every time I got confused while watching &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;’s first two episodes — a common occurrence — I reminded myself of the very first scene of the pilot: a split-screen barrage of footage in which Hillary Clinton, Donald Trump, Bernie Sanders, and an unhappy Russian man are all talking at once. "In the year 2016," a caption says in declarative white letters, "there was a growing sense that people were losing their minds…"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="swhLIr"&gt;Enter &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;, I guess?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="7ifDAp"&gt;Incorporating reality into a scripted television show is always tricky, especially when said reality includes politics. &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; dives right in, making it clear that, yes, the series is supposed to take place in the 2016 we know, and, yes, things are pretty messed up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Z8DxcB"&gt;And while today’s political climate certainly provides plenty of material to mine, the problem with &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;’s approach is that not a single aspect of it contains any subtlety. The show fails to demonstrate an understanding beyond, "Republicans and Democrats don’t like each other, kind of a lot, and doesn’t that seem like a bad thing?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="tV8TXC"&gt;When Laurel isn't nobly trying to convince her brother (&lt;a href="http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0992694/?ref_=ttfc_fc_cl_t12"&gt;Danny Pino&lt;/a&gt;) to act like a human being while pursuing his political agenda, she and Gareth are throwing scraps of Twitter arguments at each other in the name of reaching across the metaphorical aisle.  The result is that Laurel mostly bumbles her way around Washington, occasionally showing some moxie but really just absorbing the weirdness around her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="KGNUFt"&gt;Winstead does what she can, but she really does deserve better than this one-dimensional role. And Shalhoub, for his part, is miscast in the role of Southern Republican "Red Wheatus" — even if he’s game to luxuriate in his character’s smugness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="Co8eJI"&gt;All the while,&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;television coverage plays on a loop in the background, with pertinent, Fox News–style sound bites delivered by a conservative blond reporter (Megan Hilty); her statements are then countered by a fed-up take on Rachel Maddow (Beth Malone). Both remind us constantly that at the end of the day, everyone both inside Washington and outside of it pretty much knows politics is a game of chicken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qL2DJM"&gt;&lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; just tries to do too many things at once — including attempting to comment on the State of Politics Today — and the result is more convoluted than revelatory. Just take a look at the title of the pilot episode, which I promise is real: "The Insanity Principle: How Extremism in Politics Is Threatening Democracy in the 21st Century."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="eOHBUy"&gt;Sure, &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;! Why not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="okaiaT"&gt;At the very least, you can play a fun drinking game with &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;, one where you take a sip every time someone scoffs, "the &lt;em&gt;Democrats" &lt;/em&gt;or "the &lt;em&gt;Republicans&lt;/em&gt;" with a frustrated, eye-rolling sneer. The series knows politics is more contentious than ever, but that’s about &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; it seems to know. So more often than not, it devolves into the most basic of talking points — the exact thing it’s trying to skewer in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="l9qsWt"&gt;Okay, but what was that about brain-eating ants? Is this a comedy or a drama? What is &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt;?!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p id="rZsudo"&gt;These are fair questions. Unfortunately, I don’t think I — or anyone involved with the series, for that matter — have a good grasp of the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="50lIcU"&gt;The tone of &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; is immediately bizarre. It’s going for something much lighter than what &lt;em&gt;The Good Wife&lt;/em&gt; generally traded in, but laces almost every scene with self-consciously significant moments that badly want to convey gravitas. Remember how &lt;em&gt;The Good Wife&lt;/em&gt; frequently fell flat when it produced topical episodes based on "ripped from the headlines" events? &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; is like that, but with more cortex-chomping parasites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="VxUT8t"&gt;In the second episode, for example, Shalhoub’s Republican senator tries to convince someone to switch political parties, arguing with a smirk that party lines are just "brands," like Cheerios versus Chex. The only thing more inane than the senator's argument is the fact that it works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="knmW0z"&gt;So instead of achieving whatever commentary on politics and life &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; is striving for, it ends up settling for surface-level scenes whose messages boil down to something more like, "Ugh, politics, amirite?"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="NZSR8m"&gt;As for the ants … well, turning Washington into a horde of mindless zombies à la &lt;em&gt;Invasion of the Body Snatchers&lt;/em&gt; is a pretty good hook, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="qO65tk"&gt;Beyond that, the purpose of the creatures remains unclear, despite &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; showing us the aftermath of several people’s infections. Some victims are simply rendered mindlessly happy. Others — namely the politicians — are affected in a way that strengthens their most extreme views, making them efficient, focused machines whose only purpose is to further their party’s platform. Still others just kind of sit around, oozing brain matter. Super chill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HR6KQ0"&gt;The exact objective of the bugs will no doubt be revealed in time, but while we wait for that moment, we can all agree that the side effect of having one’s brain rewired — at least as &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; presents it — is currently pretty stupid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="HIJbIs"&gt;It would be one thing if &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; used this supernatural twist to energize otherwise typical political plots, but in eagerly attempting to make some larger argument about simmering anger and partisanship — which I &lt;em&gt;think&lt;/em&gt; is what the show aiming for — it just trips all over itself. &lt;em&gt;BrainDead&lt;/em&gt; has no idea what it’s trying to say, but as the chirpy music insists in every other scene, at least it’s having fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="U9qVjH"&gt;Politics, amirite?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="8tJ3He"&gt;BrainDead&lt;em&gt; airs Mondays at 10 pm Eastern on CBS.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11924152/braindead-cbs-review-recap-premiere"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11924152/braindead-cbs-review-recap-premiere</id>
    <author>
      <name>Caroline Framke</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <published>2016-06-14T08:10:02-04:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-14T08:10:02-04:00</updated>
    <title>The climate fight will be won or lost in India, in 8 charts</title>
    <content type="html">  
  &lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/o_fYSYAkmZM7g9fZzrSA1VDf8io=/0x0:1024x683/1310x873/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_image/image/49845283/india-coal-scavenging.0.jpg" /&gt;



  &lt;p id="OM1IxP"&gt;Bloomberg New Energy Finance (BNEF) is out with its annual&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/company/new-energy-outlook/"&gt;New Energy Outlook&lt;/a&gt; for 2016, forecasting global energy trends through 2040, focusing this year on electricity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="0yaru0"&gt;There’s lots to dig through, but the big story is familiar: Progress is occurring more rapidly than almost anyone forecast — global fossil fuel electricity use is expected to &lt;a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2016-06-13/we-ve-almost-reached-peak-fossil-fuels-for-electricity"&gt;peak in 2025&lt;/a&gt; and decline thereafter — but not rapidly enough to forestall&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://www.vox.com/2014/4/22/5551004/two-degrees"&gt;2 degrees of global warming&lt;/a&gt;. We’re going fast, but not fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="aOWstR"&gt;That said, there are lots of interesting nuances and substories in the report. One of them reveals that India, not China, is becoming the key to global decarbonization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="PZhPxw"&gt;Most of the big emitters have gotten a handle on their electricity systems, meaning that they are on track to phase out coal and (somewhat later) natural gas. They’re not doing it fast enough, but at least they are on the right trajectory. That’s even true for China, where just a few years ago analysts were saying that coal would dominate forever. Now there’s a post-2020 moratorium on new coal plants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="11BDT4"&gt;India, however, is a different story. Its economy is growing quickly, and with it electricity demand. That means even with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a target="_blank" href="http://blogs.cfr.org/levi/2015/03/11/do-indias-renewable-energy-targets-make-sense/"&gt;audacious renewable energy goals&lt;/a&gt; Modi has laid out, coal consumption is going to &lt;em&gt;triple&lt;/em&gt; in India by 2040, with 258 GW of new coal capacity coming online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="xvzmPO"&gt;As a result of this new coal, BNEF says, "power sector emissions will still be 5 percent higher in 2040, as progress in the EU, US and China is offset by steep emissions growth in India and SE Asia."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="uTORiM"&gt;But enough words. Let’s tell the story in charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1) Globally, through 2040, $11.4 trillion will be invested in new power generation, mostly in renewables&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="electricity investment" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vZWQcBUyBDAiIjuXd45y8UAcz2I=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637423/bnef-neo2016-total-investment.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id="Z0AOou"&gt;2) More than half of that new generating capacity will be built in the Asia-Pacific region&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="capacity additions by region" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/nr_SUk0ILIY9yzcUWiet8G1FbQc=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637425/bnef-neo2016-capacity-by-region.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ndoy7i"&gt;3) Some $2.8 trillion will be invested in power generation in China, with dramatic results&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="china new capacity" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/DXk1Bznq0_ehUDAUjsx0NNKFdjw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637451/bnef-neo2016-china-capcity.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="KG1bKr"&gt;In China, coal capacity will peak in 2020 and coal generation will peak in 2025. Through 2040, 73 percent of new generation capacity will be renewables. It's a remarkable turnaround from the story about China being told a decade ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="0YrxGC"&gt;4) Europe is also on track to drive coal and gas out of the power sector&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="eu capacity" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/8kuzfitgya4HdZYW63UyXmXyilg=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637457/bnef-neo2016-eu-capacity.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="2bGvt2"&gt;Renewables promise to be 70 percent of all electricity generation in Europe by 2040.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="9tWRiZ"&gt;5) In the US, coal is going to drop but gas is going to hang on&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="us capacity through 2040" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/wsfAcrF2oDK16lTKa0w56RVGRDA=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637473/bnef-neo2016-us-capacity.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="f2rYNL"&gt;Renewables will comprise up to 50 percent of total generating capacity in the US by 2040. Most of that "other" is nuclear, so natural gas — which is expected to stay stubbornly cheap and plentiful in the US — will remain America’s unsolved fossil problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="Bdqe6Y"&gt;6) So coal is declining everywhere ... except India&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="india capacity" src="https://cdn1.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/lvhb3tsFSmiGCjK7h0ZX4EFpNjQ=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637579/bnef-neo2016-india-capacity.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="2yZu8p"&gt;Burgeoning energy demand and persistent low coal prices mean that coal will continue to dominate the power mix in India (and elsewhere in SE Asia), rising through 2040, even though a growing share of new capacity (29 percent) will come from solar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="yFuzs5"&gt;7) Cumulatively, clean power will explode, but dirty power won’t decline much&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="electricity generation through 2040" src="https://cdn2.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/F9bb1ujnwbT1Zs1FQtRgXx6F5bw=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637589/bnef-neo2016-electricity-generation.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="oZSTMq"&gt;Despite the growth in wind and solar, fossil fuels’ total global contribution to electricity remains roughly steady through 2040, mainly because of all the new coal capacity expected to come online. BNEF expects 963 GW of new coal through 2040 — and remember, 248 GW of that, just over a quarter of the total, is destined for India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="JGnWcj"&gt;8) This means, unless something changes, global power-sector GHG emissions will hold steady&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;figure class="e-image"&gt;
        &lt;img alt="emissions through 2040" src="https://cdn0.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/_5bDf0LvR2SGTW3zN52j7DN1BGE=/400x0/filters:no_upscale()/cdn0.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/6637599/bnef-neo2016-emissions.png"&gt;
      &lt;cite&gt;(&lt;a href="https://www.bnef.com/dataview/new-energy-outlook-2016/index.html"&gt;BNEF&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/cite&gt;
  &lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p id="x02tXc"&gt;BNEF estimates that another $5.3 trillion in zero-carbon energy&amp;nbsp;investment&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;(on top of the $7.8 trillion)&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;would be needed between now and 2040 to put power-sector emissions on a 2 degree trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="F8Fssg"&gt;Most of that investment would need to go to India (and Vietnam, and other SE Asian nations), to accelerate the shift from coal to renewables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p id="mJagHO"&gt;Where’s that extra investment going to come from? What's going to drive it? How will it be structured? If there's to be any hope of averting the worst of climate change, these questions urgently need answers.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11919610/india-decarbonization-8-graphs"/>
    <id>http://www.vox.com/2016/6/14/11919610/india-decarbonization-8-graphs</id>
    <author>
      <name>David Roberts</name>
    </author>
  </entry>
</feed>
